<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web 2.0 on wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/categories/web-2.0/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web 2.0 on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2008 04:37:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/categories/web-2.0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture shock...at work</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/culture-shockat-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2008 04:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/culture-shockat-work/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re more concerned with your company culture than the size of your pay cheque, your might be interested in this Vancouver start-up. Jiibe is a user-generated service that matches your value system to a compatible company based on a questionnaire you fill out.
I can see this site being really useful to young Millennials who care a great deal about the softer aspects of job satisfaction and are in a process of self-discovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical cross-pollination with the tech industry</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/musical-cross-pollination-with-the-tech-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2008 02:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/musical-cross-pollination-with-the-tech-industry/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re Homo Sapien then you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard that song by Yael Naïm. Name not ringing any bells? You know, it&amp;rsquo;s the one that goes something like this: &amp;ldquo;La-la-la-la la-la-la-la-la&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Still not getting it? Okay, it&amp;rsquo;s the song from the MacBook Air commercial. Yes, you know the one (and if you still have no clue, check out this YouTube video).
The song is called &amp;ldquo;New Soul&amp;rdquo; and was handpicked by Steve Jobs for the MacBook campaign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Brijit liberating or enslaving?</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/is-brijit-liberating-or-enslaving/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2008 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/is-brijit-liberating-or-enslaving/</guid>
      <description>For those of you who aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with it, Brijit is a website that publishes 100-word summaries of various web, TV, radio, and print media. The idea is that there is so much information out there - wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be nice if we had the short-short version so we can get the gist of it and decide if it&amp;rsquo;s worth reading or watching the whole thing.
It&amp;rsquo;s a neat idea, but with so much content out there, it would be impossible for an editorial team to cover it all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heading to DocTrain West</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/heading-to-doctrain-west/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2008 02:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/heading-to-doctrain-west/</guid>
      <description>I won a ticket to this year&amp;rsquo;s DocTrain West conference through the Westcoast STC! I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank the organizer Scott Abel and the good people at the STC for giving me this terrific opportunity. As I mentioned before, if you can afford the $899, or have a generous employer, then be there or don&amp;rsquo;t-be-square.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>