<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Netflix on wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/categories/netflix/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Netflix on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 19:26:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/categories/netflix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix Canada top picks</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/netflix-canada-top-picks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 19:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/netflix-canada-top-picks/</guid>
      <description>Netflix Canada has been busy releasing tons of new stuff, so I&amp;rsquo;ve given up detailing every single new release. Instead, here are my top picks based on movies I&amp;rsquo;ve either seen and recommend (especially flicks I consider to be &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo;), or movies I want to see because I&amp;rsquo;ve heard or read that they are good. These are based on the last few months of new releases.
The Fog Seen it: classic</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix new releases for June 10</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/netflix-new-releases-for-june-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 16:43:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/netflix-new-releases-for-june-10/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s not a lot to recommend in the latest releases. If you really want to watch a Thor movie, avoid this stinker and shell out the extra bucks for the excellent version that&amp;rsquo;s in the cinema right now. But if I had to pick, I&amp;rsquo;d go with the critic darling Waltz with Bashir, even though it looks like a bit of a downer.
Almighty Thor Flixster Audience Rating: 6%</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest Netflix releases for June 5</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/latest-netflix-releases-for-june-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 16:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/latest-netflix-releases-for-june-5/</guid>
      <description>My top pick for today is Noise. Not the highest rated movie, but Tim robbins and William Hurt are both fantastic actors and the plot of this indie flick looks intriguing. Of course, the proof is in the pudding, as I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched any of my top picks yet!
June 5 Noise Rotten Tomatoes Rating: 57%

Desperate for some peace and quiet, New York attorney David Owen (Tim Robbins) takes matters into his own hands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest Netflix releases June 2</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/latest-netflix-releases-june-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 16:46:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/latest-netflix-releases-june-2/</guid>
      <description>Good morning people. Here are the latest releases and ratings for Netflix Canada. My top pick today is 24 City. This looks like a very timely and relevant Chinese movie with a unique directing style and is our highest rated for today.
June 02 While She Was Out Rotten Tomatoes Rating: 33%

What starts out as a Christmas Eve trip to the mall ends up as an exercise in terror for suburban mom Della Myers (Kim Basinger) when she finds herself stranded in a forest and pursued by a quartet of thugs &amp;ndash; all because she&amp;rsquo;s left an angry note on their car.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Netflix Canada releases for June 1st</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/new-netflix-canada-releases-for-june-1st/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 18:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/new-netflix-canada-releases-for-june-1st/</guid>
      <description>I love Netflix, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to tell when new movies come out and whether they&amp;rsquo;re any good or not. So, here are the latest releases for June 1st and their Rotten Tomatoes / Flixster rating. I&amp;rsquo;ll also be giving my top pick for the day for a movie I think is the number one worth watching out of the batch&amp;hellip; And my top pick today is Knight and Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefly: My review</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/firefly-my-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 20:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/firefly-my-review/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished watching the complete Firefly series on Netflix. That sounds like a lot of TV watching, but it only ran for 14 episodes before it got cancelled due to low ratings. Most geeks agree, however, that this show was a little gem, was poorly marketed by Fox, and should never have died so early. After watching it, I would have to agree.
I guess this show falls into the space-western genre, and with plenty of horses, bandits, prostitutes, and bounty hunters, I&amp;rsquo;d say it falls more into the &amp;ldquo;western&amp;rdquo; part of the spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>