<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inspiration on wordbit</title>
    <link>https://wordbit.com/categories/inspiration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inspiration on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 06:23:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wordbit.com/categories/inspiration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Free eBooks for Valentines</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/free-ebooks-for-valentines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 06:23:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/free-ebooks-for-valentines/</guid>
      <description>I wish I had more time to blog this month, but alas, you can look forward to a paucity of blog posts. Even my tweets are running dry. So, in the meantime, what better way to get your reading fix than to indulge in some licentious drivel. To celebrate 60 years of &amp;ldquo;pure reading pleasure&amp;rdquo;, Harlequin is offering 16 free eBooks for download in various formats including PDF, ePub, eReader, and MS Reader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21st century tips on finding work</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/21st-century-tips-on-finding-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 05:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/21st-century-tips-on-finding-work/</guid>
      <description>You may as well recycle those newspaper classifieds, because that old school job-finding tool belongs in the 20th century. Spurred on by the recession, a number of tech-savvy people have started blogging on various &amp;ldquo;new school&amp;rdquo; ways of getting a job. Tech evangelist Robert Scoble has some crafty tips. I tend to agree with him when he says your blog is your résumé. After all, google my name and this blog is the first search result (and if you are a hiring manager, then please note my correct formatting of the word résumé!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reader letters warm my writer&#39;s heart</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/reader-letters-warm-my-writers-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 04:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/reader-letters-warm-my-writers-heart/</guid>
      <description>As you may or may not recall, last August my article on the evils of recycling was published. Sometimes I lose sight of the fact that thousands of people read the stuff I put out there. Some probably think it&amp;rsquo;s a load of tosh. Other slightly more creepy individuals google my name and usually ask some sort of favour. But others actually have something interesting to say. So Ben, even though you&amp;rsquo;ll never read this, thanks for your letter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The writer&#39;s bane is...writing</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/the-writers-bane-iswriting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 02:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/the-writers-bane-iswriting/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished reading Anne Lamott&amp;rsquo;s Bird by Bird, a wonderfully humourous book full of advice on how to write and how to overcome those challenges all writers face. Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt I particularly like:
 &amp;ldquo;But how?&amp;rdquo; my students ask. &amp;ldquo;How do you actually do it?&amp;rdquo;
You sit down, I say. You try to sit down at approximately the same time every day. This is how you train your unconscious to kick in for you creatively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning from Leo</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/learning-from-leo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2007 07:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/learning-from-leo/</guid>
      <description>Peter Legge, CEO of Canada Wide (the behemoth that publishes just about every magazine in Western Canada), recently wrote a little book on how to jump-start your career.
He advises us to model ourselves after Leonardo da Vinci, who believed that seven key elements allowed him to become one of the most incredible innovators of our time. Here they are:
 Curiosita: An insatiably curious approach to life and an unrelenting quest for continuous learning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>