<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inspiration on wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/categories/inspiration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inspiration on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 06:23:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/categories/inspiration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Free eBooks for Valentines</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/free-ebooks-for-valentines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 06:23:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/free-ebooks-for-valentines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/02/boxshot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;boxshot&#34; /&gt; I wish I had more time to blog this month, but alas, you can look forward to a paucity of blog posts. Even my tweets are running dry. So, in the meantime, what better way to get your reading fix than to indulge in some licentious drivel. To celebrate 60 years of &amp;ldquo;pure reading pleasure&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://harlequincelebrates.com/&#34;&gt;Harlequin is offering 16 free eBooks for download&lt;/a&gt; in various formats including PDF, ePub, eReader, and MS Reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you&amp;rsquo;re not into this genre, and admittedly, I&amp;rsquo;m hardly the target audience either - do you know how lucrative this market actually is? A few years ago, I got a book called &amp;ldquo;The Art of Romance Writing&amp;rdquo; as a gag gift, but am now seriously thinking of writing a racy novel and retiring on the inevitable movie deal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21st century tips on finding work</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/21st-century-tips-on-finding-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 05:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/21st-century-tips-on-finding-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/JobSearchNewspaper1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JobSearchNewspaper&#34; /&gt; You may as well recycle those newspaper classifieds, because that old school job-finding tool belongs in the 20th century. Spurred on by the recession, a number of tech-savvy people have started blogging on various &amp;ldquo;new school&amp;rdquo; ways of getting a job. Tech evangelist Robert Scoble has &lt;a href=&#34;http://scobleizer.com/2009/01/12/if-you-are-laid-off-heres-how-to-socially-network/&#34;&gt;some crafty tips&lt;/a&gt;. I tend to agree with him when he says your blog is your résumé. After all, google my name and this blog is the first search result (and if you are a hiring manager, then please note my correct formatting of the word &lt;em&gt;résumé&lt;/em&gt;!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local writer and social media consultant Monica Hamburg talks about how to tap into the hidden job market online in &lt;a href=&#34;http://monicahamburg.wordpress.com/2009/01/13/job-search-new-school/&#34;&gt;her excellent blog post&lt;/a&gt;. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether you&amp;rsquo;re a Java programmer or a hairdresser - creating an online presence and fostering a network can benefit you. If nothing else, it&amp;rsquo;s way more fun than cold calling!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reader letters warm my writer&#39;s heart</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/reader-letters-warm-my-writers-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 04:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/reader-letters-warm-my-writers-heart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may or may not recall, last August &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/recycling-global-warming-and-toxic-toys/&#34;&gt;my article on the evils of recycling&lt;/a&gt; was published. Sometimes I lose sight of the fact that thousands of people read the stuff I put out there. Some probably think it&amp;rsquo;s a load of tosh. Other slightly more creepy individuals google my name and usually ask some sort of favour. But &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/scans/letter.html&#34;&gt;others actually have something interesting to say&lt;/a&gt;. So Ben, even though you&amp;rsquo;ll never read this, thanks for your letter. It&amp;rsquo;s not often I get to hear from the mythical &amp;lsquo;audience&amp;rsquo; writers always harp on about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The writer&#39;s bane is...writing</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-writers-bane-iswriting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 02:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-writers-bane-iswriting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/06/bird.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bird&#34; /&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished reading Anne Lamott&amp;rsquo;s B&lt;em&gt;ird by Bird&lt;/em&gt;, a wonderfully humourous book full of advice on how to write and how to overcome those challenges all writers face. Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt I particularly like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&#34;But how?&#34; my students ask. &#34;How do you actually do it?&#34;
&gt; 
&gt; You sit down, I say. You try to sit down at approximately the same time every day. This is how you train your unconscious to kick in for you creatively. So you sit down at, say, nine every morning, or ten every night. You put a piece of paper in the typewriter, or you turn on your computer and bring up the right file, and then you stare at it for an hour or so. You begin rocking, just a little at first, and then like a huge autistic child. You look at the ceiling, and over at the clock, yawn, and stare at the paper again. 
&gt; 
&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Then, with your fingers poised on the keyboard, you squint at an image that is forming in your mind - a scene, a locale, a character, whatever - and you try to quiet your mind so you can hear what that landscape has to say above the other voices in your mind. The other voices are banshees and drunken monkeys. They are the voices of anxiety, judgment, doom, guilt. Also, severe hypochondria. There may be a Nurse Ratched-like listing of things that must be done right this moment: foods that must come out of the freezer, appointments that must be canceled or made, hairs that must be tweezed. But you hold an imaginary gun to your head and make yourself stay at the desk. There is a vague pain at the base of your neck. It crosses your mind that you have meningitis. Then the phone rings and you look up at the ceiling with fury, summon every ounce of noblesse oblige, and answer the call politely, with maybe just the merest hint of irritation. The caller asks if you&#39;re working, and you say yeah, because you are.
&gt; 
&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound familiar? The hardest part about writing is definitely the writing part. Anyway, just wanted to share that with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning from Leo</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/learning-from-leo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2007 07:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/learning-from-leo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/11/LeonardodaVinci.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;LeonardodaVinci&#34; /&gt; Peter Legge, CEO of Canada Wide (the behemoth that publishes just about every magazine in Western Canada), recently wrote a little book on how to jump-start your career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He advises us to model ourselves after Leonardo da Vinci, who believed that seven key elements allowed him to become one of the most incredible innovators of our time. Here they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Curiosita&lt;/em&gt;: An insatiably curious approach to life and an unrelenting quest for continuous learning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dimostrazione&lt;/em&gt;: A commitment to test knowledge through experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sensazione&lt;/em&gt;: The continual refinement of the sense, especially sight, as the means to enliven experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sfumato&lt;/em&gt; (literally, &amp;ldquo;Going up in smoke&amp;rdquo;): A willingness to embrace ambiguity, paradox and uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arte/Scienza&lt;/em&gt;: The development of the balance between science and art, logic and imagination. Whole-brain thinking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corporalita&lt;/em&gt;: The cultivation of grace, ambidexterity, fitness, and poise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Connessione&lt;/em&gt;: A recognition of and an appreciation for the interconnectedness of all things and phenomena. Systems thinking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>