<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Writing Challenge on wordbit</title>
    <link>https://wordbit.com/categories/the-writing-challenge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Writing Challenge on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 May 2007 06:21:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wordbit.com/categories/the-writing-challenge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writer&#39;s Challenge answer revealed</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/writers-challenge-answer-revealed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2007 06:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/writers-challenge-answer-revealed/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to my brother, who figured out that the weird Japanese USB device was, in fact, an &amp;ldquo;ass-cooler&amp;rdquo;. Check out the explanation here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Challenge #2</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/writing-challenge-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2007 02:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/writing-challenge-2/</guid>
      <description>You can now expel your baited breath because writing challenge number two is here! For this task, you will be required to go to this Japanese website and view the images.
I&amp;rsquo;m assuming you cannot read Japanese, so the challenge before you is to decipher what this product is based on the images alone. Can you figure out just what this newfangled USB device does? A little research might help you out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ok, ok, you can stop pestering me...</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/ok-ok-you-can-stop-pestering-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2007 06:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/ok-ok-you-can-stop-pestering-me/</guid>
      <description>All you partakers of the writer&amp;rsquo;s challenge can stop begging me to reveal the answer, because here it is at long last! The ludicrous patent description you have been puzzling over is nothing more than a wrist support made of a rubber balloon tied filled with sand and sealed with a piece of wire. That&amp;rsquo;s the short, short version of the lengthy waffling monstrosity somebody let loose in the patent office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writer&#39;s challenge #1</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/writers-challenge-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2007 07:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/writers-challenge-1/</guid>
      <description>As promised in my last post, here is a little segment I&amp;rsquo;m going to call&amp;hellip;(insert drum-roll here)&amp;hellip;THE WRITER&amp;rsquo;S CHALLENGE! Will you muster your courage and face the cunning challenge I&amp;rsquo;ve set before you?
Here it is:
I am holding an object in my hand. Guess what the object is by reading it&amp;rsquo;s patent description.
Let me warn you, this is some of the most convoluted, ridiculously bloated writing I have ever seen being used to describe something that is deceptively simple.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>