<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Site Announcements on wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/categories/site-announcements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Site Announcements on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2011 23:07:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/categories/site-announcements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>And so it ends... or does it?</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/and-so-it-ends-or-does-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2011 23:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/and-so-it-ends-or-does-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well folks, this Wordpress blog has officially reached its end. But all the content remains and all broken links have been fixed. And now for the good news. The blogging continues over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wordbit.com&#34;&gt;wordbit.com&lt;/a&gt; where I&amp;rsquo;ve moved to the Tumblr platform. Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy access to private blog</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/easy-access-to-private-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 04:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/easy-access-to-private-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a reminder that you can read uncensored rants and view personal pictures on my private blog. To make it simple, I&amp;rsquo;ve added a &amp;ldquo;PRIVATE&amp;rdquo; button to the top menu bar on this website in between &amp;ldquo;CONTACT&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;RSS&amp;rdquo;. If you know me, just email or facebook me and ask for the password. It&amp;rsquo;s simple - if I even vaguely know who you are, then you&amp;rsquo;re in. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I&amp;rsquo;m not screening out people I don&amp;rsquo;t like, lol! Otherwise, I will still cross-post geeky stuff right here on wordbit. Thanks for reading amigos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up close and personal</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/up-close-and-personal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 04:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/up-close-and-personal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another year is upon us and wordbit is in its 5th year! But with sporadic posts, this site has slowly slipped into oblivion. Well, I always have good intentions, but I have decided to create another personal blog, while keeping wordbit as the &amp;ldquo;public face&amp;rdquo; of my professional life. So, my personal blog is at &lt;a href=&#34;http://antoineg.info&#34;&gt;antoineg.info&lt;/a&gt;, but you&amp;rsquo;ll need to ask me for the password to access it. If I know you, you&amp;rsquo;re in! I&amp;rsquo;ve just gotten tired of fighting off the spammers and dealing with privacy issues and the dominance of Facebook as well. But I&amp;rsquo;m not abandoning this site by any means. I&amp;rsquo;ll have some more articles to tell you about soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saving my Geocities site</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/saving-my-geocities-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 06:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/saving-my-geocities-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/ma_geo_1.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking a long break from blogging, but have been swamped with other projects and personal stuff. But I thought I&amp;rsquo;d take this opportunity for a cool retrospective trip through the interwebs. Now, you may know that Yahoo&amp;rsquo;s Geocities is closing this October. Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to save my oldest website from imminent oblivion through the painstaking process of re-coding each html file, capturing all the other files through a Firefox plug-in, and giving it a new home on this server. Ah, Geocities&amp;hellip;those horrid, visceral backgrounds, the ghastly html code, the weird wavy headers, the site design that makes Myspace look like a contender for the User Interface award. So, why bother? Well, there is soul in this site, and a rawness that is appealing in strange sort of way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here it is. There are lots of links that don&amp;rsquo;t work, but that&amp;rsquo;s not the point. The point is to preserve this little piece of history so that when Geocities dies, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wordbit.freehostia.com/geocities&#34;&gt;Negotiating Reality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; lives on. See you when I see you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check out my latest article</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/check-out-my-latest-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 00:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/check-out-my-latest-article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/scans/moisterize.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/05/tn_moisterize1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tn_moisterize1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; alive&lt;/em&gt; magazine is out, and this month I have a men&amp;rsquo;s beauty article published called &amp;ldquo;Are you man enough to moisturize?&amp;rdquo; Click on the thumbnail to check it out. It&amp;rsquo;s meant to be informative, but it&amp;rsquo;s also a marketing piece because I mention a few products that potential retail customers might be interested in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I&amp;rsquo;ve recently updated my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wordbit.freehostia.com/eportfolio&#34;&gt;ePortfolio&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;m going to recommend to all potential employers from now on. I&amp;rsquo;ve been sending out links to the portfolio on this blog, but that page is becoming a bit unwieldy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope everyone is enjoying the twitter feed on the right side of this page. I tend to update it more often than my blog, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good way to see what I&amp;rsquo;m up to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate relaxation techniques</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/ultimate-relaxation-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2008 18:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/ultimate-relaxation-techniques/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/05/eli.png&#34; alt=&#34;eli&#34; /&gt; The May edition of &lt;em&gt;alive&lt;/em&gt; magazine is out, and I have two articles published in it this month. A few months ago I interviewed stress guru &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elibay.com&#34;&gt;Eli Bay&lt;/a&gt; about his relaxation techniques. Take a deep breath, relax for a few minutes and &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/scans/EBayInterview.html&#34;&gt;read his insights&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/05/mosquito.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mosquito&#34; /&gt;I also wrote a short piece on &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/scans/Mosquito%20article.html&#34;&gt;the rise of the mosquito population&lt;/a&gt; in our new era of rising temperatures. Mosquitoes love warm, moist climates, and they&amp;rsquo;re getting a lot of that these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most of the rest of this week, I expect to be blogging exclusively on DocTrain West, which I&amp;rsquo;m attending this week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check out my ePortfolio</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/check-out-my-eportfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2008 03:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/check-out-my-eportfolio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wordbit.freehostia.com/eportfolio&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/03/scshotweb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;scshotweb&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve officially uploaded the latest version of my ePortolio - you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wordbit.freehostia.com/eportfolio&#34;&gt;check it out here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website uses some flash elements and some fancy css coding and is basically geared towards technical writing employers as a way to showcase my work. I may expand it in the future to include other samples too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who are interested, I designed it in Dreamweaver, Illustrator, and Photoshop. I used FlashSpring Pro 2 to convert a Powerpoint to flash. It&amp;rsquo;s best viewed using the latest version of any browser with a resolution of 1024x768. It&amp;rsquo;s also a bit flashier than the portfolio on this blog, which includes everything, including the kitchen sink.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordbit&#39;s spiffy new logo</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/wordbits-spiffy-new-logo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2008 02:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/wordbits-spiffy-new-logo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to 2008! If you&amp;rsquo;ve been here before then you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that I&amp;rsquo;ve finally put up a proper logo for the site. I&amp;rsquo;m quite pleased with it, but it can always be tweaked. Other upgrades for the new year are taking place as you read this. I&amp;rsquo;ve put up &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/portfolio/samples&#34;&gt;more writing samples&lt;/a&gt;, as well as simplified the design in my portfolio. Up next will be making an editing and design section. Anyway, that&amp;rsquo;s all for now - happy new year to all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest developments</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/latest-developments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2007 02:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/latest-developments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/07/465px-Ipod_5th_Generation_white1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;465px-Ipod_5th_Generation_white&#34; /&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m administering a new podcast for Rev. Craig Vance at my church. Craig&amp;rsquo;s sermons are really insightful and quite intellectual. Anyway, the technical side of things has hardly been cutting edge as I&amp;rsquo;ve been recording onto cassette tapes that get chewed up in my 1990 cassette player before they even get turned into an MP3. Nevertheless, I&amp;rsquo;ve managed two so far and plan to keep that site updated every week. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ctrchurch.com/sermons.htm&#34;&gt;Check it out&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also decided to redesign this website and make it even more functional and even better looking. As I obviously don&amp;rsquo;t update this blog very regularly, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to give it a less prominent place in the scheme of things. I&amp;rsquo;m debating whether to switch to Joomla and keep the Wordpress engine or just switch over totally to maintain consistency among the site elements. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how it turns out - it&amp;rsquo;ll take a while I&amp;rsquo;m sure&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Accelerator killed my website</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/google-accelerator-killed-my-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 01:18:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/google-accelerator-killed-my-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wordbit has been down for the count for a few days due to an experimental  Google app I unwisely installed. So, just in case you were thinking of trying out one of the apps in Google Labs, think again.   &lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/03/WindowsLiveWriter/GoogleAcceleratorkilledmywebsite_EC27/googleaccelarator%5B9%5D.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Accelerator ostensibly speeds up your Internet browsing by diverting web pages through their servers. The problem is that the program pre-fetches all websites on any given page. This is fine for public browsing at, say, a library. For website administration pages, it opens the doors to hell. Every option on the page will be pre-fetched by Google, including links to delete posts or change the language options, or whatever. When I discovered that Google Accelerator was messing up my Wordpress Administration page to the point where I couldn&amp;rsquo;t click on anything without it going haywire, I hastily uninstalled it. In doing so, Google Accelerator took my entire website with it. Thankfully, I had recently made backups of my site (because I&amp;rsquo;ve recently switched to a new server).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, to make a long story short, in the end I had to delete everything and redirect my nameservers to fix the problem! So, everything should be back to normal now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I trusted too much in Google because I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved everything they&amp;rsquo;ve put out there. This particular app, however, should go straight to Google&amp;rsquo;s recycle bin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources Page is up</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/resources-page-is-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2007 09:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/resources-page-is-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/resources-for-technical-writers/&#34;&gt;resources &lt;/a&gt;page for links to forums, job postings, blogs, other tech writer sites, podcasts, books, e-books, professional associations and web portals. This list is by no means complete. If you have any websites that would be of use to neophyte tech writers, please post a comment on the resources page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a wordbit anyway?</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/what-is-a-wordbit-anyway/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2007 23:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/what-is-a-wordbit-anyway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://anglish.wikia.com/wiki/Wordbit&#34;&gt;Wikia Wiki&lt;/a&gt;, a **wordbit **is &amp;ldquo;the smallest deal that bears a meaning. Wordbits are the sound or sounds, sideput, that bear meaning.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wordbits are the building blocks of language. This website is my small attempt to bring meaning to what we do as writers and hopefully contribute something to the writing &amp;ldquo;blogosphere&amp;rdquo;, if you&amp;rsquo;ll excuse the jargon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this website is more than a blog. This is also a place where you can view my on-line portfolio, or check out some resources for other writers (still in progress). You can also read more about who I am, or check out my blogroll for other bloggers on culture, communication and technology.&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; more &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some more information about this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordpress.org/&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; blogging engine (Version 2.0.7) to handle the content on this site. The modified cutline theme is courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://cutline.tubetorial.com/&#34;&gt;Chris Pearson&lt;/a&gt;. One cool feature of this theme is that everytime you log on to the main page you&amp;rsquo;ll see a randomly generated header image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m hosting the site for free on awardspace, which means it tends to be a bit choppy. If you get script errors refresh the page (Hit F5) and it should be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>