<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 17:12:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>In Memoriam: Derek Miller</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/in-memoriam-derek-miller/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 17:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/in-memoriam-derek-miller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Much-loved Vancouver writer Derek Miller passed away yesterday at the age of 41. He had struggled with cancer for the past few years. I interviewed Derek for a Print Futures assignment a while back and wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2007/02/dmprofile.pdf&#34;&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; about his writing career. In the interview, Derek told me that he didn&amp;rsquo;t know what the future would hold, but he knew for sure he would still be writing. He was right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He surely couldn&amp;rsquo;t predict he would die a few years later, but he did write until the very end. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.penmachine.com/2011/05/the-last-post&#34;&gt;His final blog post&lt;/a&gt; is his own obituary - a true writer wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have it any other way. Indeed, through his blog he has chronicled his own painful journey as his health steadily declined to a point where he couldn&amp;rsquo;t leave the house - and barely leave his bed. But he still wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am greatly saddened by Derek&amp;rsquo;s death. He inspired me to stay on the path to becoming a writer. He has inspired so many with his willingness to help others and with his words. Derek wrote with a sincerity that is rare in a world full of people who are scared of writing the truth. Me included. So here&amp;rsquo;s to you Derek - your voice is now silent but you will never be forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>