<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/categories/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2008 02:23:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/categories/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Print Futures 2008 Portfolio Show</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/print-futures-2008-portfolio-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2008 02:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/print-futures-2008-portfolio-show/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/Print%20Futures%20Portfolio%20Show%202008.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come and support the grads of the Print Futures program at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.douglas.bc.ca/programs/print-futures/special-events/portfolio-show.html&#34;&gt;our portfolio show&lt;/a&gt; this Thursday from 4:30pm to 7:30pm. You can drop in or stay for the whole event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;ll be free food, free music, and free conversation with some of the most talented writers this side of the Fraser River. The booze you&amp;rsquo;ll have to pay for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heading to DocTrain West</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/heading-to-doctrain-west/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2008 02:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/heading-to-doctrain-west/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/doctrain.west.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won a ticket to this year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.doctrain.com/west/&#34;&gt;DocTrain West&lt;/a&gt; conference through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stcwestcoast.ca/index.php&#34;&gt;Westcoast STC&lt;/a&gt;! I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank the organizer Scott Abel and the good people at the STC for giving me this terrific opportunity. As I mentioned before, if you can afford the $899, or have a generous employer, then be there or don&amp;rsquo;t-be-square.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference expounds future of CMS</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/conference-expounds-future-of-cms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 00:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/conference-expounds-future-of-cms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/cci2008logo.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content convergence and integration conference was a mind-blowing excursion into the wild terrains of content management. For those confused by the conference title, let me tell you the gist of it (from what I could gather).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in the information age, yet for the most part organizations fail to use content as a commodity and a valuable asset. As writers, we need to impress upon decision makers that the strategic use of content can indeed achieve the goals of the company, and is not a superfluous add-on. Furthermore, we can leverage social media and new ways of organizing content (such as folksonomy and dynamic publishing) to create a heightened user experience that goes beyond the traditional user manual. Oh, but for more conservative companies, the traditional manual works just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, there&amp;rsquo;s more to it than that - a lot more. Presentations ran the gambit from DAM to DITA to XML and everything in between. It was a pleasure to volunteer at the event and work with the fine folks at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.strategya.ca/&#34;&gt;the Strategy A consulting group&lt;/a&gt;, who were responsible for organizing and running the show.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Convergence &amp; Integration 2008</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/content-convergence-integration-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2008 00:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/content-convergence-integration-2008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/header.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://convergence.confabb.com/conferences/cci2008&#34;&gt;This conference&lt;/a&gt; kicked off in Vancouver today and is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place to be if you&amp;rsquo;re facing content management issues in your professional life as a technical writer, or if you want to stay on the leading edge of developments in the field. Each day has a specific theme. Day 1 (today) is about content, day 2 about technology, and day 3 about user relationships. I&amp;rsquo;ll be volunteering there the whole day tomorrow, and will tell you all about it later (if you&amp;rsquo;re going, be sure to say hello).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights? The future of XML publishing, the new Quark dynamic publishing demos, social media, mobile content management , and of course, the fabulous food.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pearls book launch</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/pearls-book-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 03:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/pearls-book-launch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/Pearls%2027.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday I had the pleasure of attending the 27th Pearls book launch, the annual anthology of creative writing works by Douglas College students. My story, &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/the-reluctant-teacher.pdf&#34;&gt;The Reluctant Teacher&lt;/a&gt;, was published in it this year. I&amp;rsquo;ve had some poetry published in Pearls before, but that was about 8 years ago, so it&amp;rsquo;s been a while. A few of the authors read by candlelight and I got to see a few familiar faces. Good times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Northern Voice a wrap</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/northern-voice-a-wrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2008 08:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/northern-voice-a-wrap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/poster1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad I was able to attend Northern Voice this year - it was informative and inspiring for the most part. All the clicking laptops around me were a bit daunting, but gave me something to aspire to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning kicked off with the keynote address by &lt;a href=&#34;http://ma.tt&#34;&gt;Matt Mullenweg&lt;/a&gt;, founder of Wordpress (the excellent blogging platform on which this website is based). Listen to &lt;a href=&#34;http://atlargemedia.com/content/podcast-matt-mullenweg-keynote-northern-voice-2008&#34;&gt;the audio&lt;/a&gt; here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then listened to a talk by the CEO of Broadband Mechanics, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marc_Canter&#34;&gt;Marc Canter&lt;/a&gt; on bringing social to software. Next was an inspirational diatribe on the state of our stats-obsessed blogging world by &lt;a href=&#34;http://uncleweed.net/&#34;&gt;Dave Olson&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, Alan Levine gave us &lt;a href=&#34;http://cogdogroo.wikispaces.com/50+Ways&#34;&gt;50 web 2.0 ways to tell a story&lt;/a&gt; (his was a tearjerker about a dog). Vancouver photographer &lt;a href=&#34;http://kriskrug.com/&#34;&gt;Kris Krug&lt;/a&gt; then faced off against his mentor &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alexwaterhousehayward.com/index.php&#34;&gt;Alex Waterhouse-Hayward&lt;/a&gt; on the best medium for photography - hard copy or digital?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.socialsignal.com/blog/rob-cottingham&#34;&gt;Rob Cottingham&lt;/a&gt; gave a talk called Blogger 911, about using blogs for crisis communications, something we&amp;rsquo;re doing a lot of in PR class. He also draws some great cartoons about social media - check them out on his page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall it was worth going and I&amp;rsquo;ll be going next year - hopefully with a laptop this time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Come to Northern Voice 2008</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/come-to-northern-voice-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 05:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/come-to-northern-voice-2008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/Banner2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Banner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a hardcore blogger or just thinking of starting one up, you can&amp;rsquo;t miss &lt;a href=&#34;http://2008.northernvoice.ca/&#34;&gt;Northern Voice&lt;/a&gt;, Vancouver&amp;rsquo;s 4th blogging and social media conference. This event gets bigger and more popular every year, but is still &amp;ldquo;cheap, friendly and open to all.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s only $40 for one day ($60 for both).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a similar note, the second &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.doctrain.com/west/&#34;&gt;DocTrain West&lt;/a&gt; is coming to Vancouver in May and the topic is - gosh, what a shocker - Web 2.0 and it&amp;rsquo;s impact on communication. If you have $999 to spare, or maybe a generous employer, then do attend - it&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;em&gt;crème de la crème&lt;/em&gt; of conferences for technical communicators.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>