<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editing on wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/categories/editing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editing on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 05:21:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/categories/editing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Editors, check your bullet lists</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/editors-check-your-bullet-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 05:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/editors-check-your-bullet-lists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing like a slip-up in bullet list formatting to completely change meaning. Check out this hilarious example from failblog.org:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/09/fail-owned-responsibility-list-fail.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/09/fail-owned-responsibility-list-fail_thumb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;fail-owned-responsibility-list-fail&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that&amp;rsquo;s a major copy-editing FAIL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My big audience</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/my-big-audience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2007 08:27:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/my-big-audience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/11/853246_27495155.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;853246_27495155&#34; /&gt; I was trying to figure out how many people are reading my writing/editing and the numbers are pretty huge. First of all, I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing for the print edition of &lt;a href=&#34;http://alive.com&#34;&gt;alive&lt;/a&gt; at a readership of about 500,000. Then every Tuesday articles I&amp;rsquo;ve edited for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metronews.ca/&#34;&gt;Metro Canada&lt;/a&gt; comes out countrywide at a readership of 700,000. And the tips of the day I write for Living Naturally are published on at least 7000 websites in the US and Canada, according to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.ca/search?hl=en&amp;amp;safe=off&amp;amp;q=%22This+internet+site+is+hosted+by+Living+Naturally%2C+a+Web+site+service+provider+to+natural+health+stores+nationwide.%22+&amp;amp;btnG=Search&amp;amp;meta=&#34;&gt;this Google search&lt;/a&gt;. Of course my name is only attached to the stuff I write in the magazine, but still, that&amp;rsquo;s a large audience to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;m having an off day and rush through an article that 700,000 people are going to read. Then, when it comes out, I look at it and think &amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe this drivel got published. I really should have spent more time on this&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Or &amp;ldquo;Ultimate Frisbee in December? What the heck was I thinking?&amp;rdquo;  It&amp;rsquo;s a humbling experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural sensitivity in user documentation</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/cultural-sensitivity-in-user-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 09:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/cultural-sensitivity-in-user-documentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/02/WindowsLiveWriter/Culturalsensitivityinuserdocumentation_AA6/angry%20leprechaun%5B4%5D.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt; When editing technical documents, how aware should you be of regional differences in pronunciation? Here is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.redhatmagazine.com/2007/02/26/how-to-write-really-good-documentationsemi-definite-rules-for-the-indefinite-article/&#34;&gt;an interesting article&lt;/a&gt; on the subject by Brian Forte. Forte raises the following issue regarding the usage of an indefinite article with initialisms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;How do you pronounce an initialism like HTML?

I was taught English in public Australian schools of the 1970s. So I was taught _aitch_ rather than _haitch._ Which means I pronounce ‘HTML’ with an initial vowel sound and I write ‘an HTML page.’

If I’d gone to a private Irish Catholic school, however, I would have been taught _haitch_ and would, naturally enough, think ‘a HTML page’ is correct.&lt;!-- more --&gt;

More generally, _haitch_ is standard in Hiberno-English and is a way for disputing Protestant and Catholic Northern Irelanders to distinguish themselves from each other.

So, if I insist on ‘an HTML page’ I’m telling 4.5 million English speakers their way of writing and speaking is wrong, or non-standard at the very least. And I can’t reveal accent by writing ‘an ’TML page’ because it’s a technical document, not a novel.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously though, how many Irish Catholics are going to tear up their Linux manuals in disgust after discovering a pernicious &amp;ldquo;an&amp;rdquo; embedded in the text? It&amp;rsquo;s nothing personal. Technical writers are just following a style guide. Some tech writers will go with &amp;ldquo;a html&amp;rdquo; because they look at the expanded form of the initialism. So &amp;ldquo;a Hypertext Markup Language Page&amp;rdquo; would be written as &amp;ldquo;a html&amp;rdquo;. Does that mean everybody who pronounces &amp;ldquo;h&amp;rdquo; as &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;aitch&amp;rdquo; (which is the majority of the English-speaking world) should label these writers as hate-mongering, prejudiced Irish Catholics?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all comes down to schisms in pronunciation. Yet, in today&amp;rsquo;s globalized world, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much room to argue with the majority.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>