<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cci2008 on wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/categories/cci2008/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cci2008 on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 00:56:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/categories/cci2008/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference expounds future of CMS</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/conference-expounds-future-of-cms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 00:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/conference-expounds-future-of-cms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/cci2008logo.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content convergence and integration conference was a mind-blowing excursion into the wild terrains of content management. For those confused by the conference title, let me tell you the gist of it (from what I could gather).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in the information age, yet for the most part organizations fail to use content as a commodity and a valuable asset. As writers, we need to impress upon decision makers that the strategic use of content can indeed achieve the goals of the company, and is not a superfluous add-on. Furthermore, we can leverage social media and new ways of organizing content (such as folksonomy and dynamic publishing) to create a heightened user experience that goes beyond the traditional user manual. Oh, but for more conservative companies, the traditional manual works just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, there&amp;rsquo;s more to it than that - a lot more. Presentations ran the gambit from DAM to DITA to XML and everything in between. It was a pleasure to volunteer at the event and work with the fine folks at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.strategya.ca/&#34;&gt;the Strategy A consulting group&lt;/a&gt;, who were responsible for organizing and running the show.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Convergence &amp; Integration 2008</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/content-convergence-integration-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2008 00:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/content-convergence-integration-2008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/header.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://convergence.confabb.com/conferences/cci2008&#34;&gt;This conference&lt;/a&gt; kicked off in Vancouver today and is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place to be if you&amp;rsquo;re facing content management issues in your professional life as a technical writer, or if you want to stay on the leading edge of developments in the field. Each day has a specific theme. Day 1 (today) is about content, day 2 about technology, and day 3 about user relationships. I&amp;rsquo;ll be volunteering there the whole day tomorrow, and will tell you all about it later (if you&amp;rsquo;re going, be sure to say hello).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights? The future of XML publishing, the new Quark dynamic publishing demos, social media, mobile content management , and of course, the fabulous food.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>