<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nv08 on wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/categories/nv08/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nv08 on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2008 08:11:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/categories/nv08/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Northern Voice a wrap</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/northern-voice-a-wrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2008 08:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/northern-voice-a-wrap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/02/poster1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;poster&#34; /&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m glad I was able to attend Northern Voice this year - it was informative and inspiring for the most part. All the clicking laptops around me were a bit daunting, but gave me something to aspire to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning kicked off with the keynote address by &lt;a href=&#34;http://ma.tt&#34;&gt;Matt Mullenweg&lt;/a&gt;, founder of Wordpress (the excellent blogging platform on which this website is based). Listen to &lt;a href=&#34;http://atlargemedia.com/content/podcast-matt-mullenweg-keynote-northern-voice-2008&#34;&gt;the audio&lt;/a&gt; here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then listened to a talk by the CEO of Broadband Mechanics, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marc_Canter&#34;&gt;Marc Canter&lt;/a&gt; on bringing social to software. Next was an inspirational diatribe on the state of our stats-obsessed blogging world by &lt;a href=&#34;http://uncleweed.net/&#34;&gt;Dave Olson&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, Alan Levine gave us &lt;a href=&#34;http://cogdogroo.wikispaces.com/50+Ways&#34;&gt;50 web 2.0 ways to tell a story&lt;/a&gt; (his was a tearjerker about a dog). Vancouver photographer &lt;a href=&#34;http://kriskrug.com/&#34;&gt;Kris Krug&lt;/a&gt; then faced off against his mentor &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alexwaterhousehayward.com/index.php&#34;&gt;Alex Waterhouse-Hayward&lt;/a&gt; on the best medium for photography - hard copy or digital?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.socialsignal.com/blog/rob-cottingham&#34;&gt;Rob Cottingham&lt;/a&gt; gave a talk called Blogger 911, about using blogs for crisis communications, something we&amp;rsquo;re doing a lot of in PR class. He also draws some great cartoons about social media - check them out on his page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall it was worth going and I&amp;rsquo;ll be going next year - hopefully with a laptop this time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>