<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources on wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/categories/resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resources on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 05:38:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/categories/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>21st century tips on finding work</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/21st-century-tips-on-finding-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 05:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/21st-century-tips-on-finding-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/JobSearchNewspaper1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may as well recycle those newspaper classifieds, because that old school job-finding tool belongs in the 20th century. Spurred on by the recession, a number of tech-savvy people have started blogging on various &amp;ldquo;new school&amp;rdquo; ways of getting a job. Tech evangelist Robert Scoble has &lt;a href=&#34;http://scobleizer.com/2009/01/12/if-you-are-laid-off-heres-how-to-socially-network/&#34;&gt;some crafty tips&lt;/a&gt;. I tend to agree with him when he says your blog is your résumé. After all, google my name and this blog is the first search result (and if you are a hiring manager, then please note my correct formatting of the word &lt;em&gt;résumé&lt;/em&gt;!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local writer and social media consultant Monica Hamburg talks about how to tap into the hidden job market online in &lt;a href=&#34;http://monicahamburg.wordpress.com/2009/01/13/job-search-new-school/&#34;&gt;her excellent blog post&lt;/a&gt;. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether you&amp;rsquo;re a Java programmer or a hairdresser - creating an online presence and fostering a network can benefit you. If nothing else, it&amp;rsquo;s way more fun than cold calling!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas shopping deals</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/christmas-shopping-deals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 05:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/christmas-shopping-deals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/pres.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the economy is caught in a perpetual flush cycle and the government is crumbling under the pressure of imminent deficits. You&amp;rsquo;re waiting for HR to ask you to stop by so they can talk about &amp;ldquo;restructuring&amp;rdquo;. You&amp;rsquo;re wondering if you can even afford to drive to the mall this holiday season, let alone buy mounds of stuff there. Well, no worries. Here are some resources for thrifty Canadians with the most meagre of budgets, because let&amp;rsquo;s face it - right now it&amp;rsquo;s cool to be cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t waste your time surfing around for deals, I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a list of the eight best Canadian deal sites out there for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pricecanada.com/&#34;&gt;Pricecanada.com&lt;/a&gt; - a shopping search engine that allows you to compare prices among numerous retailers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.redflagdeals.com/&#34;&gt;Redflagdeals.com&lt;/a&gt; - One of Canada&amp;rsquo;s oldest and best deals and freebies websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bigbigforums.com/&#34;&gt;Bigbigforums.com&lt;/a&gt; - Where cheapskate-wannabes gather in droves to discuss the latest scoop on deals, coupons and contests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://slickdeals.net/&#34;&gt;Slickdeals.net&lt;/a&gt; - This frequently updated site has Deal Alerts&amp;hellip;sweet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pricenetwork.ca/deals.php?d=315&amp;amp;s=0&#34;&gt;Pricenetwork.ca&lt;/a&gt; - On this site, people can vote on the hottest deals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pricegrabber.ca/&#34;&gt;Pricegrabber.ca&lt;/a&gt; - Another comparison shopping website that allows you to customize your own shopping list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://smartcanucks.ca/&#34;&gt;Smartcanucks.ca&lt;/a&gt; - The first Canadian deals blog (or so they claim).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://coupons.lockergnome.com/&#34;&gt;Lockergnome coupons&lt;/a&gt; - Chris Pirillo&amp;rsquo;s coupon search engine creates custom search RSS feeds. Niiiiice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe that 42 inch TV isn&amp;rsquo;t out of your reach after all? Now dust off your credit card and do your part for the economy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telemarketer&#39;s bane</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/telemarketers-bane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 01:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/telemarketers-bane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/telemarketer_art.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been almost a month since the launch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lnnte-dncl.gc.ca/index-eng&#34;&gt;Canada&amp;rsquo;s National Do Not Call List&lt;/a&gt;. If you signed up on September 30th, your right to slam a deviant telemarketer will kick in this October 30th. Sweet. When will companies learn that people telemarketing is the second most hated form of privacy invasion on this planet (Door-to-door marketing holds the number one spot in my mind)? Even junk mail doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem as bad, as annoying as it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, however, telemarketers have it tough. Not only can they get fined for contravening the DNC list, but they have to contend with a new trend - these days most people have cell phones, not land lines. Sure, you could screen the call using Caller ID, but here&amp;rsquo;s something better: once you have the number of a telemarketer, program an entry in your directory. I use the moniker &amp;ldquo;Do Not Answer&amp;rdquo;. I then set the customized ringer to &amp;ldquo;Do not ring&amp;rdquo;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had to speak to a telemarketer in five years. And because I&amp;rsquo;m feeling generous, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to share my sacred list with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, bear in mind that this list is only valid if you live in Canada - and the 604 numbers are only valid for the Vancouver area. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve confirmed that all these numbers are telemarketers of the most heinous kind. Do yourself a favour and block &amp;lsquo;em all. So, here&amp;rsquo;s a little list of my own - a Do Not Answer list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;866-428-1656&lt;br /&gt;
800-837-9531&lt;br /&gt;
604-270-7289&lt;br /&gt;
416-915-7933&lt;br /&gt;
866-428-1469&lt;br /&gt;
800-566-8064&lt;br /&gt;
866-629-7707&lt;br /&gt;
866-701-8375&lt;br /&gt;
416-581-1076&lt;br /&gt;
877-666-6339&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you haven&amp;rsquo;t signed up for the DNC list, what are you waiting for?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find a tech-writing job in Vancouver - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/find-a-tech-writing-job-in-vancouver-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/find-a-tech-writing-job-in-vancouver-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/vancouver-canada.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to start a series on finding a tech-writing job specifically in the high-tech hub of Vancouver, BC (which is where I happen to live). As I started the job search process myself, I noticed a dearth of information on this topic. I hope I can dig up some useful info for those in a similar position - eventually I&amp;rsquo;ll port this stuff over to my resources page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, without further ado, here is part 1, which will focus on job search engines. Sure, you&amp;rsquo;ll get 20% of jobs this way ( the other 80% you&amp;rsquo;ll find through the hidden job market), but it seems a good way to start. And after all, you might just might get lucky and beat the hordes of job seekers all vying for the same position&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some job search engines tailored specifically to the high-tech industry in Vancouver:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techvibes.com/job/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/techvibes_logo.gif&#34; alt=&#34;techvibes_logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techjobsvancouver.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/techjobsvan1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;techjobsvan&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bctechnology.com/frameset_emp.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/tnet1.gif&#34; alt=&#34;tnet&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devbistro.com/jobs/city/Vancouver/loc/Canada-BC&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/db1.gif&#34; alt=&#34;db&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://seeker.dice.com/jobsearch/servlet/JobSearch?Ntx=mode+matchall&amp;amp;FRMT=0&amp;amp;COUNTRY=1338&amp;amp;N=0&amp;amp;Hf=0&amp;amp;Ntk=JobSearchRanking&amp;amp;NUM_PER_PAGE=30&amp;amp;op=300&amp;amp;y=16&amp;amp;LOCATION_OPTION=3&amp;amp;x=32&amp;amp;TAXTERM=0&amp;amp;caller=0&amp;amp;DAYSBACK=30&amp;amp;TRAVEL=0&amp;amp;Ns=p_Municipality|1&amp;amp;SORTDIR=6&amp;amp;SORTSPEC=0&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/dice.gif&#34; alt=&#34;dice&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then of course there are the more generic search engines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vancouver.craigslist.ca/&#34;&gt;Craigslist&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eluta.ca/&#34;&gt;Eluta&lt;/a&gt; (I highly recommended this one), &lt;a href=&#34;http://monster.ca/&#34;&gt;Monster&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bcjobs.ca/&#34;&gt;BC jobs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.workopolis.com&#34;&gt;Workopolis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.working.com&#34;&gt;Working&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jobbank.gc.ca/&#34;&gt;Job Bank&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ca.hotjobs.yahoo.com/&#34;&gt;Hot Jobs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For search terms, a simple boolean search (writer OR editor) normally does the trick, but you can get more specific if you want (technical communicator, information architect, etc.). There&amp;rsquo;s no perfect search term. So, start clicking and have fun checking out all those juicy (yet ephemeral) jobs out there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In part 2, I&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing the interview - look for it later this week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gotta love that British humour</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/gotta-love-that-british-humour/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2007 21:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/gotta-love-that-british-humour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:10px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/The_Register_r.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get your science and techie news served up with a healthy dose of Brit witticisms. Check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theregister.com/&#34;&gt;The Register&lt;/a&gt;, a highly readable site out of the UK that dishes the sarcasm along with the geek factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:10px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/top.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;em&gt;alive&lt;/em&gt; - in conjunction with The Good Life Network has just launched their podcast page. You can here my boss Terry-Lynn being interviewed by the silver-tongued Jesse Dylan at &lt;a href=&#34;http://aliveonair.com/&#34;&gt;aliveonair.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over 120000 free technical writing articles</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/over-120000-free-technical-writing-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 06:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/over-120000-free-technical-writing-articles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a valuable resource that no technical writer, or technical-writing student, can do without: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tc.eserver.org/&#34;&gt;The EServer TC Library&lt;/a&gt;, a free library of articles on all manner of relevant subjects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/eserver%5B8%5D.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll also put this up on my resources page. A lot of these articles are derived from STC conferences and are available in PDF format.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>