<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/categories/politics/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/categories/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Telemarketer&#39;s bane</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/telemarketers-bane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 01:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/telemarketers-bane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/telemarketer_art.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been almost a month since the launch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lnnte-dncl.gc.ca/index-eng&#34;&gt;Canada&amp;rsquo;s National Do Not Call List&lt;/a&gt;. If you signed up on September 30th, your right to slam a deviant telemarketer will kick in this October 30th. Sweet. When will companies learn that people telemarketing is the second most hated form of privacy invasion on this planet (Door-to-door marketing holds the number one spot in my mind)? Even junk mail doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem as bad, as annoying as it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, however, telemarketers have it tough. Not only can they get fined for contravening the DNC list, but they have to contend with a new trend - these days most people have cell phones, not land lines. Sure, you could screen the call using Caller ID, but here&amp;rsquo;s something better: once you have the number of a telemarketer, program an entry in your directory. I use the moniker &amp;ldquo;Do Not Answer&amp;rdquo;. I then set the customized ringer to &amp;ldquo;Do not ring&amp;rdquo;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had to speak to a telemarketer in five years. And because I&amp;rsquo;m feeling generous, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to share my sacred list with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, bear in mind that this list is only valid if you live in Canada - and the 604 numbers are only valid for the Vancouver area. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve confirmed that all these numbers are telemarketers of the most heinous kind. Do yourself a favour and block &amp;lsquo;em all. So, here&amp;rsquo;s a little list of my own - a Do Not Answer list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;866-428-1656&lt;br /&gt;
800-837-9531&lt;br /&gt;
604-270-7289&lt;br /&gt;
416-915-7933&lt;br /&gt;
866-428-1469&lt;br /&gt;
800-566-8064&lt;br /&gt;
866-629-7707&lt;br /&gt;
866-701-8375&lt;br /&gt;
416-581-1076&lt;br /&gt;
877-666-6339&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you haven&amp;rsquo;t signed up for the DNC list, what are you waiting for?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet privacy saves lives</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/internet-privacy-that-saves-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2008 23:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/internet-privacy-that-saves-lives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/censorshipchina.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how many firewalls, P2P filters, script blockers, or spyware removers you use, the one giveaway to your identity on the Internet is your IP address. Those numbers will trumpet your location to whoever&amp;rsquo;s interested, which is why you&amp;rsquo;ll often see annoying ads like &amp;ldquo;Find friends in (insert your city here) now!&amp;rdquo; This lack of privacy is a huge problem for political dissidents in China, or for anyone in that country who wants to surf an uncensored version of the net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there are anonymous proxies that you can use to redirect your traffic through servers in &amp;lsquo;safe&amp;rsquo; countries. One piece of software that does this extremely well is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ultrareach.com/company/download.htm&#34;&gt;Ultrasurf 8&lt;/a&gt; by Ultrareach Internet Corp. Ultrasurf was designed specifically to provide surfing freedom and anonymity to the Chinese. The beauty of this software is that is searches for the fastest US proxies in the background while encrypting Internet Explorer so that you will never be hounded by the Chinese Internet police. Plugins like Firefox&amp;rsquo;s ProxySwitch, or ad-supported software like Hotspot Shield are not nearly as good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/YentoCensor.gif&#34; alt=&#34;YentoCensor&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefits for Canadians of using this software is that you can get around copyright restrictions on streaming your favourite US TV shows from network sites, or streaming music on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pandora.com/&#34;&gt;pandora&lt;/a&gt;. I do not endorse engaging in these sorts of activities, of course, but thought you should be aware of the possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPod levy rejected</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/ipod-levy-rejected/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 06:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/ipod-levy-rejected/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/story1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a wannabe iPod disciple and &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/ipod-price-hike/&#34;&gt;the rumour of an iPod levy&lt;/a&gt; had you on your knees praying for an intervention, your prayers have been answered. Canada&amp;rsquo;s federal court told the Canadian Copyright Board they had &amp;ldquo;no authority&amp;rdquo; to impose the levy, according to this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cbc.ca/consumer/story/2008/01/11/levy-recorders.html?ref=rss&#34;&gt;CBC News article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, this is good news indeed. I already find it cheaper to buy blank CDs in the States and would hate to cross the border to buy electronic goods as well. I&amp;rsquo;m also glad the government isn&amp;rsquo;t treating us all like a bunch of mp3 pirates who are intent on downloading every Celine Dion and Bryan Adams album we can lay our thieving hands on (because we all know how much Canadian music rocks).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPod price hike?</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/ipod-price-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 21:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/ipod-price-hike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/490822_53990118.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be aware of Canada&amp;rsquo;s Private Copyright Collective, the organization responsible for the ridiculous levy on blank audio cassettes and CDs. Now this collective is lobbying hard for a levy on recording devices such as MP3 players, cellphones, computers, and anything you can record with basically. Their argument is that just because you can pirate music on these devices, you should pay for it. These extortionist royalties are distributed to eligible songwriters, musicians, and record production companies (although the collective is unclear on who exactly is eligible - they don&amp;rsquo;t even have to be Canadian).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Copyright Board has approved the collective&amp;rsquo;s proposal and the government is promising new legislation that may be implemented before Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you very likely will be paying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra $5 on devices with up to one gigabyte (GB) of memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra $25 for one to 10 GB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra $50 for between 10 GB and 30 GB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra $75 for over 30 GB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holy smokes! Run out and get your 160 Gig iPod while you can&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four more cents</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/four-more-cents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2007 20:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/four-more-cents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Writer&amp;rsquo;s Guild of America are striking, but do you know why? Check out this three-minute video clip for an explanation. Or you could just watch more re-runs and hope that your favourite show will come back&amp;hellip;eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oJ55Ir2jCxk&amp;amp;w&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/oJ55Ir2jCxk/mqdefault.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electronic rights for authors seems a fair deal, but lets be honest - These guys are making a lot more money than writers outside of the film industry. I wonder if editors have ever gone on strike?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yahoo on trial</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/yahoo-on-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2007 19:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/yahoo-on-trial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/yahoo_thumb.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a congressional hearing held on Tuesday November 6 as part of a lawsuit against Yahoo, CEO Jerry Yang and vice-president Michael Callahan were chastised for their involvement in the arrest and imprisonment of a Chinese journalist. Yahoo is currently on trial for aiding and abetting in the torture of Chinese dissidents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2005, Chinese journalist Shi Tao was convicted by his government for divulging “state secrets”. Shi Tao had forwarded an email from the Communist Party warning the media not to observe the 15th anniversary of the Tiananmen Square massacre in 2004. Yahoo provided information to the government which helped identify Shi Tao as a dissident. He was sentenced to 10 years imprisonment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2006, Michael Callahan, Yahoo&amp;rsquo;s executive vice-president and general counsel told the congressional panel that he did not know why the Chinese government wanted Shi Tao. In the November 6 hearing, it was revealed that this testimony was false—Yahoo officials had in fact received a document outlining the nature of the investigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the hearing, house foreign affairs committee chairman Tom Lantos delivered a statement where he said that &amp;ldquo;Yahoo claims that this is just one big misunderstanding. Let me be clear — this was no misunderstanding. This was inexcusably negligent behaviour at best and deliberately deceptive behaviour at worst.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either Yahoo has some major internal communication problems or they&amp;rsquo;re so desperate for a piece of the Chinese Internet market that they&amp;rsquo;re willing to jump into bed with an oppressive Communist government no matter what the cost. I really hope for their sake that it&amp;rsquo;s the former.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vancouver police incites wrath of editor</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/vancouver-police-incites-wrath-of-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2007 06:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/vancouver-police-incites-wrath-of-editor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/oly-protest%5B5%5D.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of you may know that Vancouver is hosting the 2010 Olympic Games and that the Vancouver Olympic Organizing Committee (VANOC) has been under fire for booting the impoverished out of the downtown eastside to make the streets pretty for the impending tourist influx. You may also have heard of anti-poverty activist David Cunningham, who threatened to symbolically evict all the board members of VANOC from their plush homes by camping on their lawn and performing some kind of ritual. Well, the VANOC members didn&amp;rsquo;t appreciate that and pressed charges, which led to this latest development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Vancouver police officer actually had the balls to impersonate a newspaper reporter (from 24-Hours) and arrange an &amp;ldquo;interview&amp;rdquo; with David at a mall, whereupon he was promptly arrested. Give me a break. Have the Vancouver police no integrity whatsoever? The editor-in-chief of 24-Hours is rightly miffed, according to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cbc.ca/canada/british-columbia/story/2007/05/21/24hours-arrest.html&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, where he says that these sorts of ploys undermine trust in the media and destroy credibility. What was that cop thinking? He obviously thought 24-Hours doesn&amp;rsquo;t have enough independent clout to adopt an anti-police stance in their editorial, and he&amp;rsquo;s probably right. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean other media aren&amp;rsquo;t going to have a field day with this one. Naughty, naughty Mr. Policeman.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>