<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geeky on wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/categories/geeky/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geeky on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2011 00:54:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/categories/geeky/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Three amazing new technologies that will blow your mind</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/three-amazing-new-technologies-that-will-blow-your-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2011 00:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/three-amazing-new-technologies-that-will-blow-your-mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about the future and what it might bring. In my last post I talked about a 1988 school project that accurately predicted the dawn of the tablet age. Well, here are three emerging technologies that are quite simply gob smacking. You have to see these videos to believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quantum Levitation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know that magnetic forces repel and attract, but did you know these laws can be bended so an object stays fixed in empty space? Check this out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[youtube &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ws6AAhTw7RA?wmode=transparent&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ws6AAhTw7RA?wmode=transparent&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holographic Interface:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know the holodeck on Star Trek? Maybe it isn&amp;rsquo;t so far-fetched after all. Using the Microsoft Kinect, these guys have created a holographic interface where you can interact with holographic objects as if they were real:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[youtube &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JHL5tJ9ja_w?wmode=transparent&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JHL5tJ9ja_w?wmode=transparent&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dream Recorder:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers have used Youtube as a massive database to analyze imagery and hooked it up to a brain scanner to correlate brain patterns. This data was then used to literally display the thoughts of the subject as they dreamt. What the hell? Minority Report anyone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[youtube &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nsjDnYxJ0bo?wmode=transparent&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nsjDnYxJ0bo?wmode=transparent&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefly: My review</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/firefly-my-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 20:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/firefly-my-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/firefly_series_main.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/firefly_series_main.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;firefly_series_main&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently finished watching the complete &lt;em&gt;Firefly&lt;/em&gt; series on Netflix. That sounds like a lot of TV watching, but it only ran for 14 episodes before it got cancelled due to low ratings. Most geeks agree, however, that this show was a little gem, was poorly marketed by Fox, and should never have died so early. After watching it, I would have to agree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess this show falls into the space-western genre, and with plenty of horses, bandits, prostitutes, and bounty hunters, I&amp;rsquo;d say it falls more into the &amp;ldquo;western&amp;rdquo; part of the spectrum. The CGI is a bit dated, but not bad for 2002. What really drives the show are the terrific characters, with particularly strong female leads, and wonderful camaraderie among the crew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a liberal sprinkling of romance thrown in, I can see why both genders enjoy this show immensely. The creator, Joss Whedon, played with several sub genres throughout the too-short series, with suspense, horror, adventure, and comedy providing a different mood for any given episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the negative side, I&amp;rsquo;d have to say that the acting and the overall story arc is not as good as the crazy-good Battlestar Gallactica - but it would be hard for any Sci-Fi to come close. Given a chance, this show could have blossomed in its maturity. Too bad it was axed in its infancy. I will definitely be watching the follow-up movie, &lt;em&gt;Serenity&lt;/em&gt;, which the fans basically demanded into being. A lot of questions were left unanswered, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to some closure. Recently there was some talk of resurrecting the show independently and putting it out on the internet. Probably not going to happen, but there&amp;rsquo;s always hope.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>