<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Article on wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/categories/article/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Article on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 23:13:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/categories/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>No rest for the dead…battery</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/no-rest-for-the-deadbattery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 23:13:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/no-rest-for-the-deadbattery/</guid>
      <description>My recent article on Battery Recycling is now available in the November issue of alive. I wasn’t aware of this before researching this topic, but you can recycle both single-use and rechargeable batteries in British Columbia.
Personally, I’m a big fan of eneloop batteries. I believe the batteries Apple uses in their wireless mouse and keyboard are re-branded eneloops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New published articles</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/new-published-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 00:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/new-published-articles/</guid>
      <description>Here are some new articles of mine that were published in alive magazine. Click on the thumbnails to view them. The first is on whether cell phone towers are safe or not. There is much heated debate surrounding this issue and I got a lot of hate mail for even suggesting we don’t know all there is to know about the technology. The hard truth is that we just don’t have the data spanning a human lifetime to say one way or the other, so lay off haters!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It pays to be paranoid</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/it-pays-to-be-paranoid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2010 22:48:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/it-pays-to-be-paranoid/</guid>
      <description>As 2010 hits in full force I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of ways to schedule in more quality blog time and keep wordbit alive. In the meantime, here is my latest article on how to avoid cold and flu germs. I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you but I&amp;rsquo;ve run the germ gambit from Swine to March Madness varieties and I&amp;rsquo;ve had enough. So it&amp;rsquo;s apt then that my article recommends borderline conspiracy theory-fueled paranoid behaviour to avoid catching a sniffle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A veritable article fest</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/a-veritable-article-fest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 03:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/a-veritable-article-fest/</guid>
      <description>This year has been busy and exciting and just plain exhausting. But I&amp;rsquo;ve finally found some time to upload a bunch of the articles that I&amp;rsquo;ve had published this year for alive and blush magazines. The majority focus on green issues. I&amp;rsquo;ve been somewhat typecast as the devil&amp;rsquo;s green advocate, being asked to find flaws in all manner of righteous green concepts. To read one, click on the image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheap winter thrills</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/cheap-winter-thrills/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 04:47:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/cheap-winter-thrills/</guid>
      <description>So, you&amp;rsquo;ve done all your Christmas shopping, and maybe scored a few deals by reading my last blog post. Now you want to have some fun in the snow but the rocky economic climate is scaring you off the slopes. Continuing on the theme of thrifty spending, check out my latest article on finding deals on winter sports equipment (while being eco-savvy at the same time).
I enjoyed writing this article because, well, I&amp;rsquo;m a SME when it comes to being cheap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surf&#39;s up - and so is your heart rate</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/surfs-up-and-so-is-your-heart-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 05:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/surfs-up-and-so-is-your-heart-rate/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s probably the cheesiest line I&amp;rsquo;ve ever written. But for some reason, the editors over at alive actually seem to revel in cheese (One example is the title I&amp;rsquo;ll eternally shake my head at: G&amp;hellip;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s a Glycemic index). God bless &amp;lsquo;em though - they&amp;rsquo;re a wonderful bunch.
Anyway, here&amp;rsquo;s an article I really enjoyed writing because, well, I love surfing! And so does Scott over in the art department.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have a laugh, have a cry</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/have-a-laugh-have-a-cry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 04:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/have-a-laugh-have-a-cry/</guid>
      <description>Here are some recent article shorts. As usual, you can click on the thumbnails to read them. The one on the left is a feel-good piece on laughter yoga. The right piece touches on the depressing psychological and cultural effects of global warming. There&amp;rsquo;s also a teeny one in there on the dodgy air we have to breathe in airplanes (even Purell won&amp;rsquo;t save you this time).
 
Seeing these two articles juxtaposed like this evokes a stark contrast between Western frivolity and Aboriginal reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reader letters warm my writer&#39;s heart</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/reader-letters-warm-my-writers-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 04:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/reader-letters-warm-my-writers-heart/</guid>
      <description>As you may or may not recall, last August my article on the evils of recycling was published. Sometimes I lose sight of the fact that thousands of people read the stuff I put out there. Some probably think it&amp;rsquo;s a load of tosh. Other slightly more creepy individuals google my name and usually ask some sort of favour. But others actually have something interesting to say. So Ben, even though you&amp;rsquo;ll never read this, thanks for your letter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s talk breakfast</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/lets-talk-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 03:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/lets-talk-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>Mmmmm&amp;hellip;.breakfast. Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy a nice hot cup of tea, toast with peanut butter, and a banana on the side? At least that&amp;rsquo;s what I have every morning. And yes, this useless preamble allows me to segue into my latest article on nutritious kid&amp;rsquo;s breakfasts. It&amp;rsquo;s a short piece but the artwork is nicely laid out in a groovy &amp;lsquo;70s inspired way. Good job art department!
To read the article, click on the thumbnail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recycling, global warming, and toxic toys</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/recycling-global-warming-and-toxic-toys/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 04:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/recycling-global-warming-and-toxic-toys/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t blogged in a while, and as Uncle Argyle says &amp;ldquo;Well that&amp;rsquo;s something we shall have to remedy, isn&amp;rsquo;t it&amp;rdquo; (That quote is from Braveheart, just in case you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen one of the greatest movies ever made). Unfortunately I&amp;rsquo;m keeping it short today - here are two of my articles from alive magazine&amp;rsquo;s July and August issues respectively. Click on the thumbnails to view them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check out my latest article</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/check-out-my-latest-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 00:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/check-out-my-latest-article/</guid>
      <description>alive magazine is out, and this month I have a men&amp;rsquo;s beauty article published called &amp;ldquo;Are you man enough to moisturize?&amp;rdquo; Click here to check it out. It&amp;rsquo;s meant to be informative, but it&amp;rsquo;s also a marketing piece because I mention a few products that potential retail customers might be interested in.
Also, I&amp;rsquo;ve recently updated my ePortfolio, which I&amp;rsquo;m going to recommend to all potential employers from now on. I&amp;rsquo;ve been sending out links to the portfolio on this blog, but that page is becoming a bit unwieldy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate relaxation techniques</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/ultimate-relaxation-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2008 18:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/ultimate-relaxation-techniques/</guid>
      <description>The May edition of alive magazine is out, and I have two articles published in it this month. A few months ago I interviewed stress guru Eli Bay about his relaxation techniques. Take a deep breath, relax for a few minutes and read his insights.
I also wrote a short piece on the rise of the mosquito population in our new era of rising temperatures. Mosquitoes love warm, moist climates, and they&amp;rsquo;re getting a lot of that these days.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>