<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 20:09:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Batman v Superman</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/batman-v-superman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 20:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/batman-v-superman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a poignant moment in &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade&lt;/em&gt; when the Holy Grail crosses the Great Seal and triggers the collapse of the Temple of the Sun. The earth is torn asunder, and Elsa, a Nazi agent and Austrian archaeologist, loses her life. After Indiana Jones fails to save her, he ends up hanging precariously in the crevice himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indiana’s father catches his hand and tries to pull him to safety. But, with his other hand, Indiana tries to reach the Holy Grail, which rests tantalizingly on a narrow ledge nearby. He can almost reach it; his fingertips brush it. But his father cannot hold on as oily sweat causes their hands to slip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indiana’s father (so aptly played by Sean Connery), says, in a soft, gentle voice: “Indiana… Indiana… let it go”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he does. As Indiana rides into the sunset and John William’s theme song swells over the closing credits, we knew it really was his last crusade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we were wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty years later, a considerably older and stiffer Harrison Ford donned Indie’s hat once more for a mostly terrible comeback movie with a crystal skull and that kid from &lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;/em&gt;. It wasn’t a huge deal though. At worst, the flick was nothing more than an embarrassing footnote, best ignored. At best, a bonus Blu-ray tacked onto the already excellent Indiana Jones trilogy box set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, they just couldn’t let it go. Indiana Jones is slated to return in 2019, starring an almost 80-year old Harrison Ford. There is no doubt in anyone’s mind that it will be humiliating and awful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also completely unsurprising. The status quo in a talent-starved Hollywood is to play it safe amid decreasing revenues. It has been this way for years now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cries of indignation from the fans are depressingly familiar. Please stop messing with my childhood. Please stop corrupting the purity of my trilogy box sets. Please stop commodifying nostalgia and cheapening the originals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Hollywood isn’t going to stop anytime soon, because they’ve hit upon a winning formula. Appeal to the nostalgia of older audiences while remixing, rebooting, and resurrecting box-office darlings for new audiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, this formula pays off. For example, the Star Wars reboot, &lt;em&gt;The Force Awakens&lt;/em&gt;, was an appealing return to the Star Wars universe, despite re-hashing the exact same plot of &lt;em&gt;A New Hope&lt;/em&gt;. But a strong female lead, a tight script, and J.J. Abrams managed to re-energize the property (I doubt whether the next Star Wars movies can repeat this feat).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most often, though, it is all too easy to overdo an homage to the original without being original - &lt;em&gt;Jurassic World&lt;/em&gt; springs to mind. Or to try too hard - an all-female &lt;em&gt;Ghostbusters&lt;/em&gt; reboot seems a bit blunt and unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, after all avenues have been explored, everything just implodes on itself like a family squabble that nobody outside the family really cares about. Why is Superman fighting Batman? Why is Iron Man fighting Captain America? Who knows? Who cares? You’ve lost us - and in some cases, even alienated us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t seen &lt;em&gt;Batman v Superman&lt;/em&gt; yet, but the critics have slammed it, and a lot of Superman fans are disappointed about such a dark departure from the Christopher Reeve era. Drop Lex Luthor off at the local prison while trading family-friendly quips, or just snap his neck? This conflict is explored in a far more nuanced way in excellent new Netflix shows like &lt;em&gt;Daredevil&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Jessica Jones&lt;/em&gt;. But injecting “realism” into Superman does nothing more than taint the ethos of a celebrated superhero that arose in the patriotic 1930s. He is not your hero - he is your grandfather’s hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All our cherished characters belong to a unique and idiosyncratic time and place. And they need to stay in the past. They are part of our history, our upbringing, our collective mythos, shared from parent to child. When we offer new perspectives and reimaginings of old characters, will our children appreciate the originals with us, or adopt the shiny, corrupted versions as the “real” incarnation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, there is hope. Perhaps the tides are shifting. As fans, we used to be grateful for even terrible movies about our heroes, because there were so few. But now… there really is no reason to watch a bad Superman movie. Zack Snyder isn’t holding a gun between our eyes and forcing us to watch it. We have a choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And maybe the best choice is to let it go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battle of the five armies</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/battle-of-the-five-armies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 15:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/battle-of-the-five-armies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kanye West&amp;rsquo;s new album is fantastic. At least, that&amp;rsquo;s what people who&amp;rsquo;ve signed up for Tidal say. Because Jay Z’s streaming service is the only place you can get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except for, of course, other illicit means. But we’ll get to that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after the album’s release, Kanye crowed on Twitter that his album will never be available on Apple Music (or on CDs for that matter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels like the West Coast vs East Coast rivalry all over again. We have Apple Music on the West Coast, with Dr. Dre and friends. Then we have Jay Z and crew representing the East Coast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, should I say, the metaphorical East Coast. Because it’s not like Jay Z or Kanye actually live in the godforsaken east. They live in California of course, along with everybody else famous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But clearly, Kanye does not want to attend any more parties in L.A. So, what gives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music industry is in disarray and everybody is living in the wild west regardless of previous alliances. It’s a mexican standoff between Spotify, Google Music, Pandora, Apple Music, and Tidal. Or as I like to call it, the battle of the five armies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a mess. The heavy hitters, like Kanye, hold a gun to the heads of their fans and demand lock-in to their distribution channel of choice. Or, like Taylor Swift and Adele, simply abstain from the streaming wars altogether and rake in their own profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, lesser-known artists spread themselves thin over the multitude of disparate options out there and hope that somewhere out there, some music recommendation algorithm will unwittingly promote their music because it sounds like a cross between Justin Bieber and Drake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which leaves us, the consumers, as nothing more than collateral damage as the five armies duke it out. Paying $120 a year for a streaming service is about $120 more than most people spend on buying CDs these days. But we are willing to pay it because of the incredible value proposition of having access to all the music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is no way we’re going to sign up for more than one service. Or jump ship and lose our entire libraries. Which leaves the doors wide open for piracy. It’s no wonder that Kanye’s new album is one of the most torrented albums of all time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s just address the elephant in the room. As music fans, of course we care about how much the artists get paid. But the world has moved on from buying $18 CDs. That cash cow is well and truly hamburger, and there’s no going back. We need a sustainable industry, and maybe some painful market correction, and maybe, just maybe, artistic integrity will blossom to breathe life into music once again. Cut the strings off industry puppets and all that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And those hard-working musicians who don’t wield the same clout as Taylor and Kanye know what they have to do to survive. Tour. Tour like hell for the next twenty or thirty years, pandering and nurturing and keeping their fan base alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as consumers we selfishly want it all. We want a new world order in music. One place to go for all our music. I think we’re all secretly hoping for some sort of consolidation and monopoly to unite the fractured mess of the industry. That is why we eagerly read rumours of Samsung buying Tidal and hope it’s true. Whispers of Google acquiring Spotify. Hell, yes. Apple buying, well, just about anyone they want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Services like Rdio go under, and we shrug at another casualty of the war. Because all we want is a winner. This war, after all, isn’t about us - or what is best for the consumer. So, all we can hope for is that when the dust settles, our new leader is the lesser of five evils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because that new Kanye album is really good, damn it. Just don’t ask me how I know this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The nightmares in our DNA</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/nightmares-in-our-dna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 15:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/nightmares-in-our-dna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure you are familiar with the “nature vs nurture” debate. If not, google it - I’ll wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got it? Good. For me, most explanations for human behaviour can be lumped into the “nurture” side - a bias, no doubt, fostered by my time studying anthropology at university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is something to be said for the “nature” side as well. Evolution bakes instinctual responses into the DNA of all animals, after all. Horses, for example, have an innate fear of snakes, and therefore snake-like objects. Sometimes, a horse will rear when faced with a snake-shaped stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what vestigial instincts from our hunter gatherer days linger on to colour our nightmares today? Most people assume that man has always been at the top of the food chain; but this assumption is an arrogant one, albeit unsurprising. We’ve been top dog for thousands of years now and are used to our dominion over all of God’s creatures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a different story thousands of years ago. There was an animal that evolved to be a specialist predator on humans - the Dinofelis. When mountain lions and other big cats attack a human today, the victim often survives because modern cats don’t have teeth that can pierce our skulls. The Dinofelis, however, had short, dagger-like teeth that punctured the skull with one bite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grisly forensic evidence can be found today in African caves, where skulls show the tooth holes left by this slinking predator who attacked in the dark of night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans fought back. We invented spears and other piercing weapons. We drove the Dinofelis into extinction. We won.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the nightmares remain in our ancestral memory. They are the monsters under our bed. The silent menace in the dark. Nobody has to teach a young child to be scared of large cats. I’ve seen this for myself. When I pretend to be an elephant, or even a snake or a bear, my kids laugh it off. But when I pretend to be a slinking tiger-like creature, complete with cat like movements, my kids run screaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We feel safe when have control over our environments. Perhaps our domestication of cats is an attempt to subjugate our former oppressors and desensitize our primal fears. Maybe we find cats amusing because we’ve performed the ultimate reversal and made our greatest enemy&amp;hellip;cute. Is it any accident that we invented the Internet so we could watch cat videos all day long?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I misspoke a little when I said we are top dogs on planet Earth. We are still prey to micro-organisms that we can’t defend against with traditional weapons. Disease, plagues, viruses, and other modern killers of our overpopulated world were not nearly as devastating to the small nomadic tribes in our distant past. But our homogenous and globalized societies today are especially susceptible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the next nightmare to insinuate itself into our DNA will be of large crowds where diseases spread like wildfire. Perhaps, in some post-apocalyptic future we will have reverted to roaming in small cohesive groups, using our human ingenuity and survival skills to elude the vast zombie hordes that threaten to infect us. Wait a minute, did I just describe &lt;em&gt;The Walking Dead&lt;/em&gt;? The most popular show on TV right now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems our collective nightmare has already begun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to look forward to in 2016</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/what-to-look-forward-to-in-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 14:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/what-to-look-forward-to-in-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s January and most people like to write about New Year resolutions, or predictions for the year ahead. But I’m quite tired. And no, I didn’t mean that to sound like a sardonic riff of a &lt;em&gt;Flight of the Conchords&lt;/em&gt; song. I just feel like writing something more free flowing and fun that requires less research, intense pondering or tortured introspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m going to compile a breezy list of things I’m looking forward to in 2016. Just off the top of my head. And in no particular order. Yes, the year ahead will bring weddings and babies (not mine, just to be clear), which is all very exciting of course. And I have a new job to sink my teeth into, which is very satisfying. I also want to be… better in 2016, in many ways. But forget about that for now. Let’s talk about music, tech, movies, games, books, and that sort of superficial, but fun, fluffy stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here are some random things to look forward to in 2016:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kanye West’s new album is coming out next month. Regardless of whether you harbour fierce admiration for the man, or dismiss him as a pompous twat - you can’t deny that Kanye is one heck of a reliable tastemaker.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Uncharted 4&lt;/em&gt; is coming out this April. But here’s the thing - my TV has refused to acknowledge my PS3 for the past six months, and I don’t know who broke up with who. If it’s the PlayStation that decided to move on, then perhaps a PS4 will bring back the console love. Also, PlayStation VR is coming sometime this year, and I’m definitely looking forward to trying it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice&lt;/em&gt; is coming out in March. I’m still not sure about Ben Affleck, or about Jack Snyder, or about DC’s track record in general, so this movie could most definitely disappoint. But - Superman!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to TV, I&amp;rsquo;m a 100-percent Netflix man, since I cancelled cable quite some time ago. However, I&amp;rsquo;m still partial to &lt;em&gt;Survivor&lt;/em&gt; - a show that is like your favourite uncle - always there and always dependable. I&amp;rsquo;m also a big &lt;em&gt;Walking Dead&lt;/em&gt; fan - and it looks like that show isn&amp;rsquo;t going away any time soon, although I&amp;rsquo;m sure they will run out of shocking situations to explore at some point. I&amp;rsquo;m a season behind, but I&amp;rsquo;m okay with that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Book releases are few and far between - and George Martin recently dropped the bomb that &lt;em&gt;The Winds of Winter&lt;/em&gt; will not be finished before the next season of the TV show leapfrogs the book and brings with it unprecedented spoilers for book lovers. But despite the fact that the &lt;em&gt;Song of Fire and Ice&lt;/em&gt; has become a mummer’s farce, there are at least two other releases to look forward to: Scott Lynch’s &lt;em&gt;The Thorn of Emberlain&lt;/em&gt;, and Justin Cronin’s &lt;em&gt;The City of Mirrors&lt;/em&gt;. On the whole, it’s more satisfying to just read a book series that has already been completed. Except for Brandon Sanderson’s books - that guy writes unnaturally fast, I tell you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 7 is coming out this year, and it’s a “tick” design-refresh year in the tick-tock cycle. Man, that sounds ridiculous, but that’s how people talk about the iPhone now. I just got the iPhone, so of course I won’t be upgrading any time soon. But I’m curious to see if Apple decides to ditch the home button and go with that clean all-screen look that seems like an inevitable design evolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of tech, cars are finally roaring into the 21st century - or should I say, electric cars are silently cruising into the new millennium with insane battery tech. Chevy just beat Tesla to the punch with it’s 30K Bolt that has an impressive 200-mile range. But Tesla is sure to announce the Model 3 this year, and Elon’s vision is just too compelling at this point to not be excited in any way. The magical bundle is undoubtedly a mass-market car that is both autonomous and electric. Google is making great progress and Apple’s “secret” car project is blowing too much smoke to be mere ephemeral R&amp;amp;D tinkering - an Apple car is almost certainly far into development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year hasn&amp;rsquo;t started out on the best footing. Low oil prices have decimated the Canadian economy and driven our dollar down so far that a trip to the States is an extravagant luxury. On the other hand, house prices have shot up so high that little old ladies can&amp;rsquo;t afford property tax on their two million dollar shacks. And when looking at the big picture, a recent earthquake reminded us that the big one could hit at any moment and level the West Coast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why not enjoy the little things? A good book. A good movie. A year of simple delights. That sounds quite delectable to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norway</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/Norway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 09:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/Norway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, since I have a five-hour layover here in Amsterdam, I may as well rustle together some thoughts on my trip to Norway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only reason for my visit was for work, so let me start with my time at Kongsberg Maritime. After an unsuccessful attempt at using DITA at VTech, I was a little skeptical about plunging into structured authoring, although I was willing to learn the tools of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Ragnar, the senior information developer over there, put me through a DITA boot camp where he promised I would eat, sleep, and dream of XML and DITA. And I did. So, did I emerge a DITA disciple, ready to spread the word at home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, yes and no. On the negative side, DITA can feel a bit restrictive with its strict, rule-based architecture. And it was a bit discouraging to learn that only 15 companies in the world use a combination of Arbortext on the front-end and SDL Livecontent on the back-end for their documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, on the positive side, the true power of DITA only emerges when you’re working with a geographically diverse group of writers. Actually, I would go so far as to say that solo writers would do well to stay far, far away from DITA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are about 30 writers within the company that all share the same database. The immediate benefits to this are obvious. Although nobody shares the exact same product, they’re similar enough that you can most likely re-use content that somebody else has written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all share the same manual types, chapter headings, and boilerplate text. Even sentences are written to be as “round” as possible so that they are generic enough to be re-used everywhere. Variables and conditional text add product-specific contextualization. The database is organized to facilitate discovery and contributions to library topics is encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The supports in place are varied. A DITA steering committee of about five people at HQ oversees the XML implementation and manages requests from the writers. Each member specializes in one area, such as template improvements, or metadata tags and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also regional groups - I am now a member of the Horten Doc and DITA crew - aka the Conref champions! Even though there&amp;rsquo;s only one of me in Vancouver, it&amp;rsquo;s great to have the resource of other writers. After all, nobody understands a writer more than another writer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I was working most of the time, I did have a free weekend to explore Norway a little. On the Saturday, Ragnar was kind enough to take me into Oslo for the day. We visited the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.khm.uio.no/english/visit-us/viking-ship-museum/&#34;&gt;Viking Ship museum&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.norskfolkemuseum.no/en/&#34;&gt;Norwegian folk museum&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forsvarsbygg.no/festningene/Festningene/Akershus-festning/English/&#34;&gt;Akershus Fortress&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forsvaretsmuseer.no/nor/Hjemmefrontmuseet&#34;&gt;Resistance museum&lt;/a&gt;. I especially enjoyed that last one - hearing the stories of Norway’s resistance movement during the Nazi occupation was both fascinating and unbelievable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Sunday, I checked out &lt;a href=&#34;http://midgardsenteret.no/en/om-midgard/the-borre-park/&#34;&gt;Borre national park&lt;/a&gt; where several Viking burial mounds continue to skulk silently beside the desolate coast. It was here where they excavated the famous Viking ships. A haunting and beautiful place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some general observations about Norway and Norwegian culture (Buzzfeed headline: 10 facts about Norway you&amp;rsquo;ll never believe!):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Norwegians eat pizza with a fork and knife. They also don’t use any condiments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They prefer diesel over gasoline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nobody thinks twice about drinking coffee in an outdoor patio. In the winter. With no heaters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is cheaper to buy groceries in Sweden, but it is somewhat frowned upon. Also, Swedish cookies are so good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Norwegians will tell you they only speak a “little” English, then speak it fluently. But there seems to be a lot of variety in their accents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many traditional foods involve putrified fish - unsurprisingly most Norwegians don&amp;rsquo;t like it that much. I did, however, have a traditional Christmas dish called Pinnekjøtt, a really good lamb dish that all Norwegians enjoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Norwegians start work really early. And they eat lunch at 11AM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The streets are empty during the day - presumably because everybody either works or goes to school. Little kids all go to daycare because it is free. So no stay-at-home parents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everybody has bitter stories about how some people collect their welfare checks to buy cars and take vacations while hard-working Norwegians support their lazy asses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I guess I should mention that Norway is horribly expensive, but it is a socialist country after all, so there is a good reason for Norway’s reputation as a pricey destination. Still, when visitors like me end up paying $15 for a beer and get taxed 25% on top of that, this reputation is hard to refute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, Norway felt like the more remote parts of Canada where good working-class people try to carve out their lives in the barren landscape. It is almost nothing like Vancouver, which seems ridiculously ostentatious in comparison. And that was refreshing to me. There&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic Beach House song called, well, “Norway”. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2L_R-DELtX8&#34;&gt;Listen to it&lt;/a&gt;. You may dream of a country far away, shrouded in mist, carved up by fjords, air crisp with the tang of the sea. Yet there are sombre undertones - a mourning, an aching, a sadness that is beautiful in itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 Flagship winner</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/2015-flagship-winner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 20:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/2015-flagship-winner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The choice came down to four phones: the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/2015-flagship-1-htc-one-m9/&#34;&gt;HTC One M9&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/2015-flagship-2-samsung-galaxy-s6/&#34;&gt;Samsung Galaxy S6&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/1271/&#34;&gt;LG G4&lt;/a&gt;, or the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/2015-flagship-4-iphone-6s/&#34;&gt;iPhone 6s&lt;/a&gt;. In actuality, a more stark dichotomy lay between Android and Apple, so the choice really came down to two very different approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been living with both Android and iOS, so appreciate the merits of both operating systems. For me, hardware was a bigger consideration, as well as ongoing software support. I also didn&amp;rsquo;t want a gigantic slab of a phone that seems to be the norm these days. So, in the end, I decided to go with the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest - another factor in my decision was the company brand, and everything that brand stands for. For this reason, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even consider Huawei&amp;rsquo;s Nexus 6P, even though it seems very well made. People quickly forget, but Huawei has been suspected of &lt;a href=&#34;http://gizmodo.com/5949821/chinas-biggest-telecomms-are-officially-national-security-risks-updated&#34;&gt;spying for the Chinese government&lt;/a&gt;, even though they, of course, deny it. On the other hand, Apple is well known for its stance on privacy and security, perhaps even more so under Tim Cook&amp;rsquo;s reign. After all, Tim is an intensely private person, to the point where protecting people&amp;rsquo;s data is almost a crusade for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has never had qualms about mining people&amp;rsquo;s data to sell advertising, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never had a huge problem with this. Probably because I&amp;rsquo;ve come to believe Google&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t be evil&amp;rdquo; mantra after using their services for such a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, most of Google&amp;rsquo;s apps work beautifully on the iPhone - it seems pretty obvious that they don&amp;rsquo;t care whether you buy an Android phone or iPhone, as long as you use their services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s beautiful hardware is one of the main reasons that people are willing to kill a whole pay cheque on an iPhone. The 6s is indeed a thing of beauty and is often imitated, sometimes to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2015/10/27/9620318/htc-one-a9-review-android-iphone&#34;&gt;a ridiculous degree&lt;/a&gt;. Looking back, I had &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/one-month-till-iphone-gets-here/&#34;&gt;my eye on the original iPhone&lt;/a&gt; before it even debuted - but for some reason, I stuck with my flip phone for another five years before trying out an Android phone as my first smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it was with great excitement that I unboxed my first iPhone. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even turn it on until I&amp;rsquo;d put a screen protector on it and inserted a new SIM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, my heart broke a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spotted a dead pixel in the lower-right corner of the screen. As you may know, once you see a dead pixel, you just can&amp;rsquo;t un-see it. Especially when you just paid $1200 for a phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took it into the Apple store the next day and they were willing to exchange it for a refurbished &amp;ldquo;service phone&amp;rdquo;, not a new out-of-the-box phone. Note-to-self: If I ever buy another Apple product, just get it at the store - not online. Apple stores can&amp;rsquo;t exchange online purchases. My choices were to either return it for a service phone, or mail the phone back to Apple and wait a couple of weeks for a new replacement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, after some deliberation - involving a bizarre rambling monologue from a disgruntled Genius - a third option presented itself: to replace the entire LCD screen. So that&amp;rsquo;s what I did - they could replace it at the store and it only took about an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After using my new phone for a week, I&amp;rsquo;ve been pleasantly surprised at how well the iPhone syncs up my other Apple products - namely my iMac, iPad, and Apple TV. I&amp;rsquo;d never really considered this, but, until now, the iPhone was the only missing link in my personal Apple ecosystem (my second-gen iPod has long since ceased to be a contributing member of &amp;ldquo;the family&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could go on about how crispy the screen is or how insanely fast this thing is, but others have done so &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.anandtech.com/show/9686/the-apple-iphone-6s-and-iphone-6s-plus-review&#34;&gt;in far more detail&lt;/a&gt;. But, yeah, this thing screams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, there have also been some unexpected, quite inexplicable niggles. The Alert volume, for example, is separate from the Ringtone volume, but can&amp;rsquo;t be changed in the settings menu. I think you can change the Alert volume by playing some music and adjusting its volume, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure - either way, not very user friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I&amp;rsquo;m baffled as to how I can back up my videos in their original resolution. Photostream uploads photos to the cloud, but not videos. And trying to use Dropbox to back up photos and videos doesn&amp;rsquo;t work either because Apple doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow Dropbox to run indefinitely in the background. Google photos does a good job, but downscales 4K videos to 1080p.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, these are minor concerns that could someday be fixed in software. At the end of the day, a phone is just a tool. I know I&amp;rsquo;ve made a big deal in this blog about my upgrade. And I expected to go be glued to my new phone the moment I got it - installing tons of apps and so on. But I haven&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, the iPhone has sort of faded away into the background. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a distractingly large screen. There are no widgets to fiddle with. But when called on to perform a task - it is on point; the iPhone does it well and it does it fast. Like a well-oiled weapon that never misfires - the iPhone can be counted on when you need it most.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work update</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/work-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 18:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/work-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I blog about work very sparely, and I think most people would agree that saying too much can lead into dangerous territory. So, I tend to avoid it unless I have something general to say that doesn&amp;rsquo;t touch on any work projects. But I would be remiss in my blogging duties not to mention that I have a new job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started working as a technical writer at Vtech seven years ago - here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/new-job/&#34;&gt;a post&lt;/a&gt; I wrote when I first got the job, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/what-i-do/&#34;&gt;another&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about a month in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vtech has been very good to me and the people there are great, but last month the time came for me to move on. I worked on some great projects and enjoyed becoming a somewhat accomplished User Interface designer. My last project was a touchscreen phone which I designed from scratch - largely on my own. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m no longer working there, perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll write a post sometime about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, wanting to work closer to home, and learn some new skills, I accepted a job as the sole technical writer at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kongsbergmesotech.com/&#34;&gt;Kongsberg Mesotech&lt;/a&gt;. They&amp;rsquo;re a subsidiary of Kongsberg, a major defence contractor for Norway and a high-tech company with &lt;a href=&#34;http://200.kongsberg.com/&#34;&gt;a 200-year old history&lt;/a&gt;. I had to go through security clearance and sign an NDA, so I definitely won&amp;rsquo;t be talking about their projects here either, but I can say that I&amp;rsquo;m working primarily with underwater sonar systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really liking it. The commute is a dream compared to the absolute grind I had before. And I still get to go on my thrice-weekly runs - this time off-street on the portion of the Trans-Canada Trail that runs through Port Coquitlam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started at Vtech, they&amp;rsquo;d never had a technical writer before, so it took a while to integrate myself into the product development cycle. My new company has also never had a technical writer before, but this time, I come armed with lots of experience and confidence (cause y&amp;rsquo;all know I&amp;rsquo;m a good writer, right? RIGHT?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The senior information developer in Norway has been very supportive and indeed, the documentation team has a ton of resources, such as style guides, templates, etc. I especially appreciate the international support here because I got absolutely no support from the Hong Kong documentation team at Vtech (that isn&amp;rsquo;t good or bad - it&amp;rsquo;s just the way it was - hence the pleasant surprise).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, I will be flying to Norway for a two-week training session before the end of the year. It will be hard to be away from my family for so long, but am happy to be making face-to-face contact with the Norway team and learning valuable skills to boot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What skills though? This might get a bit technical, so if you&amp;rsquo;re not a fellow technical writer, you can probably stop reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be migrating all legacy documentation to single-sourced structured DITA authoring. The XML editor I&amp;rsquo;ll be using is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ptc.com/product/arbortext/author/editor&#34;&gt;Arbortext&lt;/a&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t have much practical experience with DITA. Although, DITA was so hot in the technical writer world a few years back, so I did research into implementing it at Vtech. Ultimately, I decided the time investment and practical application wasn&amp;rsquo;t worth it. This time, I hope things go better - and I will have more training and support of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, Kongsberg uses the Simplified Technical English (STE) standard from the Aerospace and Defence Industries Association of Europe (ASD). I have to say though, that their guidelines do not bleed over at all into user interface design because &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asd-ste100.org/&#34;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt; is absolutely horrid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, a steep learning curve, but lots of structure in place, which is fantastic. Additional areas I could push for training is photography and 3D modelling because the resources for manual illustrations aren&amp;rsquo;t so great. But I have enough on my plate for now - and that&amp;rsquo;s all you could ask for in your job, really - to be happily occupied. I do love my job and sometimes a change is just what you need to re-energize your career.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banned for blogging about Apple</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/banned-for-blogging-about-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 21:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/banned-for-blogging-about-apple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seeing as I don’t make any money off this blog, I try to keep costs down to a minimum. And so, for the past eight years or so, I’ve had no problems using a free web host to manage my self-hosted Wordpress installation. Until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been pretty busy these days (for reasons which I’ll explain in a later post). But, wanting to post at least once a month, I navigated over to wordbit.com only to discover an ugly 403 error page instead of my home page.  So, I contacted my web host support. This is what happened:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/appleban_scnsht_1.png&#34; alt=&#34;screen shot 1&#34; title=&#34;Screenshot 1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seemed pretty obvious to me by this point that the web host wanted to purge itself of all free-loaders, even if it meant making up minor infractions. But since I&amp;rsquo;d never used any of the listed forbidden words, I figured I had half a leg to stand on. I was wrong:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/appleban_scnsht_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screen shot 2&#34; title=&#34;Screenshot 2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guilty as charged - yes, I blog about Apple. And now I&amp;rsquo;d been banned for blogging about Apple. I&amp;rsquo;d say the whole debacle was asinine and petty, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t even begin to address the irony of being banned for blogging about the biggest technology giant on planet Earth. My good buddy Steven probably decided he&amp;rsquo;d had enough of subverting service requests into sales. So he checked which word appears on my blog with the highest frequency and magically turned it into a forbidden word. Even though I&amp;rsquo;ve never even come close to &amp;ldquo;abusing&amp;rdquo; the service these past few years, I was now labelled a deviant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I pulled the plug on the web host faster than you can say &amp;ldquo;Apple&amp;rdquo; and looked for a new home. I briefly considered Medium, but find their intentions for monetization hazy at best. And they only offer custom domain names by invitation. I thought seriously about moving to wordpress.com, but they have advertising now apparently. And no custom domain name, so that would mean hosting a launcher page somewhere else anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obvious and easy solution would have been to move to another free web host, but honestly, I&amp;rsquo;ve had enough. The internet at large has turned hostile toward bloggers. And I’m not just talking about the role social media has played in killing the blog. I think a lot of web hosts are setting fire to users who refuse to convert to paying customers. I also don&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with censorship ever again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this deliberation lead me to a hosting solution I&amp;rsquo;d seen a lot of software developers use - GitHub. Specifically &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub pages&lt;/a&gt;. By checking files into a repository, content management mimics software version control. Without a doubt, the most popular static site generator out there is Jeckyll. Quick primer on static site generators - Basically, they compile all blog posts into a static html webpage instead of using runtimes like PHP and a database like MySQL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eliminating database calls makes the site lightning fast on the front end with page loads being virtually non-existent. But you still have to deploy the entire site each time you add a new blog post. Apparently Jeckyll isn’t the fastest. I wanted speed on the back end too, so decided on &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, which is snappy front and back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no software geek, so it was a tough weekend for me - learning the terminal command line; running Python and Perl scripts; setting up virtual machines; figuring out how cloning, branching, committing, etc. work in GitHub; finding the perfect Hugo template; and converting my Wordpress posts to markdown. Learning to write in markdown has turned out to be simply a delight. Well done, &lt;a href=&#34;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;Gruber&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I eventually got it to work. And it&amp;rsquo;s really great. The setup I have now is exactly what I wanted - minimalist, clean, and upholding the old-school hacker ethos of the web. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to undergo a gradual cleanup effort to smooth out formatting issues resulting from the conversion from XML to markdown, and fix all image links too. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve danced this dance before over the years as my content has moved around a lot - more than I&amp;rsquo;d like. Hopefully this time I&amp;rsquo;ve found a home where I can stay for a while. One where I won&amp;rsquo;t ever be censored for, I don’t know, blogging about topics every single other person in the world blogs about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, thank you Steven. You’ve forced me to learn new things and expand my skillset. Without you, I’d still be wrangling with Wordpress and using your dodgy control panel. Thank you for the nostalgia - going back to the command line is like returning home to DOS. And thank you for giving me that aura of cool that comes to those who are crazy enough to hack together a blog on GitHub. I still have no idea what I’m doing, but I’m happier now, Steven, much happier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 Flagship 4: iPhone 6S</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/2015-flagship-4-iphone-6s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 21:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/2015-flagship-4-iphone-6s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/iphone6s.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;iphone6s&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I alluded to in my last post, the very definition of a &amp;ldquo;flagship&amp;rdquo; has perceptively shifted this past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, mid-range devices with high-end specs and razor-thin profit margins have exploded out of China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the definition of a flagship has skewed heavily toward &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt; phones (formerly known as phablets, but now the norm). Bigger phones tend to get better battery life and are able to fit in better camera components, such as Optical Image Stabilization (OIS).  But, I most certainly do not want a big phone. For me, the sweet spot is in the 4.5 to 5-inch screen size range. For this reason, I&amp;rsquo;m excluding phones like the Note 5 and iPhone 6S Plus from my overview of the year&amp;rsquo;s best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when all is said and done, a flagship choice always comes down to that most ancient and hotly disputed divide - Android or iPhone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s latest entry in the flagship wars, the iPhone 6S, comes as no surprise. Dependably meticulous manufacturing. A two-year design cycle. And so many leaks before the official announcement that the only real surprise this year was a unique take on the &amp;ldquo;selfie flash&amp;rdquo; where the whole front screen lights up. Let&amp;rsquo;s not forget the predictably glowing reviews as well. For the upper middle-class of the developed world, the iPhone is the only choice there is. It is, for better or worse, America&amp;rsquo;s phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite Apple not playing the spec game, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look anyway for the sake of consistency:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operating system:&lt;/strong&gt; iOS 9&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.7-inch 1334 x 750 pixel IPS LCD display, 326 ppi pixel density&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Processor:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.85 Ghz 64-bit A9 SoC with M9 motion co-processor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memory:&lt;/strong&gt; 2GB RAM / 16GB, 64GB, and 128GB storage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear camera:&lt;/strong&gt; 12MP rear iSight camera, F2.2 lens, True Tone flash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front-facing camera:&lt;/strong&gt; 5MP front-facing FaceTime camera, Retina flash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battery:&lt;/strong&gt; 1715 mAh non-removable Li-ion battery&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Size:&lt;/strong&gt; 138.3 x 67.1 x 7.1mm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weight:&lt;/strong&gt; 143 grams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Objectively speaking, the advantages of the iPhone are obvious. End-to-end control allows Apple to pursue a deep integration of hardware and software. This control has allowed intriguing new features, such as &amp;ldquo;3D Touch&amp;rdquo; where the screen measures different levels of pressure to activate &amp;ldquo;right-click&amp;rdquo; types of UI popups. This control allows Apple to get away with fairly middling specs, where Android phones are overcompensating with killer specs to cover a lack of optimization. This control is also what makes the iPhone camera usually so much better than the competition. I say &amp;ldquo;usually&amp;rdquo; because this year, the other guys, especially Samsung, have seriously stepped up their game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do suspect that the Android implementation is only as good as its skin. In other words, the camera is great as long as you stay locked onto TouchWiz or Sense. We all know that manufacturer Android updates are agonizingly slow and in some cases, only supported for a year or two. Flash a custom ROM like Cyanogenmod, and you can kiss your tight hardware-software camera integration goodbye. I know this from bitter experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The disadvantages of such tight control is that it can be stifling. There is a liberating feel to Android. The possibilities are endless when it comes to true customization, both on the front end and back end. Most Android phone manufacturers also aren&amp;rsquo;t afraid to explore the bleeding edge of hardware development. After all, they just leave the bulk of software development to Google, so hardly need to expend resources on it at all. Instead we get things like NFC (Android first) and 4K screens (Android first). Apple waits a while before coming up with a carefully considered rebuttal. But they are never first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually said much about the new iPhones, mostly because I don&amp;rsquo;t have to. The reviews are in - they&amp;rsquo;re great. No surprises there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if there will be any more flagships this year, so this most likely concludes my survey of the year&amp;rsquo;s best. The new Nexus phones are being announced next week, so I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely be checking those out. But, I&amp;rsquo;m not holding my breath for anything in the flagship class. I&amp;rsquo;ve got some thinking to do, because it&amp;rsquo;s finally time to make a choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A long, dry summer</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/a-long-dry-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 22:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/a-long-dry-summer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a long, dry summer - and I&amp;rsquo;m not just talking about the weather. My series on flagship phones has been somewhat stymied by some recent changes in the industry. I was expecting some more flagships to emerge from big boys like Sony and Motorola, but instead there has been a surge of mid-range devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finding all their money was being made on the entry-level Moto G, Motorola decided to scale back on an ambitious successor to last year&amp;rsquo;s Moto X.  Instead we have the Moto X Play, which is nothing more than a pumped-up version of the Moto G with mid-range specs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, after struggling to make an impact in North America, despite a worthy flagship in the Xperia series, Sony has decided to limit the release of the Xperia Z4 to it&amp;rsquo;s native Japan only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, a bunch of Chinese companies are trying to change the game by releasing cheap Android phones with impressive specs. We&amp;rsquo;ve got Asus putting out the ZenFone 2, Alcatel&amp;rsquo;s OneTouch Idol 3, Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s Redmi Note 2, and the so called &amp;ldquo;flagship killer&amp;rdquo;, the OnePlus 2. However, all these phones cut corners to get prices so low, and sometimes &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/13/9147211/android-price-wars-cost-of-cheap-smartphones&#34;&gt;the compromises aren&amp;rsquo;t worth it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what happened to the flagships? Well, it certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that Apple is taking over 90 percent of all profits in the smartphone industry. That only leaves one option - make profit on sheer volume alone. But moving as many units as possible, especially in developing markets, means putting an ever downward pressure on prices. This sounds great in theory, especially since you can&amp;rsquo;t call these new mid-range phones cheap junk. The pace of technological advancement for phones lately has been blistering. A mid-range phone in 2015 makes last year&amp;rsquo;s flagship look positively vintage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So maybe the very concept of a flagship is becoming obsolete? It&amp;rsquo;s too soon to tell. There&amp;rsquo;s no doubt that the iPhone is an overpriced luxury item, despite being a beautifully manufactured product. But with most wireless carriers doing away with contracts and subsidies, customers are only now being exposed to the true price of a smartphone. Will people stick with the quality and superior customer service that Apple represents, despite the much higher price tag, or will a better bang-for-your-buck win in the end?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year isn&amp;rsquo;t close to being over yet, so I may eat these words later&amp;hellip; but when it comes to true high-end flagships, it&amp;rsquo;s starting to look the same as in years past: a two-horse race between Apple and Samsung. And you know how I feel about Samsung.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lollipop at last</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/lollipop-at-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 23:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/lollipop-at-last/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/android_screenshots.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;android screenshots&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been excited to try out Lollipop for a long time, especially after delving deep into Google&amp;rsquo;s new design language, dubbed Material Design, and even using it in my own user interface design projects. But that is precisely the problem with Android, unless you&amp;rsquo;re using a Nexus, you have to wait a long, long time before getting the latest. All told, it takes roughly one year for most Android users to catch up. So, when &amp;ldquo;Android M&amp;rdquo; was announced, I knew my time was near. Except, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t been following along (shocking, I know), I&amp;rsquo;m currently using Cyanogenmod to extend the life of my One S, which HTC wantonly threw into the obsolescence pile after &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobilesyrup.com/2013/07/02/this-is-the-end-htc-one-s-wont-get-android-4-2-update/&#34;&gt;barely a year&lt;/a&gt; of support. Wading into the murky pool of aftermarket ROMs is daunting in and of itself, but now I&amp;rsquo;ve fully come to realize how inconsistent and whimsical placing your trust into a ragtag bunch of humble volunteers truly is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And total respect to all the community developers who code these ROMs in their spare time, cause without you guys&amp;hellip; well, let&amp;rsquo;s just say that the adoption rate for the latest Android software would probably be a lot lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it seems that ever since the company split off its for-profit arm, Cyanogen OS, resources have followed the $$$ instead. I get it - this is how capitalism works. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the situation any less frustrating though. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyanogenmod promised a stable snapshot version of Lollipop within two weeks of the announcement. Several months later, the snapshot was conspicuously lacking. Then, there was a blog post declaring, with great fanfare, that the snapshot had arrived and builds were rolling out. Except, it turned out only a scant few devices were getting snapshots. Many, including the One S, were still on nightlies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, Lollipop nightlies have been available for a long time, but many of us were waiting for a more stable snapshot, as we were accustomed to getting every month on KitKat. I eventually capitulated and moved onto the nightlies. Which have been great, by the way, my worries about stability were unfounded - I should have just flashed the nightlies a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fundamental problem here is communication, plain and simple. Given that Cyanogenmod is a community effort, I&amp;rsquo;m willing to adapt to changing development cycles and go wherever the wind is blowing. But even polite queries from users about the status of the snapshots were pointedly ignored. Instead we got developer profiles and T-shirt competitions. Why not just be honest and open about where things are at? Instead of trying to draw in a wider user base that may not fall into the uber-geek category, Cyanogenmod comes off as very exclusionary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think, maybe developers just suck at PR. It&amp;rsquo;s a shame, because Cyanogenmod could be something more than a homebrew club. It could be a genuine grassroots movement - especially for the developing world that cannot afford to upgrade their phone every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t mean this to turn into a rant, but there you go. I harbour no ill feeling toward Cyanogenmod, and frankly, I&amp;rsquo;ll be moving on anyway once I upgrade my phone this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, Lollipop is better than I hoped it would be. The interface is noticeably faster and Material Design looks great, even on my AMOLED display, which tends to favour dark colours over white. Overheating issues seem to have dissipated somewhat (but it is a hot summer, so hard to tell). But what I&amp;rsquo;m most impressed with is the increase in battery life. I suspect this improvement is due to a new runtime environment, which changed from Dalvik to to ART in Lollipop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I should have been enjoying Lollipop months ago, but here we are. I&amp;rsquo;ll have a few more months to use it yet, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll be moving onto a flagship. There have been a few launched this year, but there are many more to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay frosty, my friends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of Technical Writing</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-future-of-technical-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 00:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-future-of-technical-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/sections/money/2015/05/21/408234543/will-your-job-be-done-by-a-machine&#34;&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt; that will tell you what the odds are of your job being automated in the future. The data for the estimate is derived from an academic paper where the researchers, I&amp;rsquo;m sure, are smug in the knowledge that robots will never replace university professors. Technical writers, however, will apparently not fare so well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/techwriters.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;techwriters&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then again, most technical writers seem to be the self-deprecating sort who suspect that their profession is perpetually sliding from obscurity into obsolescence anyway.  Obscure, you say? Let&amp;rsquo;s not kid ourselves. Even our job title has been co-opted by the so called &amp;ldquo;tech writer&amp;rdquo;, who is actually not a technical writer at all, but a journalist who covers technology. We may casually call ourselves tech writers, but in the public parlance, tech writers are widely known as those guys who write at The Verge and Gizmodo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This cartoon neatly sums up our awkward collective identity crisis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/chickenconversation.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chickenconversation&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, we&amp;rsquo;re a humble lot - with a career that is not as &amp;ldquo;important&amp;rdquo; as being a doctor/lawyer/&lt;insert career your parents would be proud of&gt;, and certainly not as lucrative, we&amp;rsquo;re not surprised nobody has heard of us, or even knows exactly what we do. Even our employers often see technical writers as nothing more than a necessary evil in the product development process, and there isn&amp;rsquo;t any career advancement ladder to speak of. So, we just naturally assume that the demise of technical writing is inevitable. As a case in point, see Neal Kaplan&amp;rsquo;s post: &lt;a href=&#34;http://customersandcontent.com/2014/05/03/the-death-of-technical-writing-part-1/&#34;&gt;The death of technical writing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do agree with most of Neal&amp;rsquo;s points. Mobile software development will continue to erode the need for end user documentation, except for enterprise software and in highly specialized, regulated industries. And all the years of discourse focused on DITA at the expense of a proper business case was a waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the definition of a traditional technical writer is just the person who writes the user manual, then, yes, I definitely agree that technical writing is on it&amp;rsquo;s way out. But Neal said it himself - he&amp;rsquo;s not just a technical writer, he&amp;rsquo;s a content engineer, customer support agent, information architect, content strategist, web designer, and technical trainer too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps that is why we have an identity crisis - because there is no all encompassing job description that fits us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any discussion on technical writing, somebody inevitably brings up ROI - how we can demonstrate value to the company, etc. I instinctively dislike this train of thought because I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why we have to justify our existence at all. Nobody questions the value of a software developer or product manager, they just hire them to do the job. The onus should not be on us to prove how our documentation process or single sourcing or whatever is saving the company money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, no hiring manager would invite you in for an interview to pitch the case to create a technical writer position at a company. At least, I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of such a ghastly thing happening. But sometimes, once the manual is done, the project ends, and the work of a technical writer is done. Unless the company requires constant maintenance of their legacy documentation - a position that is definitely becoming rarer these days. But all the same, lean and cost-effective content management will not save you if the work has run dry - it is you that will save you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of behind-the-scenes magic that most people don&amp;rsquo;t know about. Technical writers love to mull over things like the merits of the Oxford Comma or how well their writing fairs in the Flesch–Kincaid readability index. But although grammatical consistency and readability and so on help the end user consume information more easily, such benefits are accrued with a deft but invisible hand. It is hard to translate readability into cost effectiveness, or easily convince others of the importance of a well-placed semicolon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is is hard to deny that technical writers don&amp;rsquo;t play a multi-faceted and invaluable role within an organization when we end up taking on content marketing, product management, and user interface design. When we definitively save the company money by writing SRED reports. When we put the user experience first and advocate for the user both early in the software development process, and at the project&amp;rsquo;s end with ongoing customer training and support. Technical writers who aren&amp;rsquo;t afraid to embed themselves within niche areas and apply their expertise wherever it is fitting become so much more than mere writers - yes, they defy easy definition, but they certainly aren&amp;rsquo;t let go when the manual is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the key skill that all technical writers possess can absolutely never be automated or easily dismissed: communication. I&amp;rsquo;ll be brutally honest: Communication is sorely lacking at most high-tech companies. You know that cliche of the quiet, socially inept software developer geek that is more comfortable talking to a machine than to people? Well, let&amp;rsquo;s just say that most cliches are based in reality. With our contribution to various parts of the product timeline, technical writers always have the big picture in mind, not just one line of code. A technical writer is the bridge between disparate departments; we facilitate, educate, and moderate. Here are some examples of where we can bridge communication between two parties:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company → User&lt;/strong&gt; (end user documentation, product training)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can play a role in the reverse too: &lt;strong&gt;User → Company&lt;/strong&gt; (product support)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Management → Developer&lt;/strong&gt; (requirements definition)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developer → Developer&lt;/strong&gt; (API documentation - &lt;a href=&#34;http://idratherbewriting.com/2014/06/03/the-future-of-tech-comm-is-developer-doc/&#34;&gt;Tom Johnson&lt;/a&gt; believes this is where technical writing is heading)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engineering → Marketing&lt;/strong&gt; (use cases, white papers, spec sheets, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will always be a need to good technical communicators to tailor information for a specific audience, and in doing so, bring an end to the broken telephones game that so many organizations like to play, and which often devolves into finger pointing when things go wrong due to poor communication. There will always be a need for a person who loves to soak up knowledge and learn, but remain an outsider who won&amp;rsquo;t resort to acronyms and techno-jargon when pressed for a simple and clear explanation of how something works. In these respects, I think the future for technical writing is looking bright, but at the same time, we must evolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to remain stuck in the past, clinging onto old paradigms of what a technical writer should be. After all, I&amp;rsquo;m a user too. Who wants to read the manual before using a product? I don&amp;rsquo;t. I will freely admit that if a product is unintuitive or the user interface cryptic, then the product has failed. User documentation should be a resource to solve problems encountered after using the product. It should stop the user from reaching for the telephone in anger and dialing that customer support hotline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the trend toward mobility and simplicity. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to go back to the old days. Technical writing has a place in a future where usability and great design trumps complexity. And when you boil it down to its essence, technical writing is simply about relationships between people. About understanding people and communicating appropriately. It is a very nuanced, human skill and no robot will be up to the task anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Apple dance</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-apple-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 21:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-apple-dance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, WWDC 2015 (Apple&amp;rsquo;s developer conference) showcased what&amp;rsquo;s new in OS X, iOS, and watchOS. There was also an unsurprising &amp;ldquo;one more thing&amp;rdquo; with the introduction of Apple Music. Unlike the massive redesign from&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/its-a-sunny-day-in-cupertino/&#34;&gt; last year&lt;/a&gt;, it was a pretty low-key affair, with Apple focusing on tweaking and stabilizing its evolving platforms. If there was one theme that emerged from the keynote, however, it would be this: Apple is no software company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody would argue that Apple doesn&amp;rsquo;t make beautiful products with unparalleled care and attention. And sometimes there is that magical moment that only Apple can conjure: That moment when their software and hardware work together to create a feature that would be impossible without Apple&amp;rsquo;s complete end-to-end control. There was a foreshadowing of such a thing at this year&amp;rsquo;s WWDC when Apple introduced multitasking for the iPad. But in this case the multitasking bride will have to wait for the 12-inch iPad Pro groom to walk down the aisle later this year before consummating their perfect marriage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when Apple tries to go head-to-head with every other competing software platform out there, they start to spread themselves a little thin. Sure, Apple prides itself on not being first, but being the best. Except, they can&amp;rsquo;t be the best at everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, how can you compete with Google, when their sole purpose is to use increasingly sophisticated &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/rise-of-the-google-machine/&#34;&gt;machine intelligence&lt;/a&gt; to manage and organize vast tracts of data? Apple is trying anyway by beefing up Siri&amp;rsquo;s AI with their new &amp;ldquo;proactive assistant&amp;rdquo;. So, just like Google Now does, she&amp;rsquo;ll tell you when to leave for appointments to beat the traffic, etc. (as an aside, I really have to question how accurate even this feature will be when using the infamous Apple Maps instead of the superior Google Maps). But then you have companies who are laser-focused only on parsing natural language, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.soundhound.com/hound&#34;&gt;SoundHound&lt;/a&gt;, with a speed that leaves both Apple and Google choking in their dust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get it - in a sense, Apple is trying to appeal to the lowest common denominator: if it can cover all possible services under its umbrella, most of Apple&amp;rsquo;s users will probably just use the default. Apple&amp;rsquo;s Mail app on iOS, for example, is serviceable for many - but power users will almost certainly turn to Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Outlook or Gmail. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter to Apple though because they don&amp;rsquo;t make much money off their software - their billions in revenue mostly come from the iPhone. All Apple needs to do is make the iPhone a more enticing purchase than the other guys by offering any service you could want. If they create more revenue on the side - then&amp;hellip; gravy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Apple Music streaming service takes on the exact same narrative - a purely defensive play to check another box and take on Spotify. Except, Apple has millions of dollars to buy Beats, pay off high-profile musicians (Hi Drake! I love your music - thanks to Google Play), and scale the service up almost immediately. After all, there are already millions of iPhones out there that will have Apple Music installed by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevermind the fact that Apple Music is almost useless without a web player. How else do people listen to music at work? Not on their 500MB data plans - I can tell you that much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And since I&amp;rsquo;m ranting a bit, I also have my &amp;ldquo;one more thing&amp;rdquo;: How in all seven frozen hells did Apple Pay come to the UK before Canada? This probably isn&amp;rsquo;t Apple&amp;rsquo;s fault, but seriously, WTF. Our banking infrastructure is practically tailor-made for Apple Pay, but - alas - our regulatory bodies are not. But there were rumours, man! Solid rumours!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I digress. When the dust settles after WWDC this year, precisely nobody will be blown away. Heck, some may even be slightly disgruntled, as I appear to be. But it won&amp;rsquo;t matter to Apple. Because Apple is a hardware company. Always was and always will be. Sure, they&amp;rsquo;ll talk the talk about how their software is &amp;ldquo;really great&amp;rdquo;, but they&amp;rsquo;ll do it with an amused smile on their faces because they&amp;rsquo;re just dancing around a marketing script. WWDC is a time to relax - to crack a few jokes about Californian hippie stereotypes and dance like goofball dads to some summer music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real stress will come later this year, when the weather turns cold, when the Christmas shopping season approaches, and Apple will reveal the shiny new cash cows that they hope will maintain their status as the world&amp;rsquo;s most valuable company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rise of the google machine</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/rise-of-the-google-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 23:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/rise-of-the-google-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Google I/O last week, developments in Android M (Milkshake? Macaroon?), Android Pay, Android Wear, Internet of Things, and VR all made an appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it was Google&amp;rsquo;s advancements in machine learning that were the most impressive. The awkwardly-named &amp;ldquo;Now on Tap&amp;rdquo; in Android M exemplified these improvements nicely. Basically, Google will now offer in-context information within apps, emails, or web pages when pressing and holding the home button on your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if your receive a text from your wife asking you to pick up dinner, Google will offer to create a reminder. Any mention of movie titles will display links to the movie&amp;rsquo;s trailer, reviews, and other info. Restaurant names will trigger a formatted yelp review and OpenTable reservation options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could either marvel at the progress Google is making in artificial intelligence and machine learning, or you could be terrified by it. Either way, a healthy respect for this gargantuan digital overlord is probably wise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But could respect ever blossom into trust? During Google I/O this year, it became clear that Google is courting us and wants to be the hub of our digital lives. It turns out that Google Plus was a misstep in that direction, so Google is trying again. From the detritus of its dismantled social network, comes the new Google Photos - a standalone version of the excellent photos management division of Google Plus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The singular joy of Google Plus photo management was that Google offered unlimited photo and video uploads. However, photos were downsized considerably. This time around, Google is leveraging its incredible server farm assets to upload unlimited photos in their native resolution (up to a 16MP maximum).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This extremely generous cloud storage solution, coupled with seamless synchronization between a dedicated website and apps on both Android and iOS, makes Google Photos the most compelling photo management tool available today. Heck, I signed up on launch day and am still gobsmacked by how good it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how far can you trust a company whose raison d&amp;rsquo;être is to sell targeted ads? I mean, photos are intensely personal - intimate snapshots of our family lives, even our secret lives. Are you comfortable with that relentless Google machine silently parsing every picture you hand it? Because that is exactly what is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google positioned its machine learning as a positive feature, and at face value it is amazing: Search for any term, such as &amp;ldquo;flowers&amp;rdquo; for example, and Google will show you all the flower pictures you&amp;rsquo;ve taken (even though you&amp;rsquo;ve never tagged them). Type in &amp;ldquo;flowers in San Diego&amp;rdquo; and Google will check geo-location data to only show you pictures of flowers you took on that trip to San Diego a few years ago. Crazy cool, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is trying to build trust here, so there is no advertising in Google Photos&amp;hellip;yet. Targeted ads based on your photo collection does not seem far-fetched, however. In fact, it seems inevitable, especially once millions of users have invested the time and energy to curate their memories through Google&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo; service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I okay with this? Well, for the most part, I am. You&amp;rsquo;d be crazy to throw all your eggs into Google&amp;rsquo;s basket though. I am definitely keeping my photos stored locally as well. And it&amp;rsquo;s not as if I haven&amp;rsquo;t made forays into photo cloud storage. I tried Flickr&amp;rsquo;s redesigned photo service (offering a healthy 1 terabyte), but it&amp;rsquo;s just not as good. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even read Yahoo&amp;rsquo;s small print, which is probably horrifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason I&amp;rsquo;m okay with all of this is that I just don&amp;rsquo;t care if a machine is looking at my pictures. It would be different if, you know - an actual person - was ogling at my candid selfies. I&amp;rsquo;m sure a lot of people feel the same way. And so millions of us will feed data into the machine. That machine will only get smarter and smarter. So, what happens when that machine knows us better than we know ourselves? An interesting question, but I&amp;rsquo;m having too much fun organizing my pictures to think too much about it right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet snark that just won&#39;t die</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/internet-snark-that-just-wont-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 23:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/internet-snark-that-just-wont-die/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Humour has long been a staple of the Internet - in fact, you probably have some favourite delicious sites, such as the Onion or the Oatmeal, that you regularly check on for a fresh serving of laughs. But then there are those single-serving static sites that have been hosting the same joke for years and years and seem impervious to non-renewal. I wonder who keeps paying for these internet one-liners? They had their day in the sun years ago, but now languish in relative obscurity as faded internet legend.  Here are three such sites that refuse to die (and a recent one that should have died weeks ago, but didn&amp;rsquo;t).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zombo.com&#34;&gt;Zombo.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This parody of flash animation was created in 1999 and still manages to epitomize the weirdness of the internet in a way that no other site can. According to who you talk to, Zombo.com is either the best or most useless website in the world. Now that Flash is quickly becoming obsolete as HTML5 takes over, it will be interesting to see if future generations will find Zombo amusing at all, or just scratch their heads at the anachronistic humour of the 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://welcometointernet.org&#34;&gt;Welcometotheinternet.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now a sarcastic insult to mock those who don&amp;rsquo;t know how internet culture works, this phrase was first uttered by Homer Simpson in a 1998 episode. Not particularly funny anymore, sites like this are fading away from our collective memory - but aren&amp;rsquo;t in the grave yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lmgtfy.com&#34;&gt;lmgtfy.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let me Google that for you&amp;rdquo; is a 2008 site designed as a snarky response to questions asked online that can easily be answered by googling the answer. Although this site has been banned on some websites, the gentlemanly thing to do would be to put it to bed now that the meme is long past it&amp;rsquo;s prime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honourable mention: &lt;a href=&#34;http://Havidol.com&#34;&gt;Havidol.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first came across this satirical site &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/new-miracle-drug/&#34;&gt;back in 2007&lt;/a&gt;, but I was surprised to find that it&amp;rsquo;s still around. This parody campaign for a fictional medication actually fooled a number of people into thinking they had this disorder. I&amp;rsquo;m actually glad this site is still up because the concept is far cleverer than some of these other examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, I mentioned an internet gag that should have died weeks ago? Remember that mysterious button in &lt;em&gt;Lost&lt;/em&gt; that had to be pushed every 108 minutes or the world would end?  Reddit&amp;rsquo;s April Fool&amp;rsquo;s joke this year was to host a button with a sixty-second counter. Every Reddit user only has one click to reset the button to 60. Once the button counts down to zero&amp;hellip;nobody know what will happen. Because it hasn&amp;rsquo;t happened yet. Yes, people are still clicking &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/thebutton&#34;&gt;the button&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must admit, I am curious, but am also a bit disturbed. This joke reminds me a lot of the cow-clicking game in &lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.wired.com/magazine/2011/12/ff_cowclicker/all/&#34;&gt;this Wired article&lt;/a&gt; - a game that was supposed to be a &lt;em&gt;Farmville&lt;/em&gt; satire, but ended up being a legitimate phenomenon in itself, much to the befuddlement of the developer. Still, there is an allure to such a long-running gag. I&amp;rsquo;ll be sure to update this post once if the button ever reaches zero.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>