<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts-rsses on wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts-rsses on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 22:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Gratitude</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/an-immigrants-gratitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 22:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/an-immigrants-gratitude/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About twenty years ago, when I was a student, I lived in an old apartment building on a busy main street. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t in a good neighbourhood. The dudes in the building across from us appeared to be drug dealers and would beg us for smokes every time we went on the balcony - even though we never had any damn smokes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the rent was cheap. I had a roommate, and each of us chipped in less than $300 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That summer was the worst. The building was a rotting carcass that smelled sickening when the sun baked its cracked wooden siding. And even with the windows closed - which only made the smell worse - the noise from the traffic roaring by never ceased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had an early bedtime that summer because I was working at the Canadian Tire warehouse and had to wake up at 5 AM to make the bus on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I didn&amp;rsquo;t get much sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun doesn&amp;rsquo;t go down until late in the summer and I was too poor to buy proper curtains. I was also too poor to buy a proper bed, but a friend-of-a-friend who worked at 1-800-GOT-JUNK gave me a free mattress. I laid it straight down on the ratty carpet, and was almost immediately infested with bed bugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My feet hurt because my steel-toed boots were ill-fitting and rubbed my feet freshly raw every day. I hated walking in those boots, so much so that I accepted rides to the bus stop with this creepy dude at work. It turned out that he had an alternative agenda - one that involved cheating on his boyfriend. I had to endure him constantly printing updated versions of his DVD list and giving me copies during the car ride in an effort to entice me over to his place to &amp;ldquo;watch some movies&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even so, it was the traffic that kept me up at night. I&amp;rsquo;ve had an aversion to living on busy streets ever since. I have this theory that when everybody drive electric cars, the traffic noise will disappear. And that garbage real estate - homes next to highways - will become prime. But that hasn&amp;rsquo;t happened yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing that kept me sane that summer was reading The &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; trilogy for the first time. These days, the entry ticket for geekdom is cheap, but back then there were no LOTR movies to watch for a quick primer to Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s world. Those long books transported me away to a magical place at a time when I needed it most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, that torturous summer was over. I abandoned my mattress in the building&amp;rsquo;s storage locker, quit Canadian Tire, tossed my shoes away, moved out, and went back to school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still drive by that building every day of my life. I just don&amp;rsquo;t see it. It&amp;rsquo;s a black hole that sucks away the surrounding light. Or maybe there&amp;rsquo;s some sort of mysterious psychic cloak that shields my cognizant mind from noticing it anymore. Subconsciously though, there is something that gnaws at me when I drive by, like a haunted face in your peripheral vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, the neighbourhood has changed. A lot. You can&amp;rsquo;t buy a house on the busy street for under a million bucks, and the rent for a two-bedroom apartment would set you back a couple of thousand dollars a month. The drug-dealer scum has moved on across the bridge to some dark hole in Surrey probably and my kid&amp;rsquo;s newly-constructed school is just a few blocks away where a hospital used to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About twenty years ago, I came to Canada as an immigrant and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t good. I was twenty years old. I&amp;rsquo;m forty now, so that means I&amp;rsquo;ve lived an equal amount of time in both South Africa and Canada. That is quite the milestone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My life is much better now and I&amp;rsquo;m so thankful for that. I have a career that I love and a beautiful family. It&amp;rsquo;s funny - even though I&amp;rsquo;ve had much better summers since that time so long ago, the dark rain-drenched days of a Vancouver winter don&amp;rsquo;t bother me at all. In fact, I adore them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if hell has one gigantic silver-lining it would be this: I may never have ended up married to my lovely wife if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t lived in that awful building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, my life isn&amp;rsquo;t all rainbows and sunshine. It&amp;rsquo;s still hard most of the time in one way or the other - the same as yours. But you won&amp;rsquo;t find me complaining about how Starbucks misspelled my name on a paper cup or how the iPhone is a piece of trash without a headphone jack. At least not today. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m grateful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten years of wordbit</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/wordbit-ten-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/wordbit-ten-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago today, &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/what-is-a-wordbit-anyway/&#34;&gt;wordbit joined the blogosphere&lt;/a&gt;. A few years after that, the term &lt;em&gt;blogosphere&lt;/em&gt; joined other buzzwords such as &lt;em&gt;web 2.0&lt;/em&gt; in the internet fad graveyard. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping &lt;em&gt;social media&lt;/em&gt; will be joining them at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But ten years ago, social media was still fun and innocent. Heck - ten years ago, there were no smartphones. The iPhone was to debut about four months later in a defining moment that changed the trajectory of the internet forever. Three years later, in 2010, &lt;em&gt;Wired Magazine&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/2010/08/ff_webrip/&#34;&gt;declared that &amp;ldquo;the Web is dead&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. The Web, in case you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, meaning the World Wide Web (WWW) - a collection of html pages served up in desktop browsers. The Web&amp;rsquo;s death was greatly exaggerated of course - you can thank responsive web design for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then again, there are millions of people who use Facebook but &lt;a href=&#34;https://qz.com/333313/milliions-of-facebook-users-have-no-idea-theyre-using-the-internet/&#34;&gt;have no idea that Facebook exists on the Internet&lt;/a&gt;. Zuckerberg hooked even the most technophobic on the Internet without them even knowing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, the world is a different place - but where does that leave the humble blog?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no easy answer to that question. In fact, I would argue that the question does not matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard some rendition of &amp;ldquo;the blog is dead&amp;rdquo; for many years now. Perhaps that is concerning for those with money at stake. When blogs started generating traffic, along came metrics, advertising, blog rolls, comments, SEO, google analytics, and so on. Without these trappings, you could argue that a blog is nothing but a pulpit in the wilderness. But that is exactly what blogs started out as. That is what a blog really is, in its purest essence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the world&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://info.cern.ch/hypertext/WWW/TheProject.html&#34;&gt;first web page&lt;/a&gt;. It is nothing more than some text and links - the ultimate content delivery medium (second only to the paper page of a book, a content delivery platform honed over hundreds of years).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it that writers crave a content authoring GUI on the back-end that is clean, simple, and clutter-free? It is ostensibly so that they can focus on their writing without distraction. How hypocritical then, that we save the clutter for the front-end - for the user. Who is the user? It is blindingly simple. When it comes to blogs, the user is only one thing - the user is a reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always respect the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re writing on the web to make a living, then you have my sympathies. In all likelihood, you have moved on to serving bite-sized content for social media junkies to snack on. But for writers who just want to write, there is simply no better medium than the blog - preferably a good old html page served up in under one second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In under one second you say? Seems like a good time to list the tools I use to accomplish this. As I&amp;rsquo;ve previously mentioned, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved on to a static site generator, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, instead of wasting precious seconds with a database call, as you would with Wordpress. The site is hosted on Github, a tool which software developers use as a code respository with version control. I author in Markdown. I use StackEdit as an online markdown editor, mostly because it syncs so nicely with files in Google Drive. I should mention that this authoring setup is gaining favour in the technical writing world as well. In progressive circles at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, wordbit&amp;rsquo;s design has evolved to meet my ideal of ultimate reader friendliness, and I&amp;rsquo;m proud of that. But coming up with content is as challenging as its always been. No writer should assume that people have nothing better to do than read their writing, because these days people have plenty to occupy their time. The toughest part for any writer is coming up with a big idea, then staying on point and writing a focused piece of work that doesn&amp;rsquo;t ramble and stray from the topic. Blogs are a fickle beast because they started as online diaries and have evolved into many things, including legitimate journalism. At best, a blog post is simply an editorial that is interesting to read. If you keep coming back then it is the voice of the writer that appeals to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ve long since given up on pandering to anyone, and mostly just &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/why-write-when-nobodys-reading/&#34;&gt;write for my own benefit&lt;/a&gt;. But writing in a public medium is always a struggle between maintaining a degree of privacy, being honest, and staying relevant. After all, ten years ago I was at a different stage of life. My priorities have changed, the topics I&amp;rsquo;m comfortable writing about have changed, and the goals for my blog has changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed is that I still have that compulsion to write that plagues writers everywhere, and that&amp;rsquo;s not going to end while I&amp;rsquo;m still breathing. So, here&amp;rsquo;s to another decade of wordbit. I&amp;rsquo;ve made it this far - why stop now?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A foray into fitness tracking</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/a-foray-into-fitness-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 22:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/a-foray-into-fitness-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shelling out for a fitness tracker in January seems like a cliché. Yet, here I am - shelling out for a fitness tracker. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolution to get in shape, and I&amp;rsquo;m not planning on buying one of those ill-fated gym memberships that everybody regrets signing up for after one too many holiday pig-outs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is true though that I haven&amp;rsquo;t gone running for a while. I entirely blame the anomalous snowy weather we&amp;rsquo;ve been having on the West Coast for that. I also know that a fitness tracker won&amp;rsquo;t work miracles in getting my butt off the couch - only good old-fashioned discipline can do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess buying my first fitness tracker just kind of happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started a few days before Christmas. I was still in that trigger-happy purchasing mode you get into after ordering all your gifts online. This unbelievable deal came up on a Garmin Vivofit HR fitness tracker. Forty bucks. It was a one-click impulse buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the deal ended up on the Red Flag forums so of course hundreds of thousands of people tried to order one. Or two, or three. Needless to say, most of the orders were cancelled, including mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But by that time I&amp;rsquo;d already researched the hell out of the Vivofit I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be getting and really warmed up to the idea of wearing a dedicated fitness tracker. Although wearables in general have had a bit of a rough year, fitness trackers have carved out a niche market for themselves. Where smartwatches try to do it all, fitness trackers are far more focused and useful. I was ready to jump in and give them a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I did some more research - this time with more careful consideration of the design and features I liked. Only one fitness tracker stood out for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tracker comes from a company who has started taking more risks in the last few years. A company who has moved from ripping off design to playing on the bleeding edge of design. A company who tries to get it right with a strategy of frequent reiteration. Sometimes their risk-taking backfires horribly. But sometimes they come up with something really intriguing. That company is Samsung.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And their fitness tracker, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.samsung.com/global/galaxy/gear-fit2/&#34;&gt;Gear Fit 2&lt;/a&gt;, although not perfect, is quite simply the most compelling one out there today - at least for me it is (everybody is, of course, entitled to their own opinion).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to bore you (and me) with a hyperbolic rhapsody about how the curved AMOLED display wraps subtly around the wrist in a sleek, understated design, or how the inky blacks and vibrant colours make data visualization on the device a pleasure to view. So, I&amp;rsquo;ll stop right there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you can&amp;rsquo;t argue with any fitness tracker that packs in so many sensors, including a heart rate monitor, GPS, accelerometer, gyroscope, and barometer for only $150 (on sale at Best Buy). These sensors are what allows the Gear Fit to automatically detect your activities, determine your speed and distance, and plot your route on a map. Throw in sleep tracking, move reminders, step count, and floors climbed and you&amp;rsquo;ve got yourself a winner. That kind of functionality is on par with the Apple Watch Series 2 - except that the Apple Watch costs over $500.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gear Fit 2 has been out for about half a year now for Android phones only.  I knew that Samsung was working on supporting iOS sometime this year and that was good enough for me. As luck would have it though, one day after I ordered it (and before it even arrived), Samsung announced iOS compatibility at CES. So I was ready to go out of the box with syncing up to my iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all the phone sync stuff made the port, but I can receive notifications from my iPhone, as well as view my health metrics in Samsung&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;S Health&amp;rdquo; app, among other things. You don&amp;rsquo;t really need much else for a fitness tracker. However, if I was buying a full-fledged $500 Samsung smartwatch, like the Gear S3, the limited functionality would give me pause. I would probably just shell out for an Apple Watch in that case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But perhaps smartwatches are ultimately a failed experiment. Even though Apple has pivoted on their watch to position it more as a fitness device, it is still, by virtue of it&amp;rsquo;s original form factor - a watch. Also, a fitness tracker does not need premium materials, such as a sapphire screen and a gold housing. For example, as was obvious even when it first debuted, nobody wants to pay $20,000 for a solid gold Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact of the matter is that Apple doesn&amp;rsquo;t make a fitness tracker. They should though, because it would be great. It actually seems very un-Apple like to make something that does too much by trying to please everyone. If they really are trying to continue Steve Jobs&amp;rsquo; legacy, you would expect a more intentional device with a singular purpose and a simple user interface but with that undefinable richness to it that elicits that one emotion that Apple is perpetually chasing: delight. Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s asking too much?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should mention that the Gear Fit 2 uses a modded version of the open-sourced &lt;em&gt;Tizen&lt;/em&gt; operating system, not Android Wear. From my experience, it is fluid and responsive and perfectly fine for a UI on a small screen. However, there is virtually no third-party app support, so I don&amp;rsquo;t hold out much hope for viewing twitter feeds or calling Ubers on this thing - not that I&amp;rsquo;d want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to is just doing it - getting out there and running. At the moment, all my Gear Fit 2 is doing is nudging me to move when I&amp;rsquo;ve been sitting for too long. But &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/12/28/well/move/work-walk-5-minutes-work.html&#34;&gt;there are benefits&lt;/a&gt; to even this limited amount of activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/how-to-run-through-the-winter/&#34;&gt;I talk a big game&lt;/a&gt; when it comes to running through the winter, but all the snow on the ground this year has made it physically impossible to get out there much. My brother-in-law suggested hammering in a bunch of screws onto the soles of my running shoes for traction, but this seems a bit extreme. He lives in Edmonton though, so maybe that&amp;rsquo;s how they roll over there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, to wrap up, let me just say that I give the Gear Fit 2 a big thumbs up for anybody who wants to get their first fitness tracker. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing what the next few years brings to this market - that&amp;rsquo;s something I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have said a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new old MacBook Pro</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-new-old-macbook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 22:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-new-old-macbook-pro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About that MacBook Pro I had my eye on. I couldn’t wait. As much as I appreciate all my iMac has done for me, I just couldn’t listen to the endless spinning and chirping of that dreadful hard drive for another year without going insane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit, I was hoodwinked at first by the narrative spun by a few entitled tech journalists. It had been two years since the MacBook Pro was last updated in early 2015. People were hungry for a new mac. That is why the general disappointment was all the more compounded when the new MacBook Pros were released recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professionals bemoaned the lack of bleeding edge CPUs and a limit of 16GB of RAM, because they all of course need at least 32GB (dude, please). And recreational users (like me) winced hard at the sky-high price increase. An increase, no doubt, resulting from the addition of a questionable touch bar added to replace the function keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I came to another realization. A realization that perhaps did not enter the minds of most tech pundits who begrudge the steep price for being an early adopter, but then pay it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that realization is that the two-year old MacBook Pro is still a damn good laptop. And arguably a better laptop for the present. So that is the one that I got. Not the new one, but the “old” 2015 one that costs almost $1000 less than the touch-bar model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s face it - the 2015 MacBook Pro has all the ports you need today, including the awesome MagSafe adapter which got turfed in the new version. Early adopters are cursing the “dongle life” they have to endure with the new MacBook Pro, but instead it is “future me” who will be cursing at the late onset of dongle life. “Present me” is quite okay with that because I’ve got an SD card reader for easily importing photos, an HDMI port for connecting to the TV, USB ports that work with everything in the world right now (including every iPhone in existence), and a Mini DisplayPort that lets me use my iMac as a monitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess which laptop doesn’t connect to the iPhone without a dongle? That’s right - the “new” MacBook Pro. Chuckle at the irony if you want to but you won’t be laughing when you shell out almost $3000 for an Apple computer that doesn’t connect with Apple’s most popular product. You could argue that the new MacBook Pro is more future-proof than the old one, but think on this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future has not been written. There is no fate but what we make for ourselves.
&lt;em&gt;John Connor in Terminator 2: Judgement Day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to say that Apple has become so big that they have the weight to foist new I/O standards on people without caring about a backlash, but that’s not true because they’ve always been that way. Even when they were smaller and scrappier they killed the floppy drive without looking back. Change is not a bad thing, but all I’m saying is that we are free to accept change at our own pace. You can change today or you can change tomorrow. Like RRSPs - you can pay your income taxes now or you can save your money and defer your taxes until you retire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MacBook Pro is an altogether different product from the iMac, but the 2015 MacBook is an extremely nice upgrade for me. The retina screen is bright and crisp (the new &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/&#34;&gt;Verge&lt;/a&gt; re-design in particular looks gorgeous on it). The keyboard and trackpad are as buttery as you’d expect from a best-in-class laptop. But the sheer speed of the thing is what has me most excited. As I’ve mentioned many times before, a solid state drive makes all the difference when it comes to the user experience, moreso I believe than processing power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only caveat to this laptop is that the base model only has a 128GB hard drive. Upgrading to one terabyte costs an extra $1000, which is obviously ridiculous. Since pictures make up the bulk of our data (my wife has a particularly large library), I solved this problem by going external. I bought two 2TB external hard drives. One of the drives is purely a Time Machine backup of the first drive. Each drive cost me $90, so this comparatively cheap “outsourcing” more than makes up for the inconvenience of plugging in an external drive to look at photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan is to never back up the internal drive at all. All my documents, music, and movies all exist in the cloud at this point. Heck, even this blog is synced up to iCloud now. There should never be a need to save any data on the internal drive. You couldn’t have gotten away with that 10 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could go on, but I’m not trying to write a review here. I don’t think casual consumers can go wrong with this 2015 model though, especially if your computer is more than five years old, like mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you’re going to read a review of the new MacBook Pro, read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-macbook-pro-review-same-better-and-worse-1479128340&#34;&gt;Joanna Stern’s&lt;/a&gt;. She has the good sense not to take it all so seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She includes a picture, for example, of how the wider trackpad can fit at least four pieces of sushi - a facetious metric which underscores the ridiculousness of such “advances” in technology. She then says that you’ll “get used to the spring of the keys in the new flat keyboard” just as you “get used to sleeping on a rock when camping.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She had a lot of trouble trying to decide whether to recommend the 2016 model over the 2015 model. In the end, her advice is to “see where the new MacBook Pro is better, the same and, yes, worse than the old MacBook Pro, then decide what matters to you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is solid advice, and that is exactly what I’ve done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A winter post</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/a-winter-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/a-winter-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, well, well. A lot has happened since I last posted here. In short, the world has become a darker place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gentle rustle of leaves swaying in the summer breeze has been replaced with the dry death rattle of winter winds. Leonard Cohen released his final magnificent album and then breathed his last breath. America had a trainwreck of an election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I haven’t even got to Apple’s disappointing MacBook Pros yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a bad joke by the way. Or maybe it wasn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a personal note, I failed to post anything in September or October - thus betraying the promise (well, more of &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/pages/about/&#34;&gt;a mild-mannered suggestion&lt;/a&gt; really) to you of at least a monthly post. In my defense, I’ve been stressed out with moving. And with the kids starting new school and daycare schedules. Also, I turned 40 and became an old crotchety man overnight. The motivation to write is pretty low right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just getting this far feels like jerking one clunky wooden leg in front of the other and breathing hard. Hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a lighter note, we did manage to escape the Vancouver rain and get away on vacation to sunny San Diego. San Diego is such a stunning place. I mean just look at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/San Diego.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;San Diego&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we arrived in the USA in the evening of election day and were as surprised (to put it mildly) as everybody with the results. There were riots in a few American cities, which was a bit worrisome, but nothing major where we were staying on the beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although, we did hear a next-door neighbour angrily shouting “I can’t live here anymore!” And the next morning a woman who was clearly in anguish stumbled out of her beach house and prostrated herself on the sand. But that was about it. To relieve stress, Californians do yoga, go surfing, smoke some weed, and think about seceding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say half the country isn’t in one of the five stages of grief (with mostly anger surfacing at the moment). As Canadians we may have less skin in the game, but sweet Christmas, what a nightmare. What was it Trump said about our Prime Minister on Twitter? The shirtless one that everybody loves?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah: “Trudeau has done such a terrible job. He should be ashamed to call himself the President of Canada”. So&amp;hellip;I’m not overly optimistic about future Canada-US relations, even if Trump eventually figures out that Canada doesn’t have a “president”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I could go on, but I think YG sums it up the best, so I’ll leave the last word with him:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WkZ5e94QnWk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.youtube.com/vi/WkZ5e94QnWk/0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;YG&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually… nah, YG isn’t getting the last word on my blog. You could say that the very fact that YG can publicly express his opinions is a sign of a healthy democracy. After all, can you imagine a North Korean rapper putting out a song called “Fuck Kim Jong-un” and not disappearing into a prison camp (along with the next three generations of his bloodline)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an aside, being absolutely fascinated with North Korea after having lived in that area, I recommend the documentary &lt;em&gt;Under the Sun&lt;/em&gt;. This movie is a really unsettling look into the educational propaganda machine used to indoctrinate children into the supreme leadership cult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, a more insidious educational reform has occurred in the USA as well. Apparently, the aftermath of the &lt;em&gt;No Child Left Behind Act&lt;/em&gt; from the Bush administration has ensured that many young people can’t distinguish between the truth and fake news stories on Facebook. Did Trump really win because a fake story about the Pope endorsing Trump went viral on Facebook during the election? Probably not, especially since younger demographics voted blue. Stranger things have most definitely happened though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One fact, however, seems horribly certain - the average American no longer has a critical mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, let’s talk about some more mundane topics. A bunch of new beginnings at the end of 2016 - what a strange year. A year of shifting loyalties it seems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the phone front, I’ve made the tough choice of leaving Wind Mobile after five years and switching to Public Mobile. Since the former is now owned by Shaw and the latter is now owned by Telus, it’s not like I’m betraying any independents (who have now all been bought up by the incumbents). But Public Mobile was offering 4GB of LTE data for the same price I was paying for 5GB of 3G data - a deal too good to pass up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know Wind is deploying their own LTE network soon using the AWS-3 spectrum, but only the LG V-20 supports this band so far, and I plan on keeping my iPhone for another two or three years. So, I may as well enjoy those high speeds today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, a few days after I started writing this (yes, I am that slow), Wind Mobile changed their name to Freedom Mobile. They also introduced their LTE plan, but it doesn’t look like the current 3G plans will be grandfathered over to LTE - I would have to give up my old plan anyway. So, I’m feeling good about my choice now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the internet front, this very website that you’re reading right now is approaching its ten-year anniversary next year. A lot has changed in ten years. Billions of people now access the internet only through Facebook. Can you believe that? Billions more access content only on their phones and has left the humble desktop browser lurching into an inexorable decline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when Godaddy wanted to charge me over $20 a year to renew my domain, I choked. I almost let wordbit.com die. They couldn’t even throw me a bone after being a loyal customer for almost ten years. But I really want to make that anniversary. Even though this website means nothing to anybody else, it still stupidly means something to me. So I switched to Namecheap, which is a company which at least lives up to its name. The only question is, why the heck didn’t I do it sooner?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A word about those new MacBook Pros. They actually are disappointing - I wasn’t joking about that. My iMac, after all, is a mid-2010 model that is so agonizingly slow. I was hoping to upgrade to a nice laptop this year and use the iMac as a secondary monitor. But, after seeing those sickening price increases and the mixed reviews, I’ve decided to wait another year. Or maybe just wait until my iMac is no longer supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, there isn’t a whole lot I do on my iMac anymore. I don’t have time to edit pictures and videos. Writing this blog doesn’t exactly require a workhorse PC. There are one or two Mac-specific applications I use, but my iPad easily handles daily web browsing and the odd Youtube video. I just have a really hard time letting go of the PC as a hub for my digital life. I think the cloud is getting close, but it isn’t there yet - privacy and security issues aside. And gaming… well the Mac was never an awesome gaming machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, my wife got me a PS4 for my birthday, and it is obviously an extremely capable gaming machine. I started playing &lt;em&gt;Uncharted 4: A Thief’s End&lt;/em&gt;, and am not only blown away by the improved graphics (I spent an overly long time staring at the play of light and sky reflecting off a puddle of water), but at the generous amount of character development. The character models and facial expressions are so good I couldn’t help but watch the cutscenes with a goofy smile on my face. The mechanics when two characters are making out are still horribly awkward though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Black Friday seems like a good time to stock up on a few PS4 titles - then I should be set for the next year. Saving money is a great advantage of being a late adopter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ended up being a bit of a messy opinionated / newsy post, so I’ll dispense with the epic well thought-out conclusion and just say thanks for stopping by - despite the two-month break. I hope to keep clunking on for a few more years to come, so until next time - stay frosty my friends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The greatest real estate opportunity on planet Earth</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-greatest-real-estate-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 20:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-greatest-real-estate-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All you savvy investors out there must know by now that you can make ridiculous amounts of money in Vancouver real estate. Those who bought a few years ago are doing VERY well for themselves. We thought this wild ride couldn’t last, but prices keep going up and up and up, with no end to the gravy train in sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that’s not really true - there have been rumblings in the media about bubbles popping, or some such nonsense, but let me assure you: there is still money to be made. Even for all you foreign investors saddled with that 15 percent tax&amp;hellip; My advice is - ignore the tax, my friends. 15 percent is nothing, NOTHING, compared to the gains you will make in the next decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, if you’re trying to decide whether to invest in Toronto or Vancouver, keep in mind that Toronto sucks. You may not know this, but Toronto does not have ANY mountains. Not one. And mountains make for spectacular views. Yes, the majority of Vancouver houses don’t have mountain views, but that is irrelevant. Just knowing the mountains exist is enough to put a smug smile on the face of a Vancouver homeowner. Look at what happened to Calgary - they have no mountains and now everybody there is sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, the delightfully high real estate prices are having a wonderful sanitizing effect. High rents and property values are forcing all those disgusting mom and pop stores, many of which are run by shady immigrants, to close. Even better, low income families with noisy children are being chased out of the city. All those related services which cost the city money will follow, such as daycares, schools, libraries, recreation centres, playgrounds, etc. Speaking of noise, there will be no more rowdy students to worry about either. Instead, the elite will flock to Vancouver - mature, cultured, and wealthy beyond all measure. Think sports cars and luxury yachts. Think Monaco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, ordinary Canadians need heavy mortgages to buy a home. These poor fools are in so much debt that the bank will own them for the rest of their lives, but they will love you for it. Why? Because when they eventually retire, they will embrace you with tears in their eyes for making them elderly millionaires for a few years before they die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, global warming will soon turn Vancouver into the next Los Angeles. I mean, literally the next Los Angeles. It seems certain that once the real Los Angeles becomes an inhospitable desert and runs out of water, America, led by the great President Donald Trump, will buy Canada and merge it into the USA. Then he will relocate Los Angeles further up the coast. All the movie stars will move there, they will put a new “Hollywood” sign up on the North Shore mountains, and Elon Musk will start building spaceships in Surrey. It will be glorious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it. There will be no “crash” or even a “soft landing”. Real estate prices will keep going up and up forever. You know the adage, “buy low, and sell high”? Well this is as low as it gets. I am telling you (with all the sincerest honesty that I can muster) that $5 million for a crackhouse on Vancouver’s East Side is a fantastic deal. FANTASTIC. Vancouver, without a doubt, represents the greatest real estate opportunity on planet Earth right now, and you would be a red-faced fool not to buy, buy, buy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A summer post</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/a-summer-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 16:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/a-summer-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s a beautiful Sunday afternoon in the middle of July - a pleasant breeze blows and it isn&amp;rsquo;t sweltering like it was last summer. I&amp;rsquo;m leaning up against a log on the south side of Queen&amp;rsquo;s Park and writing this post on my iPad. The Patullo Bridge is closed this weekend for seismic upgrades, so this area of the park is unusually serene - the drone of traffic crossing the bridge into Surrey is delightfully absent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The groundskeepers tend to ignore this part of the park because it is seldom frequented. It has a slightly unkempt, natural look  - unlike the manicured gardens to the North where happy young couples take wedding pictures in the rose garden. I like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing like sitting quietly in nature. I feel rejuvenated and at peace. Green spaces quench the thirsty soul and wash away the thick stench of the city. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine how unhappy I&amp;rsquo;d feel if I lived in the middle of an urban wasteland. A concrete prison with an apartment window looking at a brick wall and a cubicle at work with no windows at all. I guess a lot of people live that way, which explains a lot about all the aggression and stress in this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my lunch breaks I go for a run along the Pitt River. Halfway through, I stop at a small beach and sit for awhile. There is an uninhabited island in the middle of the river. It is blanketed in leafy trees and eagles spiral lazily above - guardians of a sanctuary where no people set foot. I gaze at this island and quiet my mind for a few minutes before heading back to work. I always have a more productive afternoon when I do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel lucky to be living here in British Columbia, where there are more trees than people and water is never very far away. The insane real estate in the Vancouver area is disheartening of course, but that is another conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I apologize if this meandering post doesn’t seem to have a point. I’m not trying to write one of those self-righteous diatribes about unplugging and going on a tech detox. Because, as you&amp;rsquo;ve probably figured out, I love technological innovation and trying to suss out its impact on our society. And if you&amp;rsquo;re not into the outdoors, I can respect that - especially if you&amp;rsquo;re honest about it, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vice.com/en_ca/read/being-canadian-to-me-means-not-giving-a-shit-about-the-outdoors&#34;&gt;like this outdoor-hating Canadian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the summer does give us all a reminder that moderation in our lives brings greater joy than either overindulgence or abstinence. So, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to create as well as consume. By all means read your Kindle on the beach. But also sit on top of a mountain and write or paint or whatever it is you do to nurture your creative side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you never drink, have a frosty beer on a patio. If you drink too much, then go for a swim instead. If you’re an introverted hermit, find an open space and fly a kite - look up into the blue sky instead of looking down all the time. But seek the shade of a quiet forest if you&amp;rsquo;re a gregarious sun worshipper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kids - I&amp;rsquo;m talking to you now. Have fun going outside to play Pokémon GO, but don&amp;rsquo;t forget to look up and smile at that pretty girl or handsome boy walking down the street. Also, don&amp;rsquo;t look for pokémons in sacred places, like Holocaust Museums. You have better sense than that - it isn&amp;rsquo;t up to the game creators to police your bad behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I guess that&amp;rsquo;s all I have to say this month. Let me take the opportunity to wish you all a glorious summer. Thanks as always for stopping by - I will see you in August.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WWDC 2016</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/apple-wwdc-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 22:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/apple-wwdc-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unlike Google and the other guys, there was no talk of AI or bots at Apple’s software showcase this year. Instead, Apple was true to form, highlighting aspects like “differential privacy” and “continuity” - features that keep you locked into their ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the event was fairly low key with Apple focused on improving and polishing rather than innovating (I think it was the announcement of universal cut and paste that got the biggest round of applause).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, I always enjoy sitting down to watch the two-hour infomercial that is the keynote - if only to see what free stuff I’m going to get. Remember when Apple actually charged for software upgrades? It’s way more fun to watch these things &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; you’ve sold your kidney for Apple hardware. There is no angst at WWDC - only benefits for those who have already paid the Apple tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the keynote was divided into four software platforms, I’ll do the same and comment on each one individually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;watchos-3&#34;&gt;watchOS 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sold on the Apple watch hardware just yet. I still think round smartwatches look far more classic than rectangular ones. Sure, you can read more text on a rectangular display, but I think Jony Ive should have focussed on form, and not function in this case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, Apple is positioning this thing as a fashion accessory - not a Casio calculator watch reboot. Never mind that Tim Cook sees the Apple watch as more of a fitness wearable… Forget trying to please everyone - time to focus guys!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the software side though, I am happy that they gutted the software and started over on the user interface. I’m happy because it means Apple is still committed to developing this product, and future iterations should be way more enticing than the clunky gadget this watch is now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tvos-10&#34;&gt;tvOS 10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have the Apple TV 3, so am not going to get these updates either. But I really don’t need Siri or apps on my Apple TV when I only use it for Netflix and Youtube. Also, the remote app on the iPhone is actually way more useful than the Apple TV 4 physical remote anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the Apple TV has more potential for disruption in the US, but the CRTC in Canada is never going to let the Apple TV take down the cable companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am far more interested in the rumours of an Alexa-like Siri box, possibly bundled into the next-gen Apple TV. We’ll see if those rumours pan out later this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;macos-sierra&#34;&gt;macOS Sierra&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My aging mid-2010 iMac just made the eligibility cutoff this year - iMacs that came out before 2009 are out of luck. I wish I could say that my iMac is aging gracefully, but the HDD hard drive is slowing down and crippling performance to the point of frustration. SSD hard drives were an emerging and expensive technology six years ago, but now it’s a no-brainer to go with solid state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Siri is coming to the Mac, which is good news… I guess? I’ll be able to ask Siri how much hard drive space I have left on my horribly slow hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought it was cool that the desktop and documents folders will be backed up to iCloud… but then again, you only get 5GB of free space, and Apple is pushing hard to put &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; in iCloud so you have to buy more storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I think of it, there isn’t a whole lot in macOS (formerly OS X) that is worth getting excited about, but hey, it’s free! And - that name change!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ios-10&#34;&gt;iOS 10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the iPhone is my newest Apple product, I was most interested in what’s new on the mobile front. Oh, and my iPad! I almost forgot you iPad, along with everybody else (drum roll please).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But seriously, even the minor update we got a few months ago with “Night Shift” was legitimately useful. Night Shift, in case you’re not aware, shifts the colour hue from blue to yellow at sunset everyday. I am now quite used to being bathed in a warm yellow glow every night. I wish my Kindle Paperwhite had this feature - the jarring switch to the bright blue Kindle screen after using my iPad at night feels like being blinded with a couple of photon torpedoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, “APIs for third parties” (or, &amp;ldquo;it’s an API party!&amp;rdquo;) was the defining theme of the upcoming improvements - a continuation of Apple’s ongoing efforts to be more open and developer friendly. The idea is that software hooks in Siri, Maps, and iMessage will allow a more seamless user experience. The example Craig Federighi demoed on stage was going to Maps and seeing restaurant reviews, booking a table, calling an Uber to get there, and paying for everything - all without ever leaving Maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My feelings on this sort of integration hasn’t changed much - the convenience in this scenario is great if you’re a single Silicon-Valley bro with money to burn. But if you’re a family man who needs to shop around for the best price, and needs to install car seats for the kids, and… well, let’s just say I can think of many ways to kibosh the above scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parts of iOS 10 that I like the best are the user interface improvements. The lock screen, control centre, notifications screen, and “Siri suggestions” screen (all in heavy day-to-day use) have all been revamped. Rich notifications and widgets on the lock screen with 3D-Touch support are especially great. Design-wise, they look a lot like the “Google Now cards”, which I&amp;rsquo;ve always thought were fantastic, and I can’t blame Apple for copying them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of people have said this, and I agree - at this point it doesn’t matter who is copying who. Android and iOS are borrowing the best from each other and are both converging into a user-focused paradigm. The result is a win for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing-thoughts&#34;&gt;Closing thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed watching the keynote, in the same way I enjoy listening to an old record. The familiarity and rhythm of it is pleasing in a way. But I’m not too happy about Apple trying to supplement flagging iPhone sales (in terms of growth, not revenue) by pushing paid services on us. It feels a bit disingenuous to claim you want a magical user experience on one hand, then push iCloud upgrades and accessories on the other (ooh look - you can unlock your iMac with your Apple watch - well why not with your iPhone?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;September is going to be interesting because it looks like Apple is going to ditch the tick-tock iPhone overhaul pattern. Rumours are pointing to a modest upgrade this year, with a radical design change slated for 2017 - the 10th anniversary of the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are savvy Apple fans going to forgo the upgrade this year and cost Apple billions of dollars in lost revenue? Stranger things have happened, I suppose. But there was nothing strange about WWDC 2016 (well, there was that rap-along) - on the software front, it&amp;rsquo;s business as usual, and that&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google I/O 2016</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/google-io-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 17:42:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/google-io-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I sat down to watch this year’s I/O keynote, I couldn’t &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/rise-of-the-google-machine/&#34;&gt;help but recall&lt;/a&gt; last year’s incredible gift to the Google faithful - Google Photos. Free unlimited uploads in their full resolution for pictures under 16MP. It was, and still is, an amazing service. It even uploads Live Photos on my iPhone 6S - something that even iCloud’s photostream doesn’t do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps a few years from now, Google will hold our bloated photo libraries hostage in exchange for our souls, but so far this hasn’t happened. And maybe when it does happen, we’ll willingly pay the price. It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to become addicted to the machine learning that organizes our pictures and creates photo albums for us; machine learning that can identify the content of every photo. How could you not love searching for “hugs” to view all those pictures of your loved ones engaged in a warm embrace?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year there were no surprise gifts, but Google continued to show off its burgeoning AI prowess. A new messaging app was shown with eerie “smart replies” that allows the AI to answer in your stead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picture a world where text message conversations are going on in the background between your AI and another person. Or even between two AIs. We’ll be able to abscond all social responsibility by surrendering social conversations to chatbots. In fact, this world is here already with AIs such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.ai/&#34;&gt;Amy&lt;/a&gt;, a “personal assistant” who schedules meetings for you. I expect chatbot AIs to proliferate wildly in the next few years, and could even be “the next big thing”. Companies who don’t manage to catch the next wave &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2016/5/25/11765624/walt-mossberg-apple-wwdc-2016-siri-ai-bots&#34;&gt;could find themselves left behind&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Google is throwing considerable weight behind its AI efforts, and the results are impressive. However, the AI application in Google Photos seems almost heartwarming compared to this year’s offerings. The messaging app, Allo, will almost certainly be ignored, considering the sheer number of messaging apps available, several of which Google has already put out there and left to stagnate (hangouts anyone?). Ultimately the messaging demo came across like that annoying smart kid in class who tries to entertain others by showing off how clever he is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A far more interesting application of Google’s AI (simply called Google Assistant) was shown in &lt;a href=&#34;https://home.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google Home&lt;/a&gt; - an unabashed ripoff of Amazon’s Echo. Copying an existing product isn’t going to elicit gasps of amazement from the crowd, but competition in this area isn’t a bad thing either. Yet, while the Echo allows you to order replacement toilet paper with a spoken command (from Amazon of course), Google has a grander vision. They already have excellent AI chops, as evident in the “OK Google” voice commands in the mobile space. If done right, Home could conceivably become that omniscient computer in the sky that Star Trek fans are intimately familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rumours have already started flying that Apple is also working on an ambient personal assistant to rival Echo - perhaps a revised Apple TV with facial-recognition cameras. But for now, we’ll put Apple speculation aside until WWDC in a couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sundar Pichai clearly sees AI as an avenue where Google can excel, and I tend to agree with him. No other company has the foundation of search algorithms, machine learning, big data, and access to a treasure trove of user data like Google has. And, very importantly, no other large-scale company is so comfortable being platform agnostic. While true sentient AI is a long way off, they are poised to usher in skynet’s great grandfather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this scares you, then it is simply because you are a denizen of the information age whose modus operandi revolves around you as the information gatherer - with you at the helm. It isn’t easy to relinquish control - just as it wasn’t easy for people at the tail end of the industrial age to abandon their reliance on physical manufacturing as their primary economic driver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if all this doesn’t scare you, then you’re probably reading this in the 22nd century. Perhaps you are amazed that humans once engaged in independent thought. Perhaps in surrendering the sanctity of your privacy and your body to the machine, you are now at peace because your human toils are over. Perhaps you have evolved into a cyborg with some sort of AI synthesis, like in the &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect 3&lt;/em&gt; ending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all seriousness though - regardless of where you stand today, the information age is reaching an end. If you cling to the old ways, you are now an anachronism in the looming AI age. It is still unclear what our roles will be in this new age, but what is clear is that we won’t be controlling the flow and manipulation of information anymore. If knowledge is power, then the machines have already won.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unrequited</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/unrequited/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 21:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/unrequited/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear user,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve never met, but I write to you every day. Writing to you is my job, but still, I do care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts with the small things. Knowing the frustration of ambiguity, I try to choose the perfect words for you. I painstakingly pore over both our company’s Language Guide, as well as the latest Simplified Technical English specification to ensure I am not using any forbidden words. I also try to use terminology consistently, so that I don’t give the same part two different names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also never use the word &amp;ldquo;utilize&amp;rdquo;. Although, to my abject horror, one instance did slip through when I copied some text from the Sales and Marketing department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then craft the perfect sentences - not too long, not too complex, but with delightful variations in syntactic structure so that you don’t get bored. I polish these sentences so that they are as smooth and round as a river stone, and can therefore be reused in multiple contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These shiny sentences are placed in self-contained topics, as per DITA guidelines. You can get all the information you are looking for, whether it be an explanation or a procedure, just by reading this brief chunk of text. I will never hyperlink you away to other topics, or expect you to hunt for crucial details elsewhere - I know your time is valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to make your job easier, because I know you’re a tough guy who does tough work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re a structural engineer who needs to inspect your bridge pylons. You’re a fisherman at sea trawling for your catch. You’re an ROV operator trying to dig an underwater trench. You’re a police officer on a diving team assigned to investigate the latest homicide. You’re &amp;ldquo;in the Navy now&amp;rdquo; and your commanding officer just assigned you to berth clearance and underwater security. You’re a treasure hunter who is looking for that lost shipwreck - you know the one with all that Spanish gold on it, like in &lt;em&gt;The Goonies&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as much as I respect what you do, I must confess that I’m not wholly altruistic in my motives. After all, the constant companion during my days of writing is not you - it is the words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow me an allegory. The blacksmith who makes a sword for a knight certainly wants the knight to succeed. If the sword snaps, if the weight is off, if shoddy workmanship results in a lethal end for the knight on the battlefield, then both the blacksmith&amp;rsquo;s pride and reputation will suffer. But the blacksmith’s true love is in the forging of the sword and in transforming raw and molten metals into something greater. What the blacksmith savours more than fame or glory is the slow process of hammering out the metal and continuously reshaping it until a weapon emerges. A weapon that not only performs its function, but could be seen by some as a work of art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it is with writing manuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This love I have for the craft is why I am not concerned whether you RTFM. In fact, I sincerely hope that you do not ever have to read one of my manuals from cover to cover. I am also nonplussed that my endless word tinkering will go largely unappreciated. You will never wax eloquent over the use of an Oxford Comma while figuring out how to operate your sonar. You won’t go on your smoke break and nod your head sagely at a particularly snappy sentence that says in four words what other less meticulous writers say in fifteen words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, I am your invisible defender and advocate. I am the guardian angel that you will never know you have. I even go toe-to-toe with software developers over language nuances in the user interface that software developers most certainly do not care about. Software developers only care about the little piece of code they are working on - they’re not concerned with the big picture. Mostly. I’m painting with a large brush here, but this has been my experience most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our software lead does write great user experience specifications though - complete with user stories about a stick figure named Joe. Software engineers actually documenting things is an astoundingly rare occurence, however. And if you&amp;rsquo;re a software developer, I expect you&amp;rsquo;ll be nodding along in agreement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you see, dear user, that I do care. But even though I write &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; you every day, I do not write &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; you every day. I write for me. This is true of all writers, no matter who they are and what they write. Do you think Stephen King needs you to buy any more of his novels? The short answer is: hahaha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, even though we write mostly to amuse ourselves, a rising tide lifts all boats, as JFK once said. Good writing benefits everyone - and it is my gift to you, dear user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your friendly neighbourhood technical writer&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tesla&#39;s Model 3</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/tesla-model-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 20:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/tesla-model-three/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tesla’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.teslamotors.com/model3&#34;&gt;Model 3&lt;/a&gt; is not only a jaw-droppingly stylish car, it is also a compelling window into a future world where the electric car is king.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It certainly has anyone who is interested in technology and design drooling. Tesla’s electric cars come across as gadgets, complete with over-the-air software upgrades - not boring utilitarian vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the Model 3 truly is a product of the tech industry. It’s also an eccentric genius billionaire’s baby. Which makes Tesla a truly unique company, and the Model 3 an astoundingly fresh entrant in a stale car industry. An industry, by the way, that last saw true innovation over a hundred years ago with the debut of Henry Ford’s Model T.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is the Model 3 really a vision of the future, or merely a mirage?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seven years ago I wrote an article called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alive.com/lifestyle/the-eco-dilemma/&#34;&gt;The Eco Dilemma&lt;/a&gt; about the electric car as a utopian fantasy. At the time, the economy was in shambles, gas prices were sky high, climate change was scaring the hell out of us, and there was strong interest in alternatives to fossil fuels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today the economy is better, gas is dirt cheap, and people are sick of hearing about climate change. Besides from this, my article still stands true. I stand by my conclusion that what we need most are sustainable communities based on an analysis of local needs, whether that be effective public transit in urban areas, or telecommuting in the suburbs. The car, after all - whether electric or gas-powered - does reek of that entitled Western mentality born out of the 1950s American dream of mass suburbia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, although going car-free is a laudable option, it is probably most appealing to that small subset of Earth’s population who want to save money and have access to decent public transit (being green is just a bonus title they can claim for brownie points). Totally doable if you live, for example, in New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for the vast majority who must drive, or prefer it, electric cars seem like a way to have your cake and eat it too. Assuming, of course, your local electrical grid sources its power from clean energy. I mentioned this particular quandary in my article and it &lt;a href=&#34;http://gizmodo.com/why-teslas-model-3-car-cant-fix-our-energy-problems-1768095326&#34;&gt;still stands true today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scaling up an electric car infrastructure for mass adoption is arguably a more insurmountable problem than engineering appealing and relatively affordable electric cars. In fact, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/2016/01/gm-electric-car-chevy-bolt-mary-barra/&#34;&gt;General Motors will actually beat Tesla&lt;/a&gt; in bringing a $35000 electric car with a 200-mile range to the masses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tesla has some answers to the infrastructure problem. Their supercharger network may ease range anxiety for the few times a year that you go on a road trip. A more pressing infrastructure challenge may be building enough centres to service a massive influx of new customers. The same challenge will apply to any manufacturer who has invested in a gas-centric infrastructure for the past 100 years - pivoting is no easy task (GM take note).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting an astounding number of pre-orders, there is also some doubt as to whether Tesla can ramp up production fast enough to meet all the pent-up demand. And do so with sufficient quality control so that there aren’t &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2016/4/8/11393278/tesla-model-3-vs-apple-iphone-sales-compared&#34;&gt;too many defects introduced&lt;/a&gt; with such rapid production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this is all conjecture at this point - I’m willing to give Tesla the benefit of the doubt and see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I would love to own a Model 3, despite these uncertainties - and I’m no car guy. Maybe it was reading Elon’s biography (by Ashlee Vance) that sold me on Tesla as part of a grand vision (that culminates in sending people to Mars). Or maybe it was insane blog posts like &lt;a href=&#34;http://waitbutwhy.com/2015/06/how-tesla-will-change-your-life.html&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps I’m just a sucker for shiny new tech, and as I mentioned earlier - Tesla is basically software on wheels, not a bunch of controlled explosions stuffed into a tin can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately though, I’m probably not going to end up in the Model 3 driver’s seat (note that I did not say “never”, because hopelessness is so gauche, you know).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sobering fact is that the Model 3 is still unaffordable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Model 3 may be priced to sell (whatever that is supposed to mean) in the US at least. However, with the Canadian dollar at an all-time low, $35000 US ends up being almost $46000 at today’s exchange rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that British Columbia’s energy supply is relatively clean, with 86 percent generated by hydroelectricity. The bad news is that BC’s subsidy for buying electric cars is only $5000, or up to $8250 if you scrap your old car. In Ontario, you can get up to $14000 off. Norway has insane incentives - in fact, the Model S is actually the &lt;em&gt;overall&lt;/em&gt; number one selling car over there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, for electric cars to be practical, you need to live in a detached house with a garage. When charging the batteries overnight, street parking isn’t going to cut it. In Vancouver, the average price for a detached home is almost $2 million dollars (as of March 2016). Yes, you read that right. Vancouver has the most expensive real estate in Canada, so most of us, including our family, live in a condo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, most condo strata councils aren’t exactly forward thinking. You could end up like &lt;a href=&#34;http://bc.ctvnews.ca/no-charge-couple-forced-to-move-because-of-electric-vehicle-1.1987615&#34;&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt;, who was forced to move because his strata refused to let him charge his electric car (now that is a true green warrior - he would rather sell his condo than sell his car). He offered more than enough money to cover the costs, so it wasn’t even a financial thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in summary, to get a Model 3, you need to spend at least $40000 to buy it new (you could buy a new Mercedes-Benz for that price), and own a detached house so that you can charge it every night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, this is no car for “the everyman”, especially in this city, where you’d have to be a millionaire to afford it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, does my dream to own a Model 3 die here, in this obscure blog post at the end of the internet? Well, there is always hope. Hope and the kidney black market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it is easier to just sit back and appreciate the turn of the tide. To bear witness to a new era of innovation in the auto industry. That in itself will be a boon to our battered planet, because yes, I still care about our planet a little, even if I won’t be driving a green dream machine to prove it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batman v Superman</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/batman-v-superman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 20:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/batman-v-superman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a poignant moment in &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade&lt;/em&gt; when the Holy Grail crosses the Great Seal and triggers the collapse of the Temple of the Sun. The earth is torn asunder, and Elsa, a Nazi agent and Austrian archaeologist, loses her life. After Indiana Jones fails to save her, he ends up hanging precariously in the crevice himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indiana’s father catches his hand and tries to pull him to safety. But, with his other hand, Indiana tries to reach the Holy Grail, which rests tantalizingly on a narrow ledge nearby. He can almost reach it; his fingertips brush it. But his father cannot hold on as oily sweat causes their hands to slip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indiana’s father (so aptly played by Sean Connery), says, in a soft, gentle voice: “Indiana… Indiana… let it go”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he does. As Indiana rides into the sunset and John William’s theme song swells over the closing credits, we knew it really was his last crusade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we were wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty years later, a considerably older and stiffer Harrison Ford donned Indie’s hat once more for a mostly terrible comeback movie with a crystal skull and that kid from &lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;/em&gt;. It wasn’t a huge deal though. At worst, the flick was nothing more than an embarrassing footnote, best ignored. At best, a bonus Blu-ray tacked onto the already excellent Indiana Jones trilogy box set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, they just couldn’t let it go. Indiana Jones is slated to return in 2019, starring an almost 80-year old Harrison Ford. There is no doubt in anyone’s mind that it will be humiliating and awful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also completely unsurprising. The status quo in a talent-starved Hollywood is to play it safe amid decreasing revenues. It has been this way for years now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cries of indignation from the fans are depressingly familiar. Please stop messing with my childhood. Please stop corrupting the purity of my trilogy box sets. Please stop commodifying nostalgia and cheapening the originals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Hollywood isn’t going to stop anytime soon, because they’ve hit upon a winning formula. Appeal to the nostalgia of older audiences while remixing, rebooting, and resurrecting box-office darlings for new audiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, this formula pays off. For example, the Star Wars reboot, &lt;em&gt;The Force Awakens&lt;/em&gt;, was an appealing return to the Star Wars universe, despite re-hashing the exact same plot of &lt;em&gt;A New Hope&lt;/em&gt;. But a strong female lead, a tight script, and J.J. Abrams managed to re-energize the property (I doubt whether the next Star Wars movies can repeat this feat).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most often, though, it is all too easy to overdo an homage to the original without being original - &lt;em&gt;Jurassic World&lt;/em&gt; springs to mind. Or to try too hard - an all-female &lt;em&gt;Ghostbusters&lt;/em&gt; reboot seems a bit blunt and unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, after all avenues have been explored, everything just implodes on itself like a family squabble that nobody outside the family really cares about. Why is Superman fighting Batman? Why is Iron Man fighting Captain America? Who knows? Who cares? You’ve lost us - and in some cases, even alienated us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t seen &lt;em&gt;Batman v Superman&lt;/em&gt; yet, but the critics have slammed it, and a lot of Superman fans are disappointed about such a dark departure from the Christopher Reeve era. Drop Lex Luthor off at the local prison while trading family-friendly quips, or just snap his neck? This conflict is explored in a far more nuanced way in excellent new Netflix shows like &lt;em&gt;Daredevil&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Jessica Jones&lt;/em&gt;. But injecting “realism” into Superman does nothing more than taint the ethos of a celebrated superhero that arose in the patriotic 1930s. He is not your hero - he is your grandfather’s hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All our cherished characters belong to a unique and idiosyncratic time and place. And they need to stay in the past. They are part of our history, our upbringing, our collective mythos, shared from parent to child. When we offer new perspectives and reimaginings of old characters, will our children appreciate the originals with us, or adopt the shiny, corrupted versions as the “real” incarnation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, there is hope. Perhaps the tides are shifting. As fans, we used to be grateful for even terrible movies about our heroes, because there were so few. But now… there really is no reason to watch a bad Superman movie. Zack Snyder isn’t holding a gun between our eyes and forcing us to watch it. We have a choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And maybe the best choice is to let it go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;EDIT - May 12, 2016: I couldn&#39;t let it go. I did pay good money to see Batman duking it out with Superman. My friends wanted to see it so I had to swallow my righteousness and join the unwashed masses in the cinema. It was pretty much what I expected. Wonder Woman was fantastic, but man, they need to hire better writers. What would it take to get the Avengers writing team to give it a go? Too much, I reckon.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battle of the five armies</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/battle-of-the-five-armies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 15:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/battle-of-the-five-armies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kanye West&amp;rsquo;s new album, &lt;em&gt;The Life of Pablo&lt;/em&gt;, is fantastic. At least, that&amp;rsquo;s what people who&amp;rsquo;ve signed up for Tidal say. Because Jay Z’s streaming service is the only place you can get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except for, of course, other illicit means. But we’ll get to that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after the album’s release, Kanye crowed on Twitter that his album will never be available on Apple Music (or on CDs for that matter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels like the West Coast vs East Coast rivalry all over again. We have Apple Music on the West Coast, with Dr. Dre and friends. Then we have Jay Z and crew representing the East Coast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, should I say, the metaphorical East Coast. Because it’s not like Jay Z or Kanye actually live in the godforsaken east. They live in California of course, along with everybody else famous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But clearly, Kanye does not want to attend any more parties in L.A. So, what gives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music industry is in disarray and everybody is living in the wild west regardless of previous alliances. It’s a mexican standoff between Spotify, Google Music, Pandora, Apple Music, and Tidal. Or as I like to call it, the battle of the five armies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a mess. The heavy hitters, like Kanye, hold a gun to the heads of their fans and demand lock-in to their distribution channel of choice. Or, like Taylor Swift and Adele, simply abstain from the streaming wars altogether and rake in their own profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, lesser-known artists spread themselves thin over the multitude of disparate options out there and hope that somewhere out there, some music recommendation algorithm will unwittingly promote their music because it sounds like a cross between Justin Bieber and Drake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which leaves us, the consumers, as nothing more than collateral damage as the five armies duke it out. Paying $120 a year for a streaming service is about $120 more than most people spend on buying CDs these days. But we are willing to pay it because of the incredible value proposition of having access to all the music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is no way we’re going to sign up for more than one service. Or jump ship and lose our entire libraries. Which leaves the doors wide open for piracy. It’s no wonder that Kanye’s new album is one of the most torrented albums of all time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s just address the elephant in the room. As music fans, of course we care about how much the artists get paid. But the world has moved on from buying $18 CDs. That cash cow is well and truly hamburger, and there’s no going back. We need a sustainable industry, and maybe some painful market correction, and maybe, just maybe, artistic integrity will blossom to breathe life into music once again. Cut the strings off industry puppets and all that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And those hard-working musicians who don’t wield the same clout as Taylor and Kanye know what they have to do to survive. Tour. Tour like hell for the next twenty or thirty years, pandering and nurturing and keeping their fan base alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as consumers we selfishly want it all. We want a new world order in music. One place to go for all our music. I think we’re all secretly hoping for some sort of consolidation and monopoly to unite the fractured mess of the industry. That is why we eagerly read rumours of Samsung buying Tidal and hope it’s true. Whispers of Google acquiring Spotify. Hell, yes. Apple buying, well, just about anyone they want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Services like Rdio go under, and we shrug at another casualty of the war. Because all we want is a winner. This war, after all, isn’t about us - or what is best for the consumer. So, all we can hope for is that when the dust settles, our new leader is the lesser of five evils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because that new Kanye album is really good, damn it. Just don’t ask me how I know this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;EDIT - April 8, 2016: So Kanye released his latest album on all the major streaming services, including Apple Music. So either Kanye is a chronic liar, or he&#39;s blowing in the wind like a whimsical fairy. That&#39;s the nicest way I can put it. Either way, I&#39;m happy.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The nightmares in our DNA</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/nightmares-in-our-dna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 15:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/nightmares-in-our-dna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure you are familiar with the “nature vs nurture” debate. If not, google it - I’ll wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got it? Good. For me, most explanations for human behaviour can be lumped into the “nurture” side - a bias, no doubt, fostered by my time studying anthropology at university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is something to be said for the “nature” side as well. Evolution bakes instinctual responses into the DNA of all animals, after all. Horses, for example, have an innate fear of snakes, and therefore snake-like objects. Sometimes, a horse will rear when faced with a snake-shaped stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what vestigial instincts from our hunter gatherer days linger on to colour our nightmares today? Most people assume that man has always been at the top of the food chain; but this assumption is an arrogant one, albeit unsurprising. We’ve been top dog for thousands of years now and are used to our dominion over all of God’s creatures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a different story thousands of years ago. There was an animal that evolved to be a specialist predator on humans - the Dinofelis. When mountain lions and other big cats attack a human today, the victim often survives because modern cats don’t have teeth that can pierce our skulls. The Dinofelis, however, had short, dagger-like teeth that punctured the skull with one bite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grisly forensic evidence can be found today in African caves, where skulls show the tooth holes left by this slinking predator who attacked in the dark of night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans fought back. We invented spears and other piercing weapons. We drove the Dinofelis into extinction. We won.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the nightmares remain in our ancestral memory. They are the monsters under our bed. The silent menace in the dark. Nobody has to teach a young child to be scared of large cats. I’ve seen this for myself. When I pretend to be an elephant, or even a snake or a bear, my kids laugh it off. But when I pretend to be a slinking tiger-like creature, complete with cat like movements, my kids run screaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We feel safe when have control over our environments. Perhaps our domestication of cats is an attempt to subjugate our former oppressors and desensitize our primal fears. Maybe we find cats amusing because we’ve performed the ultimate reversal and made our greatest enemy&amp;hellip;cute. Is it any accident that we invented the Internet so we could watch cat videos all day long?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I misspoke a little when I said we are top dogs on planet Earth. We are still prey to micro-organisms that we can’t defend against with traditional weapons. Disease, plagues, viruses, and other modern killers of our overpopulated world were not nearly as devastating to the small nomadic tribes in our distant past. But our homogenous and globalized societies today are especially susceptible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the next nightmare to insinuate itself into our DNA will be of large crowds where diseases spread like wildfire. Perhaps, in some post-apocalyptic future we will have reverted to roaming in small cohesive groups, using our human ingenuity and survival skills to elude the vast zombie hordes that threaten to infect us. Wait a minute, did I just describe &lt;em&gt;The Walking Dead&lt;/em&gt;? The most popular show on TV right now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems our collective nightmare has already begun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to look forward to in 2016</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/what-to-look-forward-to-in-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 14:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/what-to-look-forward-to-in-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s January and most people like to write about New Year resolutions, or predictions for the year ahead. But I’m quite tired. And no, I didn’t mean that to sound like a sardonic riff of a &lt;em&gt;Flight of the Conchords&lt;/em&gt; song. I just feel like writing something more free flowing and fun that requires less research, intense pondering or tortured introspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m going to compile a breezy list of things I’m looking forward to in 2016. Just off the top of my head. And in no particular order. Yes, the year ahead will bring weddings and babies (not mine, just to be clear), which is all very exciting of course. And I have a new job to sink my teeth into, which is very satisfying. I also want to be… better in 2016, in many ways. But forget about that for now. Let’s talk about music, tech, movies, games, books, and that sort of superficial, but fun, fluffy stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here are some random things to look forward to in 2016:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kanye West’s new album is coming out next month. Regardless of whether you harbour fierce admiration for the man, or dismiss him as a pompous twat - you can’t deny that Kanye is one heck of a reliable tastemaker.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Uncharted 4&lt;/em&gt; is coming out this April. But here’s the thing - my TV has refused to acknowledge my PS3 for the past six months, and I don’t know who broke up with who. If it’s the PlayStation that decided to move on, then perhaps a PS4 will bring back the console love. Also, PlayStation VR is coming sometime this year, and I’m definitely looking forward to trying it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice&lt;/em&gt; is coming out in March. I’m still not sure about Ben Affleck, or about Jack Snyder, or about DC’s track record in general, so this movie could most definitely disappoint. But - Superman!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to TV, I&amp;rsquo;m a 100-percent Netflix man, since I cancelled cable quite some time ago. However, I&amp;rsquo;m still partial to &lt;em&gt;Survivor&lt;/em&gt; - a show that is like your favourite uncle - always there and always dependable. I&amp;rsquo;m also a big &lt;em&gt;Walking Dead&lt;/em&gt; fan - and it looks like that show isn&amp;rsquo;t going away any time soon, although I&amp;rsquo;m sure they will run out of shocking situations to explore at some point. I&amp;rsquo;m a season behind, but I&amp;rsquo;m okay with that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Book releases are few and far between - and George Martin recently dropped the bomb that &lt;em&gt;The Winds of Winter&lt;/em&gt; will not be finished before the next season of the TV show leapfrogs the book and brings with it unprecedented spoilers for book lovers. But despite the fact that the &lt;em&gt;Song of Fire and Ice&lt;/em&gt; has become a mummer’s farce, there are at least two other releases to look forward to: Scott Lynch’s &lt;em&gt;The Thorn of Emberlain&lt;/em&gt;, and Justin Cronin’s &lt;em&gt;The City of Mirrors&lt;/em&gt;. On the whole, it’s more satisfying to just read a book series that has already been completed. Except for Brandon Sanderson’s books - that guy writes unnaturally fast, I tell you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 7 is coming out this year, and it’s a “tick” design-refresh year in the tick-tock cycle. Man, that sounds ridiculous, but that’s how people talk about the iPhone now. I just got the iPhone, so of course I won’t be upgrading any time soon. But I’m curious to see if Apple decides to ditch the home button and go with that clean all-screen look that seems like an inevitable design evolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of tech, cars are finally roaring into the 21st century - or should I say, electric cars are silently cruising into the new millennium with insane battery tech. Chevy just beat Tesla to the punch with it’s 30K Bolt that has an impressive 200-mile range. But Tesla is sure to announce the Model 3 this year, and Elon’s vision is just too compelling at this point to not be excited in any way. The magical bundle is undoubtedly a mass-market car that is both autonomous and electric. Google is making great progress and Apple’s “secret” car project is blowing too much smoke to be mere ephemeral R&amp;amp;D tinkering - an Apple car is almost certainly far into development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year hasn&amp;rsquo;t started out on the best footing. Low oil prices have decimated the Canadian economy and driven our dollar down so far that a trip to the States is an extravagant luxury. On the other hand, house prices have shot up so high that little old ladies can&amp;rsquo;t afford property tax on their two million dollar shacks. And when looking at the big picture, a recent earthquake reminded us that the big one could hit at any moment and level the West Coast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why not enjoy the little things? A good book. A good movie. A year of simple delights. That sounds quite delectable to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>