<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 21:28:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Banned for blogging about Apple</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/banned-for-blogging-about-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 21:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/banned-for-blogging-about-apple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seeing as I don’t make any money off this blog, I try to keep costs down to a minimum. And so, for the past eight years or so, I’ve had no problems using a free web host to manage my self-hosted Wordpress installation. Until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been pretty busy these days (for reasons which I’ll explain in a later post). But, wanting to post at least once a month, I navigated over to wordbit.com only to discover an ugly 403 error page instead of my home page. So, I contacted my web host support. This is what happened:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/appleban_scnsht_1.png&#34; alt=&#34;screen shot 1&#34; title=&#34;Screenshot 1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seemed pretty obvious to me by this point that the web host wanted to purge itself of all free-loaders, even if it meant making up minor infractions. But since I&amp;rsquo;d never used any of the listed forbidden words, I figured I had half a leg to stand on. I was wrong:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/appleban_scnsht_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screen shot 2&#34; title=&#34;Screenshot 2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guilty as charged - yes, I blog about Apple. And now I&amp;rsquo;d been banned for blogging about Apple. I&amp;rsquo;d say the whole debacle was asinine and petty, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t even begin to address the irony of being banned for blogging about the biggest technology giant on planet Earth. My good buddy Steven probably decided he&amp;rsquo;d had enough of subverting service requests into sales. So he checked which word appears on my blog with the highest frequency and magically turned it into a forbidden word. Even though I&amp;rsquo;ve never even come close to &amp;ldquo;abusing&amp;rdquo; the service these past few years, I was now labelled a deviant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I pulled the plug on the web host faster than you can say &amp;ldquo;Apple&amp;rdquo; and looked for a new home. I briefly considered Medium, but find their intentions for monetization hazy at best. And they only offer custom domain names by invitation. I thought seriously about moving to wordpress.com, but they have advertising now apparently. And no custom domain name, so that would mean hosting a launcher page somewhere else anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obvious and easy solution would have been to move to another free web host, but honestly, I&amp;rsquo;ve had enough. The internet at large has turned hostile toward bloggers. And I’m not just talking about the role social media has played in killing the blog. I think a lot of web hosts are setting fire to users who refuse to convert to paying customers. I also don&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with censorship ever again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this deliberation lead me to a hosting solution I&amp;rsquo;d seen a lot of software developers use - GitHub. Specifically &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub pages&lt;/a&gt;. By checking files into a repository, content management mimics software version control. Without a doubt, the most popular static site generator out there is Jeckyll. Quick primer on static site generators - Basically, they compile all blog posts into a static html webpage instead of using runtimes like PHP and a database like MySQL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eliminating database calls makes the site lightning fast on the front end with page loads being virtually non-existent. But you still have to deploy the entire site each time you add a new blog post. Apparently Jeckyll isn’t the fastest. I wanted speed on the back end too, so decided on &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, which is snappy front and back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no software geek, so it was a tough weekend for me - learning the terminal command line; running Python and Perl scripts; setting up virtual machines; figuring out how cloning, branching, committing, etc. work in GitHub; finding the perfect Hugo template; and converting my Wordpress posts to markdown. Learning to write in markdown has turned out to be simply a delight. Well done, &lt;a href=&#34;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;Gruber&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I eventually got it to work. And it&amp;rsquo;s really great. The setup I have now is exactly what I wanted - minimalist, clean, and upholding the old-school hacker ethos of the web. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to undergo a gradual cleanup effort to smooth out formatting issues resulting from the conversion from XML to markdown, and fix all image links too. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve danced this dance before over the years as my content has moved around a lot - more than I&amp;rsquo;d like. Hopefully this time I&amp;rsquo;ve found a home where I can stay for a while. One where I won&amp;rsquo;t ever be censored for, I don’t know, blogging about topics every single other person in the world blogs about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, thank you Steven. You’ve forced me to learn new things and expand my skillset. Without you, I’d still be wrangling with Wordpress and using your dodgy control panel. Thank you for the nostalgia - going back to the command line is like returning home to DOS. And thank you for giving me that aura of cool that comes to those who are crazy enough to hack together a blog on GitHub. I still have no idea what I’m doing, but I’m happier now, Steven, much happier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 Flagship 4: iPhone 6S</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/2015-flagship-4-iphone-6s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 21:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/2015-flagship-4-iphone-6s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/09/iphone6s.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;iphone6s&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I alluded to in my last post, the very definition of a &amp;ldquo;flagship&amp;rdquo; has perceptively shifted this past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, mid-range devices with high-end specs and razor-thin profit margins have exploded out of China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the definition of a flagship has skewed heavily toward &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt; phones (formerly known as phablets, but now the norm). Bigger phones tend to get better battery life and are able to fit in better camera components, such as Optical Image Stabilization (OIS). But, I most certainly do not want a big phone. For me, the sweet spot is in the 4.5 to 5-inch screen size range. For this reason, I&amp;rsquo;m excluding phones like the Note 5 and iPhone 6S Plus from my overview of the year&amp;rsquo;s best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when all is said and done, a flagship choice always comes down to that most ancient and hotly disputed divide - Android or iPhone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s latest entry in the flagship wars, the iPhone 6S, comes as no surprise. Dependably meticulous manufacturing. A two-year design cycle. And so many leaks before the official announcement that the only real surprise this year was a unique take on the &amp;ldquo;selfie flash&amp;rdquo; where the whole front screen lights up. Let&amp;rsquo;s not forget the predictably glowing reviews as well. For the upper middle-class of the developed world, the iPhone is the only choice there is. It is, for better or worse, America&amp;rsquo;s phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite Apple not playing the spec game, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look anyway for the sake of consistency:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operating system:&lt;/strong&gt; iOS 9&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.7-inch 1334 x 750 pixel IPS LCD display, 326 ppi pixel density&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Processor:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.85 Ghz 64-bit A9 SoC with M9 motion co-processor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memory:&lt;/strong&gt; 2GB RAM / 16GB, 64GB, and 128GB storage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear camera:&lt;/strong&gt; 12MP rear iSight camera, F2.2 lens, True Tone flash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front-facing camera:&lt;/strong&gt; 5MP front-facing FaceTime camera, Retina flash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battery:&lt;/strong&gt; 1715 mAh non-removable Li-ion battery&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Size:&lt;/strong&gt; 138.3 x 67.1 x 7.1mm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weight:&lt;/strong&gt; 143 grams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Objectively speaking, the advantages of the iPhone are obvious. End-to-end control allows Apple to pursue a deep integration of hardware and software. This control has allowed intriguing new features, such as &amp;ldquo;3D Touch&amp;rdquo; where the screen measures different levels of pressure to activate &amp;ldquo;right-click&amp;rdquo; types of UI popups. This control allows Apple to get away with fairly middling specs, where Android phones are overcompensating with killer specs to cover a lack of optimization. This control is also what makes the iPhone camera usually so much better than the competition. I say &amp;ldquo;usually&amp;rdquo; because this year, the other guys, especially Samsung, have seriously stepped up their game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do suspect that the Android implementation is only as good as its skin. In other words, the camera is great as long as you stay locked onto TouchWiz or Sense. We all know that manufacturer Android updates are agonizingly slow and in some cases, only supported for a year or two. Flash a custom ROM like Cyanogenmod, and you can kiss your tight hardware-software camera integration goodbye. I know this from bitter experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The disadvantages of such tight control is that it can be stifling. There is a liberating feel to Android. The possibilities are endless when it comes to true customization, both on the front end and back end. Most Android phone manufacturers also aren&amp;rsquo;t afraid to explore the bleeding edge of hardware development. After all, they just leave the bulk of software development to Google, so hardly need to expend resources on it at all. Instead we get things like NFC (Android first) and 4K screens (Android first). Apple waits a while before coming up with a carefully considered rebuttal. But they are never first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually said much about the new iPhones, mostly because I don&amp;rsquo;t have to. The reviews are in - they&amp;rsquo;re great. No surprises there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if there will be any more flagships this year, so this most likely concludes my survey of the year&amp;rsquo;s best. The new Nexus phones are being announced next week, so I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely be checking those out. But, I&amp;rsquo;m not holding my breath for anything in the flagship class. I&amp;rsquo;ve got some thinking to do, because it&amp;rsquo;s finally time to make a choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A long, dry summer</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/a-long-dry-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 22:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/a-long-dry-summer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a long, dry summer - and I&amp;rsquo;m not just talking about the weather. My series on flagship phones has been somewhat stymied by some recent changes in the industry. I was expecting some more flagships to emerge from big boys like Sony and Motorola, but instead there has been a surge of mid-range devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finding all their money was being made on the entry-level Moto G, Motorola decided to scale back on an ambitious successor to last year&amp;rsquo;s Moto X. Instead we have the Moto X Play, which is nothing more than a pumped-up version of the Moto G with mid-range specs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, after struggling to make an impact in North America, despite a worthy flagship in the Xperia series, Sony has decided to limit the release of the Xperia Z4 to it&amp;rsquo;s native Japan only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, a bunch of Chinese companies are trying to change the game by releasing cheap Android phones with impressive specs. We&amp;rsquo;ve got Asus putting out the ZenFone 2, Alcatel&amp;rsquo;s OneTouch Idol 3, Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s Redmi Note 2, and the so called &amp;ldquo;flagship killer&amp;rdquo;, the OnePlus 2. However, all these phones cut corners to get prices so low, and sometimes &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/13/9147211/android-price-wars-cost-of-cheap-smartphones&#34;&gt;the compromises aren&amp;rsquo;t worth it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what happened to the flagships? Well, it certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that Apple is taking over 90 percent of all profits in the smartphone industry. That only leaves one option - make profit on sheer volume alone. But moving as many units as possible, especially in developing markets, means putting an ever downward pressure on prices. This sounds great in theory, especially since you can&amp;rsquo;t call these new mid-range phones cheap junk. The pace of technological advancement for phones lately has been blistering. A mid-range phone in 2015 makes last year&amp;rsquo;s flagship look positively vintage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So maybe the very concept of a flagship is becoming obsolete? It&amp;rsquo;s too soon to tell. There&amp;rsquo;s no doubt that the iPhone is an overpriced luxury item, despite being a beautifully manufactured product. But with most wireless carriers doing away with contracts and subsidies, customers are only now being exposed to the true price of a smartphone. Will people stick with the quality and superior customer service that Apple represents, despite the much higher price tag, or will a better bang-for-your-buck win in the end?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year isn&amp;rsquo;t close to being over yet, so I may eat these words later&amp;hellip; but when it comes to true high-end flagships, it&amp;rsquo;s starting to look the same as in years past: a two-horse race between Apple and Samsung. And you know how I feel about Samsung.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lollipop at last</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/lollipop-at-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 23:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/lollipop-at-last/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/screenshot_2015-07-16-15-11-39.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot_2015-07-16-15-11-39&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/screenshot_2015-07-16-15-13-14.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot_2015-07-16-15-13-14&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/screenshot_2015-07-16-15-16-37.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot_2015-07-16-15-16-37&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been excited to try out Lollipop for a long time, especially after delving deep into Google&amp;rsquo;s new design language, dubbed Material Design, and even using it in my own user interface design projects. But that is precisely the problem with Android, unless you&amp;rsquo;re using a Nexus, you have to wait a long, long time before getting the latest. All told, it takes roughly one year for most Android users to catch up. So, when &amp;ldquo;Android M&amp;rdquo; was announced, I knew my time was near. Except, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t been following along (shocking, I know), I&amp;rsquo;m currently using Cyanogenmod to extend the life of my One S, which HTC wantonly threw into the obsolescence pile after &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobilesyrup.com/2013/07/02/this-is-the-end-htc-one-s-wont-get-android-4-2-update/&#34;&gt;barely a year&lt;/a&gt; of support. Wading into the murky pool of aftermarket ROMs is daunting in and of itself, but now I&amp;rsquo;ve fully come to realize how inconsistent and whimsical placing your trust into a ragtag bunch of humble volunteers truly is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And total respect to all the community developers who code these ROMs in their spare time, cause without you guys&amp;hellip; well, let&amp;rsquo;s just say that the adoption rate for the latest Android software would probably be a lot lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it seems that ever since the company split off its for-profit arm, Cyanogen OS, resources have followed the $$$ instead. I get it - this is how capitalism works. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the situation any less frustrating though. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyanogenmod promised a stable snapshot version of Lollipop within two weeks of the announcement. Several months later, the snapshot was conspicuously lacking. Then, there was a blog post declaring, with great fanfare, that the snapshot had arrived and builds were rolling out. Except, it turned out only a scant few devices were getting snapshots. Many, including the One S, were still on nightlies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, Lollipop nightlies have been available for a long time, but many of us were waiting for a more stable snapshot, as we were accustomed to getting every month on KitKat. I eventually capitulated and moved onto the nightlies. Which have been great, by the way, my worries about stability were unfounded - I should have just flashed the nightlies a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fundamental problem here is communication, plain and simple. Given that Cyanogenmod is a community effort, I&amp;rsquo;m willing to adapt to changing development cycles and go wherever the wind is blowing. But even polite queries from users about the status of the snapshots were pointedly ignored. Instead we got developer profiles and T-shirt competitions. Why not just be honest and open about where things are at? Instead of trying to draw in a wider user base that may not fall into the uber-geek category, Cyanogenmod comes off as very exclusionary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think, maybe developers just suck at PR. It&amp;rsquo;s a shame, because Cyanogenmod could be something more than a homebrew club. It could be a genuine grassroots movement - especially for the developing world that cannot afford to upgrade their phone every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t mean this to turn into a rant, but there you go. I harbour no ill feeling toward Cyanogenmod, and frankly, I&amp;rsquo;ll be moving on anyway once I upgrade my phone this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, Lollipop is better than I hoped it would be. The interface is noticeably faster and Material Design looks great, even on my AMOLED display, which tends to favour dark colours over white. Overheating issues seem to have dissipated somewhat (but it is a hot summer, so hard to tell). But what I&amp;rsquo;m most impressed with is the increase in battery life. I suspect this improvement is due to a new runtime environment, which changed from Dalvik to to ART in Lollipop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I should have been enjoying Lollipop months ago, but here we are. I&amp;rsquo;ll have a few more months to use it yet, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll be moving onto a flagship. There have been a few launched this year, but there are many more to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay frosty, my friends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of Technical Writing</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-future-of-technical-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 00:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-future-of-technical-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/sections/money/2015/05/21/408234543/will-your-job-be-done-by-a-machine&#34;&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt; that will tell you what the odds are of your job being automated in the future. The data for the estimate is derived from an academic paper where the researchers, I&amp;rsquo;m sure, are smug in the knowledge that robots will never replace university professors. Technical writers, however, will apparently not fare so well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/techwriters.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;techwriters&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then again, most technical writers seem to be the self-deprecating sort who suspect that their profession is perpetually sliding from obscurity into obsolescence anyway. Obscure, you say? Let&amp;rsquo;s not kid ourselves. Even our job title has been co-opted by the so called &amp;ldquo;tech writer&amp;rdquo;, who is actually not a technical writer at all, but a journalist who covers technology. We may casually call ourselves tech writers, but in the public parlance, tech writers are widely known as those guys who write at The Verge and Gizmodo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This cartoon neatly sums up our awkward collective identity crisis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/chickenconversation.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chickenconversation&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, we&amp;rsquo;re a humble lot - with a career that is not as &amp;ldquo;important&amp;rdquo; as being a doctor/lawyer/&lt;insert career your parents would be proud of&gt;, and certainly not as lucrative, we&amp;rsquo;re not surprised nobody has heard of us, or even knows exactly what we do. Even our employers often see technical writers as nothing more than a necessary evil in the product development process, and there isn&amp;rsquo;t any career advancement ladder to speak of. So, we just naturally assume that the demise of technical writing is inevitable. As a case in point, see Neal Kaplan&amp;rsquo;s post: &lt;a href=&#34;http://customersandcontent.com/2014/05/03/the-death-of-technical-writing-part-1/&#34;&gt;The death of technical writing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do agree with most of Neal&amp;rsquo;s points. Mobile software development will continue to erode the need for end user documentation, except for enterprise software and in highly specialized, regulated industries. And all the years of discourse focused on DITA at the expense of a proper business case was a waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the definition of a traditional technical writer is just the person who writes the user manual, then, yes, I definitely agree that technical writing is on it&amp;rsquo;s way out. But Neal said it himself - he&amp;rsquo;s not just a technical writer, he&amp;rsquo;s a content engineer, customer support agent, information architect, content strategist, web designer, and technical trainer too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps that is why we have an identity crisis - because there is no all encompassing job description that fits us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any discussion on technical writing, somebody inevitably brings up ROI - how we can demonstrate value to the company, etc. I instinctively dislike this train of thought because I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why we have to justify our existence at all. Nobody questions the value of a software developer or product manager, they just hire them to do the job. The onus should not be on us to prove how our documentation process or single sourcing or whatever is saving the company money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, no hiring manager would invite you in for an interview to pitch the case to create a technical writer position at a company. At least, I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of such a ghastly thing happening. But sometimes, once the manual is done, the project ends, and the work of a technical writer is done. Unless the company requires constant maintenance of their legacy documentation - a position that is definitely becoming rarer these days. But all the same, lean and cost-effective content management will not save you if the work has run dry - it is you that will save you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of behind-the-scenes magic that most people don&amp;rsquo;t know about. Technical writers love to mull over things like the merits of the Oxford Comma or how well their writing fairs in the Flesch–Kincaid readability index. But although grammatical consistency and readability and so on help the end user consume information more easily, such benefits are accrued with a deft but invisible hand. It is hard to translate readability into cost effectiveness, or easily convince others of the importance of a well-placed semicolon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is is hard to deny that technical writers don&amp;rsquo;t play a multi-faceted and invaluable role within an organization when we end up taking on content marketing, product management, and user interface design. When we definitively save the company money by writing SRED reports. When we put the user experience first and advocate for the user both early in the software development process, and at the project&amp;rsquo;s end with ongoing customer training and support. Technical writers who aren&amp;rsquo;t afraid to embed themselves within niche areas and apply their expertise wherever it is fitting become so much more than mere writers - yes, they defy easy definition, but they certainly aren&amp;rsquo;t let go when the manual is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the key skill that all technical writers possess can absolutely never be automated or easily dismissed: communication. I&amp;rsquo;ll be brutally honest: Communication is sorely lacking at most high-tech companies. You know that cliche of the quiet, socially inept software developer geek that is more comfortable talking to a machine than to people? Well, let&amp;rsquo;s just say that most cliches are based in reality. With our contribution to various parts of the product timeline, technical writers always have the big picture in mind, not just one line of code. A technical writer is the bridge between disparate departments; we facilitate, educate, and moderate. Here are some examples of where we can bridge communication between two parties:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.** Company → User** (end user documentation, product training)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can play a role in the reverse too: &lt;strong&gt;User → Company&lt;/strong&gt; (product support)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.** Product Management → Developer** (requirements definition)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developer → Developer&lt;/strong&gt; (API documentation - &lt;a href=&#34;http://idratherbewriting.com/2014/06/03/the-future-of-tech-comm-is-developer-doc/&#34;&gt;Tom Johnson&lt;/a&gt; believes this is where technical writing is heading)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;**Engineering → Marketing **(use cases, white papers, spec sheets, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will always be a need to good technical communicators to tailor information for a specific audience, and in doing so, bring an end to the broken telephones game that so many organizations like to play, and which often devolves into finger pointing when things go wrong due to poor communication. There will always be a need for a person who loves to soak up knowledge and learn, but remain an outsider who won&amp;rsquo;t resort to acronyms and techno-jargon when pressed for a simple and clear explanation of how something works. In these respects, I think the future for technical writing is looking bright, but at the same time, we must evolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to remain stuck in the past, clinging onto old paradigms of what a technical writer should be. After all, I&amp;rsquo;m a user too. Who wants to read the manual before using a product? I don&amp;rsquo;t. I will freely admit that if a product is unintuitive or the user interface cryptic, then the product has failed. User documentation should be a resource to solve problems encountered after using the product. It should stop the user from reaching for the telephone in anger and dialing that customer support hotline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the trend toward mobility and simplicity. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to go back to the old days. Technical writing has a place in a future where usability and great design trumps complexity. And when you boil it down to its essence, technical writing is simply about relationships between people. About understanding people and communicating appropriately. It is a very nuanced, human skill and no robot will be up to the task anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Apple dance</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-apple-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 21:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-apple-dance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, WWDC 2015 (Apple&amp;rsquo;s developer conference) showcased what&amp;rsquo;s new in OS X, iOS, and watchOS. There was also an unsurprising &amp;ldquo;one more thing&amp;rdquo; with the introduction of Apple Music. Unlike the massive redesign from&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/its-a-sunny-day-in-cupertino/&#34;&gt; last year&lt;/a&gt;, it was a pretty low-key affair, with Apple focusing on tweaking and stabilizing its evolving platforms. If there was one theme that emerged from the keynote, however, it would be this: Apple is no software company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody would argue that Apple doesn&amp;rsquo;t make beautiful products with unparalleled care and attention. And sometimes there is that magical moment that only Apple can conjure: That moment when their software and hardware work together to create a feature that would be impossible without Apple&amp;rsquo;s complete end-to-end control. There was a foreshadowing of such a thing at this year&amp;rsquo;s WWDC when Apple introduced multitasking for the iPad. But in this case the multitasking bride will have to wait for the 12-inch iPad Pro groom to walk down the aisle later this year before consummating their perfect marriage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when Apple tries to go head-to-head with every other competing software platform out there, they start to spread themselves a little thin. Sure, Apple prides itself on not being first, but being the best. Except, they can&amp;rsquo;t be the best at everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, how can you compete with Google, when their sole purpose is to use increasingly sophisticated &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/rise-of-the-google-machine/&#34;&gt;machine intelligence&lt;/a&gt; to manage and organize vast tracts of data? Apple is trying anyway by beefing up Siri&amp;rsquo;s AI with their new &amp;ldquo;proactive assistant&amp;rdquo;. So, just like Google Now does, she&amp;rsquo;ll tell you when to leave for appointments to beat the traffic, etc. (as an aside, I really have to question how accurate even this feature will be when using the infamous Apple Maps instead of the superior Google Maps). But then you have companies who are laser-focused only on parsing natural language, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.soundhound.com/hound&#34;&gt;SoundHound&lt;/a&gt;, with a speed that leaves both Apple and Google choking in their dust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get it - in a sense, Apple is trying to appeal to the lowest common denominator: if it can cover all possible services under its umbrella, most of Apple&amp;rsquo;s users will probably just use the default. Apple&amp;rsquo;s Mail app on iOS, for example, is serviceable for many - but power users will almost certainly turn to Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Outlook or Gmail. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter to Apple though because they don&amp;rsquo;t make much money off their software - their billions in revenue mostly come from the iPhone. All Apple needs to do is make the iPhone a more enticing purchase than the other guys by offering any service you could want. If they create more revenue on the side - then&amp;hellip; gravy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Apple Music streaming service takes on the exact same narrative - a purely defensive play to check another box and take on Spotify. Except, Apple has millions of dollars to buy Beats, pay off high-profile musicians (Hi Drake! I love your music - thanks to Google Play), and scale the service up almost immediately. After all, there are already millions of iPhones out there that will have Apple Music installed by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevermind the fact that Apple Music is almost useless without a web player. How else do people listen to music at work? Not on their 500MB data plans - I can tell you that much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And since I&amp;rsquo;m ranting a bit, I also have my &amp;ldquo;one more thing&amp;rdquo;: How in all seven frozen hells did Apple Pay come to the UK before Canada? This probably isn&amp;rsquo;t Apple&amp;rsquo;s fault, but seriously, WTF. Our banking infrastructure is practically tailor-made for Apple Pay, but - alas - our regulatory bodies are not. But there were rumours, man! Solid rumours!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I digress. When the dust settles after WWDC this year, precisely nobody will be blown away. Heck, some may even be slightly disgruntled, as I appear to be. But it won&amp;rsquo;t matter to Apple. Because Apple is a hardware company. Always was and always will be. Sure, they&amp;rsquo;ll talk the talk about how their software is &amp;ldquo;really great&amp;rdquo;, but they&amp;rsquo;ll do it with an amused smile on their faces because they&amp;rsquo;re just dancing around a marketing script. WWDC is a time to relax - to crack a few jokes about Californian hippie stereotypes and dance like goofball dads to some summer music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real stress will come later this year, when the weather turns cold, when the Christmas shopping season approaches, and Apple will reveal the shiny new cash cows that they hope will maintain their status as the world&amp;rsquo;s most valuable company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rise of the google machine</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/rise-of-the-google-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 23:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/rise-of-the-google-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Google I/O last week, developments in Android M (Milkshake? Macaroon?), Android Pay, Android Wear, Internet of Things, and VR all made an appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it was Google&amp;rsquo;s advancements in machine learning that were the most impressive. The awkwardly-named &amp;ldquo;Now on Tap&amp;rdquo; in Android M exemplified these improvements nicely. Basically, Google will now offer in-context information within apps, emails, or web pages when pressing and holding the home button on your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if your receive a text from your wife asking you to pick up dinner, Google will offer to create a reminder. Any mention of movie titles will display links to the movie&amp;rsquo;s trailer, reviews, and other info. Restaurant names will trigger a formatted yelp review and OpenTable reservation options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could either marvel at the progress Google is making in artificial intelligence and machine learning, or you could be terrified by it. Either way, a healthy respect for this gargantuan digital overlord is probably wise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But could respect ever blossom into trust? During Google I/O this year, it became clear that Google is courting us and wants to be the hub of our digital lives. It turns out that Google Plus was a misstep in that direction, so Google is trying again. From the detritus of its dismantled social network, comes the new Google Photos - a standalone version of the excellent photos management division of Google Plus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The singular joy of Google Plus photo management was that Google offered unlimited photo and video uploads. However, photos were downsized considerably. This time around, Google is leveraging its incredible server farm assets to upload unlimited photos in their native resolution (up to a 16MP maximum).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This extremely generous cloud storage solution, coupled with seamless synchronization between a dedicated website and apps on both Android and iOS, makes Google Photos the most compelling photo management tool available today. Heck, I signed up on launch day and am still gobsmacked by how good it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how far can you trust a company whose raison d&amp;rsquo;être is to sell targeted ads? I mean, photos are intensely personal - intimate snapshots of our family lives, even our secret lives. Are you comfortable with that relentless Google machine silently parsing every picture you hand it? Because that is exactly what is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google positioned its machine learning as a positive feature, and at face value it is amazing: Search for any term, such as &amp;ldquo;flowers&amp;rdquo; for example, and Google will show you all the flower pictures you&amp;rsquo;ve taken (even though you&amp;rsquo;ve never tagged them). Type in &amp;ldquo;flowers in San Diego&amp;rdquo; and Google will check geo-location data to only show you pictures of flowers you took on that trip to San Diego a few years ago. Crazy cool, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is trying to build trust here, so there is no advertising in Google Photos&amp;hellip;yet. Targeted ads based on your photo collection does not seem far-fetched, however. In fact, it seems inevitable, especially once millions of users have invested the time and energy to curate their memories through Google&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo; service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I okay with this? Well, for the most part, I am. You&amp;rsquo;d be crazy to throw all your eggs into Google&amp;rsquo;s basket though. I am definitely keeping my photos stored locally as well. And it&amp;rsquo;s not as if I haven&amp;rsquo;t made forays into photo cloud storage. I tried Flickr&amp;rsquo;s redesigned photo service (offering a healthy 1 terabyte), but it&amp;rsquo;s just not as good. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even read Yahoo&amp;rsquo;s small print, which is probably horrifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason I&amp;rsquo;m okay with all of this is that I just don&amp;rsquo;t care if a machine is looking at my pictures. It would be different if, you know - an actual person - was ogling at my candid selfies. I&amp;rsquo;m sure a lot of people feel the same way. And so millions of us will feed data into the machine. That machine will only get smarter and smarter. So, what happens when that machine knows us better than we know ourselves? An interesting question, but I&amp;rsquo;m having too much fun organizing my pictures to think too much about it right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet snark that just won&#39;t die</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/internet-snark-that-just-wont-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 23:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/internet-snark-that-just-wont-die/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Humour has long been a staple of the Internet - in fact, you probably have some favourite delicious sites, such as the Onion or the Oatmeal, that you regularly check on for a fresh serving of laughs. But then there are those single-serving static sites that have been hosting the same joke for years and years and seem impervious to non-renewal. I wonder who keeps paying for these internet one-liners? They had their day in the sun years ago, but now languish in relative obscurity as faded internet legend. Here are three such sites that refuse to die (and a recent one that should have died weeks ago, but didn&amp;rsquo;t).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zombo.com&#34;&gt;Zombo.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This parody of flash animation was created in 1999 and still manages to epitomize the weirdness of the internet in a way that no other site can. According to who you talk to, Zombo.com is either the best or most useless website in the world. Now that Flash is quickly becoming obsolete as HTML5 takes over, it will be interesting to see if future generations will find Zombo amusing at all, or just scratch their heads at the anachronistic humour of the 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://welcometointernet.org&#34;&gt;Welcometotheinternet.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now a sarcastic insult to mock those who don&amp;rsquo;t know how internet culture works, this phrase was first uttered by Homer Simpson in a 1998 episode. Not particularly funny anymore, sites like this are fading away from our collective memory - but aren&amp;rsquo;t in the grave yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lmgtfy.com&#34;&gt;lmgtfy.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let me Google that for you&amp;rdquo; is a 2008 site designed as a snarky response to questions asked online that can easily be answered by googling the answer. Although this site has been banned on some websites, the gentlemanly thing to do would be to put it to bed now that the meme is long past it&amp;rsquo;s prime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honourable mention: &lt;a href=&#34;http://Havidol.com&#34;&gt;Havidol.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first came across this satirical site &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/new-miracle-drug/&#34;&gt;back in 2007&lt;/a&gt;, but I was surprised to find that it&amp;rsquo;s still around. This parody campaign for a fictional medication actually fooled a number of people into thinking they had this disorder. I&amp;rsquo;m actually glad this site is still up because the concept is far cleverer than some of these other examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, I mentioned an internet gag that should have died weeks ago? Remember that mysterious button in &lt;em&gt;Lost&lt;/em&gt; that had to be pushed every 108 minutes or the world would end?  Reddit&amp;rsquo;s April Fool&amp;rsquo;s joke this year was to host a button with a sixty-second counter. Every Reddit user only has one click to reset the button to 60. Once the button counts down to zero&amp;hellip;nobody know what will happen. Because it hasn&amp;rsquo;t happened yet. Yes, people are still clicking &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/thebutton&#34;&gt;the button&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must admit, I am curious, but am also a bit disturbed. This joke reminds me a lot of the cow-clicking game in &lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.wired.com/magazine/2011/12/ff_cowclicker/all/&#34;&gt;this Wired article&lt;/a&gt; - a game that was supposed to be a &lt;em&gt;Farmville&lt;/em&gt; satire, but ended up being a legitimate phenomenon in itself, much to the befuddlement of the developer. Still, there is an allure to such a long-running gag. I&amp;rsquo;ll be sure to update this post once if the button ever reaches zero.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 Flagship 3: LG G4</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/1271/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 20:40:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/1271/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/05/lg-g4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;LG G4&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the blossoming South Korean GDP, whether Samsung or LG triumphs is a moot point. But nonetheless, there is a cute national rivalry between these two Korean companies in their efforts to one-up each other. And it has served them well. When looking at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gartner.com/newsroom/id/2996817&#34;&gt;2014 sales&lt;/a&gt;, Samsung is currently the top smartphone manufacturer in the world, and LG is in a respectable fifth place. If Samsung is the aggressive older brother, then LG comes off as the clean-cut, conservative younger brother who is extremely capable, but somewhat boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start by taking a look at the spec sheet of the LG G4:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operating system:&lt;/strong&gt; Android 5.1 Lollipop&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.5-inch Quad HD IPS Quantum Display (2560 x 1440, 538ppi)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Processor:&lt;/strong&gt; Qualcomm Snapdragon 808&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memory:&lt;/strong&gt; 3GB LPDDR3 RAM / 32GB eMMC ROM, microSD card up to 2TB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear camera:&lt;/strong&gt; 16MP with F1.8 aperture / OIS 2.0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front-facing camera:&lt;/strong&gt; 8MP with f/2.0 aperture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battery:&lt;/strong&gt; 3,000 mAh removable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Size:&lt;/strong&gt; 148.9 x 76.1 x 6.3-9.8 mm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weight:&lt;/strong&gt; 155 grams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In keeping with LG&amp;rsquo;s conservatism, the LG G4 breaks no new ground here. While Samsung and Apple have both opted for non-removable storage and batteries in the name of design, LG has kept the removable back with a user-replaceable battery and SD card. Personally, I&amp;rsquo;d expect enough battery power and storage capabilities in a 2015 flagship, that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to constantly swap out these components. Tinkering with hardware is a bother and takes away from a seamless user experience. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are Android diehards out there who will appreciate LG&amp;rsquo;s stubborn adherence to the old ways, but I&amp;rsquo;m not one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really a fan of how this phone looks either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a big, ugly phone. The removable back options range from dimpled plastic to a faux stitched-leather that just reminds me of the horrible skeuomorphic Corinthian leather in Apple&amp;rsquo;s old notes and calendar apps. It also reminds me of business-type accessories, such as handbags and leather briefcases, neither of which appeal to my aesthetic sensibilities. In addition, the placement of the volume keys on the back just seems odd and unintuitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said that, it feels a bit incongruous to pick on the design because, in all other respects, this seems like a rock-solid phone. By all accounts, the slightly-curved screen is bright and has superb colour accuracy. The camera is right up there with the other big boys - maybe not the best out there, but close enough. The Snapdragon 808, while not as fast as the 810, appears to be more than adequate in maintaining a smooth user experience. Unsurprisingly, LG&amp;rsquo;s software skin continues to be all sorts of ugly, but that is easily fixed with a launcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I respect LG. I&amp;rsquo;ve never had a problem with LG phones in the past, and let&amp;rsquo;s give praise where it&amp;rsquo;s due: the Nexus 5 is just a perfect combination of price and feature sets. But do I feel an emotional tug toward their products? Not really. They may have won my mind, but not my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of storytelling in games</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-evolution-of-storytelling-in-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 00:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-evolution-of-storytelling-in-games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tens of thousands of years ago, humans would gather around the fire at night and share stories. We craved narratives to explain our world. And in the crackling fires of the darkest nights, myth and legend was born. As the oral tradition was displaced by the written word, our appetite for storytelling only increased. For thousands of years, from the Bible to Shakespeare - we&amp;rsquo;ve clung especially tight to those narratives that define the very essence of humanity, through courage, conflict, betrayal, and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relatively recent medium of film (which is only about 130 years old) has spawned a multi-billion dollar industry whose sole purpose is to entertain, delight - and even challenge us - through storytelling. Recent technological advancements have allowed the moviemakers of the 21st century to transport us to fictional worlds and depict fantastical creatures that are completely believable. But, without a good story, even the best special effects won&amp;rsquo;t save a terrible plot. See exhibit A: the &lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;/em&gt; franchise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history of storytelling in games is an even shorter one. As a kid, my brother and I spent hours shooting extraterrestrials in &lt;em&gt;Space Invaders&lt;/em&gt;. But we never did find out why those aliens were so intent on destroying planet Earth. Fast forward thirty years later to the alien invasion in &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/em&gt;, and it&amp;rsquo;s a whole different story (sorry).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 1990s brought us so many amazing story-driven adventure games from publishers such as &lt;em&gt;Sierra&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Lucasarts&lt;/em&gt;. Man, I loved those games. As a kid who grew up devouring books, adventure games were a natural extension of the &lt;em&gt;Choose Your Own Adventure&lt;/em&gt; style of interactivity that allowed you to actually be in the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, it all fell apart. There came a terrible dry spell for a decade or so where first-person shooter after first-person shooter was threatening to sink the industry into a mire of prepubescent bloodlust devoid of any plausible exposition whatsoever. But, I think we&amp;rsquo;re mostly over that now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there is still a lot of shooting going on in games today. Some games, such as the &lt;em&gt;Uncharted&lt;/em&gt; series, pull it off by throwing you into ridiculous action-movie style set pieces that you can&amp;rsquo;t help but love. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a guy thing, like enjoying the &lt;em&gt;Fast and Furious&lt;/em&gt; movies. Other shooting games - I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you _Call of Duty - _just come off as recruiting tools for the US army.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, I&amp;rsquo;m extremely encouraged by the recent wave of indie games that are trying to push storytelling in games into different directions. In &lt;em&gt;Papo and Yo&lt;/em&gt;, an alcoholic father forces a young Brazilian boy to cower in the closet, where he retreats into a dream-like world and eventually finds catharsis. &lt;em&gt;Gone Home&lt;/em&gt; tells its story through contextual exploration, where you read notes and letters while rifling through the belongings of an absentee family. There are no guns in sight. Even more commercial games, such as &lt;em&gt;The Walking Dead&lt;/em&gt;, are welcome revivals of the adventure genre, and explore relationships in parallel with the splitting open of zombie heads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of relationships, I&amp;rsquo;m playing &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age II&lt;/em&gt; right now. Bioware is well-known for compelling RPGs with great storytelling and even characters you can pursue romances with. &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age II&lt;/em&gt; was criticized for a weak plot, and I can definitely see why. Although the meticulous attention to world-building is there, the lack of a narrative thread leaves the game feeling listless. In response, Bioware made sure the writing in &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age: Inquisition&lt;/em&gt; was top-notch (or so I hear - it&amp;rsquo;ll be while before I get around to playing it, I&amp;rsquo;m sure). The point is, the story is no longer an afterthought in gaming these days. People really care about good writing. In fact, it can make or break a game, regardless of how good the graphics are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As games continues to evolve, it seems obvious that storytelling will surge into the forefront of bleeding-edge game design. In retrospect, we can see how faster graphics processing allowed game designers to move from linear-track shooters to creating massive open worlds. I believe the same will happen with storytelling, where advances in Artificial Intelligence (AI) will allow a deep and profound interaction with non-player characters (NPCs). Gamers will be able to influence and engage in the complex moving parts of plot and character development in unimaginable ways. A truly idiosyncratic gaming experience will become possible, where no two playthroughs could ever be alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you think five possible endings sounds impressive? How about thousands of variations. Tens of thousands. Millions. How about an infinite number of parallel universes for you to explore in your own virtual reality. Games won&amp;rsquo;t be &amp;ldquo;games&amp;rdquo; anymore, they&amp;rsquo;ll be alternative realities, every bit as real as this reality. NPCs will be indistinguishable from your friends. Heck, they&amp;rsquo;ll probably be your only friends. At that point, that great human accomplishment - the ability to tell a good story, will be eclipsed by the ability of the machine to tell an infinite variation of stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this never happens though. I&amp;rsquo;d like to think we can step back from that inevitable abyss and appreciate the art of the story, which is really a celebration of our imagination. Sometimes too much choice overwhelms us. What we really want is to just relax in front of the fire and listen to a story being told.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, I have a confession. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m confronted with a terrible in-game choice, it paralyzes me. Do I save Carley or Doug from the zombie attack? Do I upload the Reaper code to the Geth collective? Do I kill that little boy, Connor, because he is possessed by a demon? In the end, I always check out both alternatives. And I&amp;rsquo;m always relieved to find out that neither choice really changes the main plot. It was all smoke and mirrors - the illusion of choice. The story goes on as it was meant to, guided by the storyteller&amp;rsquo;s deft hand. That, in the end, is as comforting as the crackle and hiss of that flickering fire, keeping the terrible unknowns of the night at bay.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 Flagship 2: Samsung Galaxy S6</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/2015-flagship-2-samsung-galaxy-s6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 17:52:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/2015-flagship-2-samsung-galaxy-s6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/samsung_galaxy_s6.png&#34; alt=&#34;samsung_galaxy_s6&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the Galaxy S6, it was easy to hate Samsung. Their slimy plastic phones looked cheap and Touchwiz was a bloated mess. Not only that, but their entire business plan seemed to revolve around blatantly ripping off Apple. So much so that they were originally fined a billion in damages in that infamous 2012 lawsuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But man, have they stepped up their design game this year. The S6 eschews plastic in favour of shiny glass and metal. Not that they haven&amp;rsquo;t stopped poaching Apple&amp;rsquo;s best ideas. At certain angles, the S6 takes great gulping gobs of inspiration from the iPhone 6 - most notably in the bottom styling of the speaker grills and ports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The S6 Edge - a pricier variant of the S6 with a curved display - presents a rather head-scratching design decision, though. Why not commit to one flagship model? Design is about making choices and committing to one carefully considered culmination of those choices, not copping out by putting the burden (and confusion) of choice on the consumer. But still, the Edge is a stunner, although it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to offer any functional advantage over the S6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with most Android phones, Samsung went with some heavy-hitting specs to brute force a smooth experience for the user. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Android 5.0.2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;5.1-inch 2560 x 1440 pixel Super AMOLED display&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Exynos 14nm 64-bit Octa Core&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;3GB DDR4 RAM / 32-128GB internal storage&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;16MP rear Sony IMX240 sensor w/ F1.9 lens, Optical Image Stabilization&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;5MP front camera&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;UHD 4K @ 30fps, 1080p @ 60fps, 720p @ 120fps video capture&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;2,550mAh non-removable battery&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;143.4 x 70.5 x 6.8mm&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;138 grams&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s that incredible eight cores of CPU power again - this time from Samsung&amp;rsquo;s own Exynos processor. And with a 577 PPI, that screen makes the iPhone&amp;rsquo;s 326 PPI look a bit dated - on paper at least. But specs aren&amp;rsquo;t everything, as I&amp;rsquo;ve hammered home recently, so I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t let the numbers romance me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do the reviews say? Well, most praise the new design and that gorgeous screen. The camera seems to be really good - perhaps the best out of all Android phones and on par with the iPhone 6, sometimes even surpassing it. HTC should be very worried right now. Battery life sounds adequate, but not amazing. And the offensive bits of Touchwiz seem to have been toned down - but this is a small consideration considering you can just install whatever launcher you want on Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, this phone is a real contender for the coveted title of &amp;ldquo;my next&amp;rdquo;. It remains to be seen how well this phone holds up over the next eight months, though. When it comes to future proofing, there are a few things to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With USB Type-C set to become the new standard, it would be nice to have it on my phone. Also, I want to stick with Wind, my current carrier, and they&amp;rsquo;ve just gotten hold of some juicy 30Mhz spectrum in a recent auction. Unfortunately, LTE is probably a way off and phones that support the AWS-3 band probably won&amp;rsquo;t arrive until next year. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I can wait that long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to leave emotion and brand loyalty out of rational decision-making, even though that is easier said than done. But I have to admit it - the S6 has definitely challenged my instinctual hatred of all things Samsung.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 Flagship 1: HTC One M9</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/2015-flagship-1-htc-one-m9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 17:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/2015-flagship-1-htc-one-m9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/03/htc_one_m9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;htc_one_m9&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HTC One M9 is the first flagship of 2015, and it&amp;rsquo;s a beauty. By retaining the same curved aluminum shell and two front-facing speakers as last year&amp;rsquo;s M8, HTC is making a bold statement: We don&amp;rsquo;t need to improve on an already impeccable design. And for the most part, they&amp;rsquo;re right - if going on looks alone, there&amp;rsquo;s no doubt that this is a premium phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internals, however, have been upgraded with the following specs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Android 5.0.2 w/ Sense 7.0&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;5-inch 1920×1080 pixel SuperLCD 3 panel, 441 pixels per inch&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Qualcomm Snapdragon 810 SoC, 64-bit, octa core&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;3GB RAM / 32GB internal storage (expandable via microSD)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;20.7MP rear camera sensor, F2.2 lens&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;4MP front-facing UltraPixel sensor, F2.0 fixed-focus lens&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;4K UHD video capture, 2160p @ 30fps, 1080p @ 60fps, 720p @ 120fps&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;2,840mAh non-removable battery, Fast Charge support&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;144.6 x 69.7 x 9.6mm&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;157 grams&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reviews are saying that this phone screams - and it should; Eight cores, good god, that&amp;rsquo;s more processing power than my quad-core iMac. I knew the day would come when smartphones out-spec my computer, but it still blows my mind. There were reports of the Snapdragon 810 overheating when running certain benchmarks, but it looks like they fixed that with a software update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a decent battery life and a gorgeous screen, this phone seems like a solid contender for my hard-earned dollars. Except, that it isn&amp;rsquo;t. The camera. Oh HTC, you messed up the camera again. Here is a sampling from various reviews:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engadget:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Main camera is lackluster&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PhoneArena:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Details are emphasized more with this new camera, but low lighting performance is just laughable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GSMarena:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;20MP main camera produces first-rate images with a wide dynamic range, accurate colors and correct exposure, although on the noisy side&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Android Authority:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;While you’d expect the move to a higher megapixel count to equate to a much better experience than found in the M8, we are sad to say this isn’t the case&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Android Central:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you want to have the best smartphone, you have to have solid hardware, software and camera quality. HTC’s still struggling some with the latter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Techno Buffalo:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The good news is that the M9 captures photos very quickly, letting you capture fast-moving action without missing a beat. HTC’s cameras have always been fast, and you’ll continue to get that same instant experience here. Using modes like HDR and Bokeh will add processing time, but otherwise you should expect to capture a rambunctious child without issue.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If only the images themselves were any good. This is easily the most disappointing part of the M9, continuing a kind of problematic trend that started with the M7.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Verge:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Smartphones aren’t just phones anymore, they are increasingly the only cameras that people own or use. People often pick a phone based solely on how well it takes pictures and the phone’s camera can make or break the device. In the case of the M9 (and the M8 before it), it breaks it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Syrup:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The M9 can, and does, take some great photos, but it’s not quite at the point where I can point at a subject on Auto mode and reliably obtain a great result.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people simply won&amp;rsquo;t care about a bad camera, and so the M9 may be the perfect phone for them. But I&amp;rsquo;m hoping for a great camera than can capture pictures of fast-moving kids and for impromptu shots while out and about. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to fiddle with manual settings, because by the time I&amp;rsquo;ve set it up, then the moment will have gone. In 2015, I absolutely expect a really great convergence device that will replace my point-and-shoot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love HTC&amp;rsquo;s design - I really appreciate the design of my HTC One S: sleek, rounded corners, and an aluminum shell treated with a process called microarc oxidation, leaving it as hard as ceramic. The M9 has a similarly amazing design and with Lollipop and Sense 7, a seemingly great user experience. But such a serious stumble on image quality can&amp;rsquo;t be forgiven. Unfortunately, it looks like my next phone won&amp;rsquo;t be another HTC phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next flagship I&amp;rsquo;ll be considering will be the Samsung Galaxy S6. Coming in the next month or so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The time war</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-time-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 18:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-time-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everybody wants your attention. There&amp;rsquo;s an invisible war raging out there and it&amp;rsquo;s all about where you are focusing your engagement. The victor of this war gets the spoils - your precious time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest player in the battle for your eyeballs is the Apple Watch. At an event on Monday, Apple revealed more details about the smartwatch (along with an obscenely thin MacBook).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reactions to the Apple Watch event were mixed, as to be expected. However, I&amp;rsquo;m sure Apple has nothing to worry about. Similar reactions followed the announcement of the iPad, and look how that story went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the questions being raised is who would actually buy the Apple Watch Edition (which costs up to $22000 Canadian). Given the yearly obsolescence cycle of gadgets, this seems like a valid question. After all, where a luxury mechanical watch is an heirloom, the ostentatious solid-gold Apple Watch comes off as a toy for rich douchebags. Still, there&amp;rsquo;s no mystery over who will buy a short-lived gold watch - status symbols and conspicuous consumption are embedded into the culture of the nouveau riche, especially in places like China or Dubai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The compelling subtext here is Apple&amp;rsquo;s utter braggadocio in peddling Veblen goods to the one percent - surely a signal to the world that the company is now the reigning King and no longer the underdog of yesteryears. But I digress - back to the time war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Apple Watch, or indeed any smartwatch, is another contender for your attention. But how useful is it really? &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/thoughts-on-the-apple-watch/&#34;&gt;My earlier thoughts&lt;/a&gt; on the Apple Watch still hold true. I&amp;rsquo;d like to expand on the idea of attention a little bit more though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any given moment of the day, you are attending to something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s break it down. You wake up. You have a shower, eat breakfast, and brush your teeth all while struggling to get the kids ready to go to daycare. Do you really want to be bothered with twitter notifications while you&amp;rsquo;re already overwhelmed with multitasking and trying to rush out the door? You jump in your car for the daily commute. Is it safe for you to catch up on your emails while you&amp;rsquo;re driving and attending to the road? I know these are all slightly silly rhetorical questions, but bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most, the vast majority of the day is taken up by your particular employment. For me, and I suspect for many of you, my eight working hours are spent staring at a computer screen. My dominant attention is on the screen, so shouldn&amp;rsquo;t my notifications appear there too - as a seamless integration into my workflow?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, with OS X Yosemite, Apple recently introduced this exact synchronicity between your iPhone and Mac. Notifications, texts, and even phone calls will appear on your computer screen and allow you to leave the phone alone. For PC users, the wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pushbullet.com/&#34;&gt;Pushbullet&lt;/a&gt; provides similar functionality (and is in fact cross-platform). When your eyes never have to leave your screen, you remain in context and notifications feel like less of a distraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I&amp;rsquo;m getting notifications on my computer screen, do I want duplicate notifications to pop up on my watch? No, of course not. It&amp;rsquo;s one or the other. One of the major selling points of the Apple watch has just been rendered moot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But perhaps in other contexts, the Apple Watch could work. If your hands are dirty then a smartwatch would be great, like say if you&amp;rsquo;re digging up weeds or working on a construction site and you want to see who is calling you. Too bad Apple isn&amp;rsquo;t marketing their watch to blue collar workers though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, Apple is targeting the ultra-rich and maybe white collar workers on the low end. The examples of usage Apple gave at their event were so ridiculously idiosyncratic, they won&amp;rsquo;t appeal to many outside Silicon Valley. Using your watch to call an Uber car, for example. Really? Who actually does that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our age of sensory overload, we&amp;rsquo;re trying to find ways to focus more and multitask less. Our time is a finite resource best spent doing the things we love. If any smartwatch is going to succeed, it needs to help us manage our lives more efficiently, not introduce more chaos and noise. The current generation of smartwatches may help a select few, but for most of us, they&amp;rsquo;d probably do more harm than good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTC One S vs iPhone 6</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/htc-one-s-vs-iphone-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 00:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/htc-one-s-vs-iphone-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of this year, I&amp;rsquo;ll finally be upgrading to a new phone. After three years with the HTC One S, I&amp;rsquo;ve realized that&amp;hellip; three years is a long time. So, I&amp;rsquo;ll be skipping the entry-level and mid-tier phones and just shell out for a flagship. For a device you use everyday, it&amp;rsquo;s worth getting the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be blogging about all the flagship contenders that come out this year in a series of blog posts, then decide on the winner by December. In the meantime, here&amp;rsquo;s a fun comparison between my three-year old mid-tier phone and the latest iPhone. The results are actually quite surprising:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/03/table.png&#34; alt=&#34;table&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I&amp;rsquo;ll freely admit that I&amp;rsquo;ve cherry picked the specs listed here, but most of these are essential hardware requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is obvious that the latest iPhone has a far better screen and a bigger battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the HTC One S and the iPhone 6 are actually on par in a few areas: The same 3G network speed (I&amp;rsquo;m not bringing LTE into this) and the same RAM. Both have an eight-megapixel camera. Both record 1080p video. All the standard smartphone stuff like GPS and Bluetooth is all on equal ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait a minute. My HTC One S actually has a faster CPU&amp;hellip;sure, it&amp;rsquo;s only 0.1 GHz faster, but still, for a three-year old mid-tier device, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty amazing. Not only that, but the One S is lighter, and has extras such as the FM Radio and ability to use Flash in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even design-wise, both these phones have sleek curved lines that make for a pleasant tactile experience - but the One S came first. So, on paper at least, the HTC One S seems to hold its own against what is ostensibly the best smartphone in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If only that were true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My HTC One S has become slow and lags in a number of areas. Heck, even the ringtone stutters and crackles when the phone rings. The undeniable truth is that specs don&amp;rsquo;t matter. By integrating both the hardware and software, Apple can focus on the user experience from the ground up and is utterly aloof from the spec war. Android phones must have killer specs because only overkill will guarantee a great user experience - like hitting a nail with Mjölnir. By flashing a custom ROM onto my phone, I&amp;rsquo;ve further divorced the software from the hardware. The camera, in particular, has gone from not-bad to atrocious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow me to emphasize: I&amp;rsquo;m no fanboy of either Android or Apple and am a user of both platforms. Each have their merits and drawbacks. And I don&amp;rsquo;t regret going the custom ROM route. But in the year to come, when I&amp;rsquo;m taking a cold, hard look at the flagships - I&amp;rsquo;m not going to take the specs that seriously. A 20MP camera is useless without proper image processing. More RAM is useless if it drains the battery. When you design a phone, there are many tough choices to be made, but if you&amp;rsquo;re not putting the user experience first, then you&amp;rsquo;re making the wrong ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driverless cars in Sci-Fi movies</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/driverless-cars-in-sci-fi-movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 00:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/driverless-cars-in-sci-fi-movies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cars are so integral to American culture, that it&amp;rsquo;s no surprise they often appear in Hollywood movies about the future. But with self-driving cars rapidly gaining traction (sorry) in the public imagination, we are getting a better idea of what a realistic future of autonomous vehicles may look like. So, the question is, which science fiction movies got it right, and who got it wrong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we can answer this question, we need to establish a few things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we need to determine a plausible future date where the majority of vehicles on the road will be autonomous. Navigant, a market research think tank, has studied the emerging technology of self-driving cars and has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.navigantresearch.com/newsroom/three-quarters-of-vehicles-sold-in-2035-are-expected-to-have-autonomous-capability&#34;&gt;concluded&lt;/a&gt; that by 2035, at least 75 percent of all cars sold will be autonomous. So, let&amp;rsquo;s go with that general time frame as the future date when self-driving cars are more or less mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, we will be focusing exclusively on American science fiction movies, so any depictions of self-driving cars in other genres or mediums is out. So, no &lt;em&gt;Christine&lt;/em&gt;, arguably the most terrifying depiction of a driverless car. And no Benny the Cab from &lt;em&gt;Who Framed Roger Rabbit&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;Herby_  - even if they are pretty cute sentient cars. And, although Kitt from _Knight Rider&lt;/em&gt; is actually a pretty realistic autonomous vehicle, he appears on television. But Kitt is still awesome, even if the 80s are long gone, so it would be remiss not to mention him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, the science fiction movie in question should sincerely attempt to depict our future society, although there is room for some artistic license of course. The movie is usually set in a specific year, so that will be taken into account when comparing the depicted year with our proposed 2035 date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, are you ready? Read the answer to who got it wrong and who got it right, after the break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who got it wrong:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the movies that didn&amp;rsquo;t quite hit the mark (in chronological order).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timecop (set in 2004)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/02/timecop.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Timecop&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The voice-controlled driverless cars in Timecop not only look hideous but arrived too early in our timeline. We didn&amp;rsquo;t even have the iPhone in 2004.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interstellar (set in 2034)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/02/interstellar.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;interstellar&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so 2034 is one year shy of our 2035 date. But, still. I find it hard to believe the amazing aerospace tech shown in the movie, as well as the tech in autonomous drones, and fully-fledged AI robots didn&amp;rsquo;t filter down to the auto industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gattaca (set in the mid to late 21st century)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/02/gattaca.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;gattaca&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cars that Uma Thurman and Ethan Hawke drive are definitely stylish, but come off as decidedly old school. In a society dedicated to creating perfect humans through genetic engineering, you&amp;rsquo;d think they would also pimp their rides too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Recall (set in 2084)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/02/total_recall.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;total_recall&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total Recall did predict driverless cars, so no problem there. But the creepy android taxi driver is just comical (which suits the tone of the movie, I guess). But seriously, everybody knows skeuomorphism is so 2007.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Judge Dredd (set in 2139)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/02/judge_dredd.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;judge_dredd&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 124 years in the future and not only do people still drive themselves around but a futuristic douchebag gets busted for DUI - an unlikely occurrence in a future where the designated driver should be an anachronism. So unrealistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who got it right:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the movies that nailed it, also in chronological order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Demolition Man (set in 2032)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/02/demolitionman.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DemolitionMan&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years shy of 2035, but Sandra Bullock demonstrates an extremely believable scenario when she takes a video chat in her autonomous police car, complete with a Siri-like voice assistant. Cheesy movie, but the car tech is spot on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I, Robot (set in 2035)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/02/irobot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;iRobot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The futuristic Audi that Will Smith drives in &lt;em&gt;I, Robot&lt;/em&gt; is simply badass. This autonomous car actually feels quite familiar and is entirely believable. And look at the year when this movie is set - 2035! Bang on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minority Report (set in 2054)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/02/minority_report.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;minority_report&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The driverless cars in this awesome movie are super high-tech and even deliver you straight to your condo window by driving up the side of the building. Perhaps a little ambitious for only 39 years from now, but probably the coolest depiction of autonomous vehicles in any sci-fi movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logan&amp;rsquo;s Run (set in 2274)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wordbitarchives.files.wordpress.com/2015/02/logansrun.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;logansrun&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to give props to a movie that came out in 1976 but accurately predicted the advent of the autonomous vehicle. And that design has definitely stood the test of time, although maybe doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the best crash-test ratings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These movies offer an intriguing glimpse into the possible future of autonomous vehicles. If I was to announce a winner, however, I&amp;rsquo;d probably go with _I, Robot - _for believability and for fitting perfectly in the proposed timeframe. One thing is for sure, if I make it to 2035, I&amp;rsquo;ll be looking back on this blog post and writing a follow-up post to discuss what actually panned out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>