<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wordbit</title>
    <link>http://wordbit.com/categories/reading/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://wordbit.com/categories/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A veritable article fest</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/a-veritable-article-fest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 03:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/a-veritable-article-fest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year has been busy and exciting and just plain exhausting. But I&amp;rsquo;ve finally found some time to upload a bunch of the articles that I&amp;rsquo;ve had published this year for &lt;em&gt;alive&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;blush&lt;/em&gt; magazines. The majority focus on green issues. I&amp;rsquo;ve been somewhat typecast as the devil&amp;rsquo;s green advocate, being asked to find flaws in all manner of righteous green concepts. To read one, click on the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/scans/blush2.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/blush0002.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baby&amp;rsquo;s nontoxic nursery: Preparing a healthy space for your newborn. What paints should you choose when decorating baby&amp;rsquo;s new room? Surrounding your new child with noxious fumes is the last thing you want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/scans/Sept09.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/sep090001.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lawn warfare: Pesticide and herbicide use in Canada. I interviewed the PR person from the David Suzuki Foundation as well as a professor of biomolecular chemistry to write this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/scans/August09.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/august090002.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get in the habit: 10 easy ways to shrink your carbon footprint. This one is self explanatory. But did you know the concept for a carbon footprint was derived from those newfangled desktops in the early 90s that stood upright instead of lying flat?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/scans/July09.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/july090005.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In it for the money: Green initiatives that are good for our &lt;strike&gt;ecology&lt;/strike&gt; economy. This is one of those slightly cynical pieces. The intro comes from a really funny ad for IBM that you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VSNFE6eUjfY&#34;&gt;watch here on Youtube&lt;/a&gt;. The art department did an awesome job with this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/scans/March09.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/march090002.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The eco dilemma: Why electric cars won&amp;rsquo;t save the world. Once again, an alternative look at a green &lt;em&gt;deus ex machina&lt;/em&gt; (a term, incidentally, that I had originally used in the intro - but my editor wisely replaced this rather academic term with &amp;ldquo;save the day&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/scans/April09.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/April090001.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selenium and cancer: Good news and bad. A short piece on the links between cancer and an antioxidant called selenium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/scans/09shorts.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/march090001.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two very short pieces: Cleaning our lakes - about a government restriction of phosphates, and When TVs die - about the switchover from analog to digital and the potential aftermath of discarded TVs in our landfills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free eBooks for Valentines</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/free-ebooks-for-valentines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 06:23:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/free-ebooks-for-valentines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/boxshot.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I had more time to blog this month, but alas, you can look forward to a paucity of blog posts. Even my tweets are running dry. So, in the meantime, what better way to get your reading fix than to indulge in some licentious drivel. To celebrate 60 years of &amp;ldquo;pure reading pleasure&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://harlequincelebrates.com/&#34;&gt;Harlequin is offering 16 free eBooks for download&lt;/a&gt; in various formats including PDF, ePub, eReader, and MS Reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you&amp;rsquo;re not into this genre, and admittedly, I&amp;rsquo;m hardly the target audience either - do you know how lucrative this market actually is? A few years ago, I got a book called &amp;ldquo;The Art of Romance Writing&amp;rdquo; as a gag gift, but am now seriously thinking of writing a racy novel and retiring on the inevitable movie deal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surf&#39;s up - and so is your heart rate</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/surfs-up-and-so-is-your-heart-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 05:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/surfs-up-and-so-is-your-heart-rate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/surfing194.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s probably the cheesiest line I&amp;rsquo;ve ever written. But for some reason, the editors over at &lt;em&gt;alive&lt;/em&gt; actually seem to revel in cheese (One example is the title I&amp;rsquo;ll eternally shake my head at: &lt;em&gt;G&amp;hellip;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s a Glycemic index&lt;/em&gt;). God bless &amp;lsquo;em though - they&amp;rsquo;re a wonderful bunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here&amp;rsquo;s an article I really enjoyed writing because, well, I love surfing! And so does Scott over in the art department. He took some glorious pictures in Tofino and quite simply graced my article with them. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alive.com/lifestyle/goodbye-treadmill-hello-waves/&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to hit the beach dude.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have a laugh, have a cry</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/have-a-laugh-have-a-cry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 04:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/have-a-laugh-have-a-cry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some recent article shorts. As usual, you can click on the thumbnails to read them. The one on the left is a feel-good piece on laughter yoga. The right piece touches on the depressing psychological and cultural effects of global warming. There&amp;rsquo;s also a teeny one in there on the dodgy air we have to breathe in airplanes (even Purell won&amp;rsquo;t save you this time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/scans/laughteryoga.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/yoga192.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;yoga192&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/scans/greenlivingnov08.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/green%20living193.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;green living193&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing these two articles juxtaposed like this evokes a stark contrast between Western frivolity and Aboriginal reality. Note how they&amp;rsquo;re both sitting in the same cross-legged position too. I almost wish the art department had actually planned it that way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reader letters warm my writer&#39;s heart</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/reader-letters-warm-my-writers-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 04:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/reader-letters-warm-my-writers-heart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may or may not recall, last August &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.com/posts/recycling-global-warming-and-toxic-toys/&#34;&gt;my article on the evils of recycling&lt;/a&gt; was published. Sometimes I lose sight of the fact that thousands of people read the stuff I put out there. Some probably think it&amp;rsquo;s a load of tosh. Other slightly more creepy individuals google my name and usually ask some sort of favour. But &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbit.freehostia.com/scans/letter.html&#34;&gt;others actually have something interesting to say&lt;/a&gt;. So Ben, even though you&amp;rsquo;ll never read this, thanks for your letter. It&amp;rsquo;s not often I get to hear from the mythical &amp;lsquo;audience&amp;rsquo; writers always harp on about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The writer&#39;s bane is...writing</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-writers-bane-iswriting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 02:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/the-writers-bane-iswriting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/bird.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished reading Anne Lamott&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Bird by Bird&lt;/em&gt;, a wonderfully humourous book full of advice on how to write and how to overcome those challenges all writers face. Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt I particularly like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But how?&amp;rdquo; my students ask. &amp;ldquo;How do you actually do it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You sit down, I say. You try to sit down at approximately the same time every day. This is how you train your unconscious to kick in for you creatively. So you sit down at, say, nine every morning, or ten every night. You put a piece of paper in the typewriter, or you turn on your computer and bring up the right file, and then you stare at it for an hour or so. You begin rocking, just a little at first, and then like a huge autistic child. You look at the ceiling, and over at the clock, yawn, and stare at the paper again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, with your fingers poised on the keyboard, you squint at an image that is forming in your mind - a scene, a locale, a character, whatever - and you try to quiet your mind so you can hear what that landscape has to say above the other voices in your mind. The other voices are banshees and drunken monkeys. They are the voices of anxiety, judgment, doom, guilt. Also, severe hypochondria. There may be a Nurse Ratched-like listing of things that must be done right this moment: foods that must come out of the freezer, appointments that must be canceled or made, hairs that must be tweezed. But you hold an imaginary gun to your head and make yourself stay at the desk. There is a vague pain at the base of your neck. It crosses your mind that you have meningitis. Then the phone rings and you look up at the ceiling with fury, summon every ounce of noblesse oblige, and answer the call politely, with maybe just the merest hint of irritation. The caller asks if you&amp;rsquo;re working, and you say yeah, because you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound familiar? The hardest part about writing is definitely the writing part. Anyway, just wanted to share that with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find a good book faster</title>
      <link>http://wordbit.com/posts/find-a-good-book-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 05:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wordbit.com/posts/find-a-good-book-faster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;border:20px solid white&#34; src=&#34;http://wordbit.com/images/logo.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking around for a book review website that aggregates all the critic reviews, sort of like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rottentomatoes.com&#34;&gt;Rotten tomatoes&lt;/a&gt; does with movies. The best I could find was the website for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bookmarksmagazine.com/&#34;&gt;Bookmarks Magazine&lt;/a&gt;. They add up reviews from most major US newspapers to give a book a rating out of five stars. It&amp;rsquo;s a handy way to see if a book will make it past your discerning taste radar and sneak its way onto your bedside table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you could always browse on Amazon or check out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/pages/books/&#34;&gt;New York Times book review&lt;/a&gt;, which most book junkies religiously follow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>