<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freelancing on wordbit</title>
    <link>https://wordbit.com/categories/freelancing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freelancing on wordbit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 23:13:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wordbit.com/categories/freelancing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>No rest for the dead…battery</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/no-rest-for-the-deadbattery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 23:13:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/no-rest-for-the-deadbattery/</guid>
      <description>My recent article on Battery Recycling is now available in the November issue of alive. I wasn’t aware of this before researching this topic, but you can recycle both single-use and rechargeable batteries in British Columbia.
Personally, I’m a big fan of eneloop batteries. I believe the batteries Apple uses in their wireless mouse and keyboard are re-branded eneloops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New published articles</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/new-published-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 00:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/new-published-articles/</guid>
      <description>Here are some new articles of mine that were published in alive magazine. Click on the thumbnails to view them. The first is on whether cell phone towers are safe or not. There is much heated debate surrounding this issue and I got a lot of hate mail for even suggesting we don’t know all there is to know about the technology. The hard truth is that we just don’t have the data spanning a human lifetime to say one way or the other, so lay off haters!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It pays to be paranoid</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/it-pays-to-be-paranoid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2010 22:48:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/it-pays-to-be-paranoid/</guid>
      <description>As 2010 hits in full force I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of ways to schedule in more quality blog time and keep wordbit alive. In the meantime, here is my latest article on how to avoid cold and flu germs. I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you but I&amp;rsquo;ve run the germ gambit from Swine to March Madness varieties and I&amp;rsquo;ve had enough. So it&amp;rsquo;s apt then that my article recommends borderline conspiracy theory-fueled paranoid behaviour to avoid catching a sniffle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A veritable article fest</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/a-veritable-article-fest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 03:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/a-veritable-article-fest/</guid>
      <description>This year has been busy and exciting and just plain exhausting. But I&amp;rsquo;ve finally found some time to upload a bunch of the articles that I&amp;rsquo;ve had published this year for alive and blush magazines. The majority focus on green issues. I&amp;rsquo;ve been somewhat typecast as the devil&amp;rsquo;s green advocate, being asked to find flaws in all manner of righteous green concepts. To read one, click on the image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21st century tips on finding work</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/21st-century-tips-on-finding-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 05:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/21st-century-tips-on-finding-work/</guid>
      <description>You may as well recycle those newspaper classifieds, because that old school job-finding tool belongs in the 20th century. Spurred on by the recession, a number of tech-savvy people have started blogging on various &amp;ldquo;new school&amp;rdquo; ways of getting a job. Tech evangelist Robert Scoble has some crafty tips. I tend to agree with him when he says your blog is your résumé. After all, google my name and this blog is the first search result (and if you are a hiring manager, then please note my correct formatting of the word résumé!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to write for Wired?</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/want-to-write-for-wired/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 01:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/want-to-write-for-wired/</guid>
      <description>Wired magazine has some interesting pieces this month. Well, every month is pretty good, but writers might appreciate this behind-the-scenes look at how an article is assigned, written, edited, and designed. You can read the email correspondence between author and editor, and get an idea of how to pitch your story idea to a magazine. Great stuff.
Also, technical writers might get a kick out of this photo essay of classic instruction manuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Brijit liberating or enslaving?</title>
      <link>https://wordbit.com/posts/is-brijit-liberating-or-enslaving/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2008 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wordbit.com/posts/is-brijit-liberating-or-enslaving/</guid>
      <description>For those of you who aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with it, Brijit is a website that publishes 100-word summaries of various web, TV, radio, and print media. The idea is that there is so much information out there - wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be nice if we had the short-short version so we can get the gist of it and decide if it&amp;rsquo;s worth reading or watching the whole thing.
It&amp;rsquo;s a neat idea, but with so much content out there, it would be impossible for an editorial team to cover it all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>